<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Madison Area Real Estate Journal</title>
    <description>Our mission at Holt Real Estate Team is to be your best resource for Madison Area real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Holt Real Estate Team, your professional Madison Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 14:26:32 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 14:26:32 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Take an Inventory of Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uz-f2k3xFp4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a homeowner, it’s very important that you do an inventory of the possessions in your home in the event that something catastrophic happens to it, like a fire. There’s no time like the present to do this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could you name the make, model, and price of all the TVs you own? Do you know where all the jewelry, trinkets, or collectibles are and how much they’re worth? This kind of thing can add up if something catastrophic does happen to your home, and it’s definitely something you don’t want to deal with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I have two main tips for you to remember when doing your home inventory.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;use your smartphone to go room by room and take pictures and video of every important item you want to catalog.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’re done doing that, &lt;strong&gt;use a cloud-based service to upload and store your photos and video.&lt;/strong&gt; In my opinion, Google Drive works best for this. If you already have a Google account, then it’s free. It has quite a bit of storage, and you can also utilize Google Sheets to further itemize your possessions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, the last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is to try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 10:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Decluttering After the Holiday Season</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oOam93P4WKQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you all had a wonderful holiday and are excited for the new year. If you’re like my family, now is the time you look to declutter your home as you prepare for the coming year, and I’ve got some tips to help you do that more easily today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t wait.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t let weeks pass by as your holiday items sit in the home without a proper place. I recommend getting on the task of decluttering right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Prioritize.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re struggling to find a place for one or more items that you have, consider whether the items are something that you need to hold on to. There may be certain items that are important to you and your family, but there may also be other items that you’ve acquired over the years that you don’t really use in your annual decorating. If that’s the case, it might be time to donate or resell those items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A lot of your extra gift wrap and trimmings are recyclable.%20http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A lot of your extra gift wrap and trimmings are recyclable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Organize gift wrap.&lt;/strong&gt; It can be very easy for rolls of gift wrap to get spread out and take up a lot of room. Now is a great time to go through and organize that gift wrap to make sure you’re not holding on to scraps of paper that won’t help you in the future. Maybe you could repurpose those for a craft project or something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Recycle.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that you’re not just tossing all of your extra gift wrap and trimmings in the trash. A lot of this stuff is recycled material and you want to properly dispose of it according to your local recycling priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Prepare for next year.&lt;/strong&gt; You may have things that you kept in storage and didn’t pull out for the holidays. I like to take this time of year to evaluate the inventory I have and see if any of them are ones I intend to hold onto in the future. It’s also just a good time to organize your stuff so that you know where everyone is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about this list or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 10:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seasons Greetings from the Holt Real Estate Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yWBAepuGbbw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all of us here at the Holt Real Estate Team: We wish you and your family the very best this holiday season. This is the time you should spend with your family and friends, and give joy and thanks for all that you have, so enjoy it! Speaking of giving thanks: We appreciate all of your support this year, and we love being able to help people make their real estate dreams come true. Here’s to helping even more of you in 2020! Thank you all so much, and happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 14:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-the-holt-real-estate-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-the-holt-real-estate-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everything You Need to Know About USDA Loans</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PXuzEEE_acU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a low- to moderate-income buyer, or just someone without a significant down payment saved up, then a USDA loan might be the perfect path to homeownership for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The USDA loan program allows homeowners to purchase a qualifying rural property for no money down.&lt;/strong&gt; Like any mortgage option, you will need to meet certain criteria, though. The primary qualifying factors are your income, for which limits will vary by area, as well as the location of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The bottom line is that the USDA loan is a great option for those savvy enough to take advantage.%20http://localhost:4000/everything-you-need-to-know-about-usda-loans.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The bottom line is that the USDA loan is a great option for those savvy enough to take advantage.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rd.usda.gov/programs-services/single-family-housing-guaranteed-loan-program&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more and for access to a loan availability map showing what properties near you may qualify. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes located within Stoughton city limits, for example, are ineligible, but areas just to the north (near Madison) do qualify—as do properties in the Village of McFarland, the Village of Oregon, Deforest/Windsor/ Mount Horeb, Cambridge, and many other municipalities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that the USDA loan is a great option for those savvy enough to take advantage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 13:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/everything-you-need-to-know-about-usda-loans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/everything-you-need-to-know-about-usda-loans.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Thanksgiving Message From Our Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CU0D6DKTiaA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to take a moment today to say thank you. Thank you to all of you wonderful folks who have trusted us with your real estate needs in the Madison area. We also want to thank those of you who have partnered with our company to ensure that our clients’ experiences are second-to-none. We can’t thank you enough for all that you do to help our team grow and thrive. On behalf of everyone here at The Holt Real Estate Team, thank you for your support and we hope you have a wonderful Thanksgiving. To hear my full message, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-thanksgiving-message-from-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-thanksgiving-message-from-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons to Buy an Investment Property Before Becoming a Homeowner</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r6m5Fe4kGeE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently someone approached me to ask whether buying an investment property before buying their first primary residence was a good idea, and, actually, it very well may be. Here are five reasons why: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Interest rates are low.&lt;/strong&gt; Low interest rates mean greater purchasing power, which gives those looking to invest a unique opportunity to enjoy low monthly payments on their property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Homes are continuing to appreciate each year.&lt;/strong&gt; According to Core Logic’s value index, home values have increased every year for the past seven years. And, according to most experts, real estate is one of the safest (and wisest) investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you ever tire of renting your property out, or if you’re simply ready to become a homeowner, yourself, there is always the option for you to move into the home.%20http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-buy-an-investment-property-before-becoming-a-homeowner.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you ever tire of renting your property out, or if you’re simply ready to become a homeowner, yourself, there is always the option for you to move into the home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Real estate investing creates passive income.&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond just having someone else cover the expense of your monthly payments, renting out a property means that you can rely on your investment to generate passive income, as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Short-term rentals are popular right now.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if you aren’t interested in being a long-term landlord, short-term rentals are in high demand right now. Airbnb and VRBO have opened up numerous options for investors. Your investment property also doesn’t need to be local. You can purchase a rental property in a tourist “hot spot” and have someone else manage it for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. You can turn the investment into your primary residence later on.&lt;/strong&gt; If you ever tire of renting your property out, or if you’re simply ready to become a homeowner, yourself, there is always the option for you to move into the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-buy-an-investment-property-before-becoming-a-homeowner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-buy-an-investment-property-before-becoming-a-homeowner.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Preparing Your Home for Our Fall Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qAKVc8Q1VQ4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temperature is dropping, leaves are changing color, and pumpkin spice is everywhere you look. With fall color and produce back in season, you might be tempted to load up your house with both. However, if you plan to sell your home this fall, you might want to exercise some restraint. In the eyes of buyers, less is more. Here are four tips to consider: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pay attention to your fall-themed curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; While too many fall decorations can distract attention away from your home’s best features, a few tasteful accents can produce an inviting atmosphere. Take the time to rake and round up fallen leaves and do general yard care. Buyers may give you a pass if they see your lawn is blanketed with leaves, but that doesn’t mean your home will make a good impression. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=While too many fall decorations can distract attention away from your home’s best features, a few tasteful accents can produce an inviting atmosphere.%20http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-preparing-your-home-for-our-fall-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“While too many fall decorations can distract attention away from your home’s best features, a few tasteful accents can produce an inviting atmosphere.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Go easy on the gory Halloween decorations.&lt;/strong&gt; Decorating your home with fake blood, guts, and skeletons might just be part of getting into the holiday spirit for you, but you never know what kind of reaction you’ll get from buyers. Some may be amused, but some may be frightened, and anything that has the potential to turn off a buyer is a no-no when listing your home. Play it safe with your decor choices, so you can appeal to the masses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Let in the light.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s always a good idea to pull back the curtains and allow natural light to help you showcase your home. With shorter days in the fall and winter, you want to make sure you maximize the amount of light flooding into your home. This way, your home will appear larger. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Make the space inviting.&lt;/strong&gt; As the weather cools off, a warm and cozy atmosphere will give buyers a warm and cozy feeling. Place plush throws on your couch and beds and add fall-accented pillows to your couch and chairs as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about selling your home or about real estate in general, or there’s a topic you’d like me to cover in a future video, feel free to give me a call at 608-345-6594 or you can email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:JDHolt@KW.com&quot;&gt;JDHolt@KW.com&lt;/a&gt;. I hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 11:57:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-preparing-your-home-for-our-fall-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-preparing-your-home-for-our-fall-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Keep Your Yard Fresh This Winter</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LjnIyOmNwh0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day, I was speaking with a friend of mine about their yard and gave them some advice about what they can do to make sure it stays in tip-top shape through the fall and winter as they prepare for a possible spring sale. &lt;strong&gt;Here are eight helpful tips that you can use to keep your yard in good shape:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.  Fertilization and weed control.&lt;/strong&gt; This helps reduce the stress your lawn will endure over the summer, and weed control will take care of those fall weeds as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Aerate your yard. It should be overseeded as well.&lt;/strong&gt; Aeration prepares it for winter and promotes healthy growth for spring. Overseeding helps fill in any bare spots and helps your lawn recover from the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Rake and pick up leaves.&lt;/strong&gt; This will reduce possible insect and disease damage over the winter. It’s also a good time to remove any dead or unsafe branches in your yard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Roots have a better chance to establish in the fall.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-keep-your-yard-fresh-this-winter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Roots have a better chance to establish in the fall.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The final mow of the season.&lt;/strong&gt; Set your mower to the lowest height recommended for your grass on the last mow of the year to reduce the ability of diseases to affect them in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Plant trees and shrubs.&lt;/strong&gt; In the fall, it gives roots a chance to establish in a lower-stress, moist environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Cut back and divide perennials.&lt;/strong&gt; This will result in a more established plant next spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Add some fall color.&lt;/strong&gt; Hearty mums are a great choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Plant spring bulbs.&lt;/strong&gt; To ensure vibrant, early spring color in your landscaping, be sure to plant your bulbs in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about these tips or about anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 15:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-keep-your-yard-fresh-this-winter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-keep-your-yard-fresh-this-winter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Value of Having an Agent in Your Corner</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8xDjq1E5Uxg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, purchasing new construction isn’t all that different from purchasing an existing home in an established neighborhood. Of course, for either purchase, there’s a lot of value that &lt;strong&gt;having the support of a professional agent can bring you when making such an important (and expensive) decision.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you visited a model home on the weekend and talked to the on-site sales agent, you likely wouldn’t be talking to an agent who had your best interests at heart. What I mean by that is that particular agent is likely employed by or represents the builder and their fiduciary responsibility is to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you hire an agent of your own, &lt;strong&gt;you get the advocacy of someone who does have your best interests at heart&lt;/strong&gt; and who will help you navigate the intricacies of negotiation, paperwork, terms, conditions, and every other aspect of the real estate process in order to ensure that you’re getting the best benefits from your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, builders may offer discounts, savings, or incentives if you work with their lender or select specific upgrades and finishes; as agents in your corner, we’ll make sure that those incentives truly are savings and won’t come back to bite you later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As agents in your corner, we’ll make sure that the builder’s incentives truly are savings and won’t come back to bite you later on.%20http://localhost:4000/the-value-of-having-an-agent-in-your-corner.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As agents in your corner, we’ll make sure that the builder’s incentives truly are savings and won’t come back to bite you later on.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something else to take into consideration is how long you plan to live in the home. If, for whatever reason, this home ends up not being your forever home and you decide to resell it later on, &lt;strong&gt;your agent can also advise you on which upgrades you can do to increase your future resale value and which ones may actually decrease or not improve that value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest things an agent on your side can help you with is &lt;strong&gt;researching the builder&lt;/strong&gt;: how they work, the quality of their products, their building programs, the incentives they offer, and their sales history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, &lt;strong&gt;it typically doesn’t cost you any extra money to hire an agent like myself to represent you.&lt;/strong&gt; Like any seller in a real estate transaction, the builder will be the one who ends up paying for your agent’s commission. If you’re not working with an agent, don’t assume they will just pass that difference on to you as cost savings, often they may use that money instead for marketing or just for profit. I’ve found that most of the builders in our market are “agent-friendly” and like working with buyers that have representation; the key thing is that we, the agents, need to be the ones who introduce you to the builder, not the other way around. If you have more questions on that, send me a message and we can talk more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see value in having an agent like myself represent you in the purchase of a new construction property, and are looking to buy a brand-new home, reach out to us. We’d love to have your back in the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 17:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-value-of-having-an-agent-in-your-corner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-value-of-having-an-agent-in-your-corner.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Successfully Sell After a Failed Listing Attempt</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/F3CJtjgeIG0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a common misconception among sellers (and even some real estate agents) that all it takes to sell a home is to stick a sign in the yard and wait for the offers to roll in. However, this couldn’t be further from the truth. Many sellers who attempt this route end up with expired listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do after this has happened to you? What does it take to make your second attempt at listing successful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it’s important to realize that you’re not alone. &lt;strong&gt;Year to Date in Dane County, 10.68% of single-family home listings and 6.46% of all condo listings expired. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are actually a number of factors that can contribute to a listing’s success (or its failure). Chief among these factors are price, condition, and location, but also marketing. &lt;strong&gt;The marketing an agent uses to advertise a home can make or break its ability to sell. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your agent needs to actively seek out buyers, rather than waiting for buyers to come to them.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-successfully-sell-after-a-failed-listing-attempt.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your agent needs to actively seek out buyers, rather than waiting for buyers to come to them.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An effective marketing plan must include professional photography (and videography), an enticing description on its online listing, and adequate exposure. Your agent should use every available method to reach buyers, including social media advertising, print advertising, open houses, among other things. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proactive prospecting, in particular, is critical. In other words, your agent needs to actively seek out buyers, rather than waiting for buyers to come to them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the agent you’re working with can’t do these things for you and your home, then it’s time to seek out a more experienced, knowledgeable professional.&lt;/strong&gt; Our team would be happy to fill that role for you. So, if you or someone you know is looking to sell, please reach out to us. We can help you sell quickly and for top dollar, within a time frame that works for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me or my team a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 15:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-successfully-sell-after-a-failed-listing-attempt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-successfully-sell-after-a-failed-listing-attempt.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
