<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joshua Holt: Madison Real Estate Agent Video Blog</title>
    <description>Our mission at Holt Real Estate Team is to be your best resource for Madison, WI real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Holt Real Estate Team, your professional Madison, WI Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 12:57:47 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 12:57:47 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying Now vs. Timing the Market </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aMyg4i-545k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;How to decide if you should try to time the market for a cheaper price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you waiting for prices to drop significantly before you buy a house? That is a common mentality nowadays, especially with interest rates as high as they are. No one can say exactly what will happen in the future, but many are hoping that values will crash so they can swoop in and buy properties for low prices. Should you wait to buy a house? Is it worth the risk? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some industry experts say the fluctuation in prices depends on the needs and goals of the particular area.&lt;/strong&gt; A J.P. Morgan 2022 analysis of 116 metropolitan areas predicts housing prices to go in three general directions over the next couple of years. Some areas are predicted to drop 20% to 30%, some 10% to 15%, and some not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=What happens if you wait for a crash that never comes?%20http://localhost:4000/buying-now-vs-timing-the-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“What happens if you wait for a crash that never comes?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, no one can say for sure what the future holds, but are you willing to take the risk of hoping that your area will be one of the few where prices fall? It is important to remember that many factors go into deciding prices, like interest rates, the state of the economy, the season of the year, etc. As a result, many experts believe it is not wise to wait for price decreases. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People on this side of the debate say that trying to time the market to buy at the lowest possible point is often a fool’s game. &lt;strong&gt;The market changes often and quickly, so many are convinced that buying when it’s right for you and your family is the best choice.&lt;/strong&gt; You never know when the peak is going to end, and you don’t want to have any regrets. Hindsight is the only thing that’s 20/20. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Association of Home Builders’ chief economist, Robert Dietz, says, “I think you want to be strategic and patient—patience is different from waiting for a crash.” It is good to take the time to do your research and figure out your strategy, and buyers have more time to do that now as the market is shifting. However, that is different than waiting around for the market to crash to get the lowest price. If you do, you might miss your shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a lot of information to take in, so if you have any questions or want to talk with me about your specific situation, don’t hesitate to reach out. I would love to create a strategy with you that works best for you and your family. Call or email me anytime. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 23:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buying-now-vs-timing-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buying-now-vs-timing-the-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Thanksgiving From the Whole Holt Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vyvMqhGX4ks?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Our brief message of thanks to you from the entire Holt Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this amazing and special time of year, I wanted to take a few moments to share a message of thanks and gratitude from me and my team. &lt;strong&gt;We are so grateful for everybody that has trusted us with the opportunity to help with their real estate needs.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether that is buying, selling, or investing, we just want to say thank you. You’ve given us the great privilege of helping more families than ever before in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each member of our team is grateful for you and for their own special blessings during this time of year. We are grateful for food and family, friends, and time to decompress. We are thankful for our health, careers, football, and the opportunity to help those in need. Finally, we have so much to be grateful for in our pets and in seeing our families after the long pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, from all of us here at the Holt Team, happy holidays and happy Thanksgiving.&lt;/strong&gt; If you need help with anything, don’t forget to call or email us. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 23:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/happy-thanksgiving-from-the-whole-holt-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/happy-thanksgiving-from-the-whole-holt-team.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buyer Options in This Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5xOG4SXG7h8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Buyers have multiple options available to them that can lower their rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates are top of mind for most buyers when they’re considering whether or not to buy a home right now. We’ve found that many folks don’t know that there are options to help mitigate those interest rates, both in the short or long term. I recently talked with Joe Allen from Guild Mortgage, one of our local lender partners, to help explain some of the options that folks have when it comes to interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to watch the full message above or use these timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:00 — Introducing today’s topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:40 — The current market situation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:30 — Buyer solutions: 2-1 and 3-1 buydowns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:50 — Solution with a set rate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:40 — Talk with a lender and a Realtor to choose the best solution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:30 — Wrapping up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to contact me by phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buyer-options-in-this-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buyer-options-in-this-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Local Group That’s Closing the Housing Gap</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6YWWDL_AzVQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;All about a local organization that’s serving our community in great ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that only 15% of black households own their homes? Today we are honored to be joined by Tiffany Malone, co-creator of Own It: Building Black Wealth, to find out more about the program and how they are helping close this tremendous gap. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Own It is a movement designed to address racial disparities in real estate through a strong collaboration of community and business partnerships. &lt;strong&gt;Although discrimination in housing is no longer legal, echoes from the past and access to money remain some of black families’ biggest barriers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiffany grew up in a single-family household and was surrounded by lots of people who had homes when her parents did not. At a young age, she saw what homeownership could do regarding wealth and how it set people apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can help close the gap in housing opportunities.%20http://localhost:4000/a-local-group-thats-closing-the-housing-gap.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can help close the gap in housing opportunities.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program has two parts. One is an educational portion, and the other is a grant. &lt;strong&gt;Once a participant completes the educational part, they can apply for $15,000 to buy a one- or two-unit home.&lt;/strong&gt; The home can be anywhere, but most people buy in the Madison area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to get involved, you can become an ambassador, volunteer, or donate. Visit their website by clicking &lt;a href=&quot;https://ownitbbw.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and you can find the forms you need. You can attend their mixers and events, and you can help spread the word. Lastly, you can be educated by the reading materials found on their website. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are contributing ambassadors, so if you’d like any more information on this company, you can also contact us. Call or email, we would love to connect you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-local-group-thats-closing-the-housing-gap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-local-group-thats-closing-the-housing-gap.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Price Your Home in a Correcting Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NMqPENKlNJk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;You can still get top dollar if you price your home correctly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been paying attention to housing market news, you’ve probably heard about decreasing sales, rising interest rates, and increasing inventory. Do these factors mean we’re heading for a housing market crash? According to the experts, the answer is no. &lt;strong&gt;Instead of crashing, our housing market is correcting.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the crazy housing market caused by low interest rates and the increased flexibility of remote work, prices skyrocketed. In fact, the average home price increased by 10.2% from July 2021 to July 2022. The truth is that the crazy pandemic market wasn’t sustainable. According to Moody Analytics, 210 metro areas were overvalued by 25% or more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to sell your home soon, what does this all mean for you? Fortunately, we’re still in a seller’s market, but you have to be careful about how you price your home. If you make the wrong move, your house could sit on the market for a long time, and you may have to decrease your price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re still in a seller’s market, but you have to be careful about how you price your home.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-price-your-home-in-a-correcting-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re still in a seller’s market, but you have to be careful about how you price your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a correcting market like ours, &lt;strong&gt;it is more important than ever not to price your home too high.&lt;/strong&gt; If you do, you could end up “chasing the market.” In this scenario, your initial price is too high, and buyers won’t look at your home. You could try lowering your price, but by that point, the market may have changed again. This is a seller’s worst nightmare—if it happens, you may even have to take your property off the market and try again later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One strategy that works in a shifting market is to price your home slightly below market value on purpose. It seems odd, but this will guarantee that your home is the most attractive deal in your area. If everything goes according to plan, buyers will flock to your house, and the competition among them will naturally bring the price up to or above market value. The risk with this strategy is that if only a few buyers come to your home, there might not be enough competition to drive up the price. However, this is a fantastic option if you need to sell quickly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can always work with a real estate professional to look at comparable sales in your area and find a goldilocks price—one that isn’t too high or too low, but just right. This can be difficult to do on your own in a correcting market, but professionals have access to market data that will make the process much easier. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bottom line is that sellers can still achieve fantastic results in this market as long as they do their research and price their homes correctly.&lt;/strong&gt; If you would like to discuss which strategy might be best for you, don’t hesitate to call or email me. Make it a great day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-price-your-home-in-a-correcting-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-price-your-home-in-a-correcting-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Olivia Joined The Holt Real Estate Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x8tQjVvsoRI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Introducing our newest hire, executive assistant Olivia Kracht. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m here with Olivia Kracht, our new executive assistant. She just joined the team, so we wanted to introduce her to all of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olivia has lived in the Madison area for around five years. She and her husband moved here for work, and after about a year, she had their first son. Olivia finished her bachelor’s degree and decided she wanted to pursue a different opportunity, which led her to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re so grateful to have Olivia on the team.%20http://localhost:4000/why-olivia-joined-the-josh-holt-team.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re so grateful to have Olivia on the team.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before real estate, she worked in the hospitality world&lt;/strong&gt;, which she says was fun but also a bit draining. After the move, she worked as an office manager for a little bit. She wasn’t sure about joining the real estate industry at first—anything new is bound to be a bit scary, but she had always been interested in real estate. In the end, she thought she might as well take the leap, and the interview process made her feel much more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She hopes to settle into a role where she can support everyone on the team and offer guidance.&lt;/strong&gt; She wants to help people grow individually and as a team so we can all prosper and reach our goals. Outside of work, she spends her time camping, playing soccer and volleyball, and reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re so grateful to have Olivia on our team. She’s going to be instrumental in helping us deliver on our promise to our clients. If you have any questions, feel free to call or email us anytime. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-olivia-joined-the-josh-holt-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-olivia-joined-the-josh-holt-team.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Some Homes Sell and Others Don’t </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eQnQhkxfows?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Three types of homes that are selling and three that aren’t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our market shift is real and happening right now. So today I want to discuss the three types of properties in our market that are still selling well and three that aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first kind of home that’s still selling well is three- or four-bedroom, two-bath, single-family homes in above-average locations. The second one is condos that have at least two bedrooms. So whether they are more in the city center of Madison or out in the suburban areas, condos with two bedrooms or more are still selling well. The third type of property that are still selling well are entry-level homes in above-average locations. They sell even better when they’ve been remodeled or have had a refresh or update made to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many entry-level buyers don’t necessarily have the funds to do updates to the home. If you have that type of home and can put those updates into it, those types of properties are going to do really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s very important that you get your pricing right from the get-go.%20http://localhost:4000/why-some-homes-sell-and-others-dont.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s very important that you get your pricing right from the get-go.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If those homes are selling well, which ones aren’t?&lt;/strong&gt; The first category is entry-level homes in below-average locations, especially if they need a lot of work. The second type that are struggling are average homes in average locations. There isn’t anything wrong with these homes, but higher interest rates make them less affordable for many buyers. That being said, the market for these types of houses fluctuates a lot. No other type is as sensitive to interest rate increases, so condition is crucial for these properties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, overpriced homes are really struggling. Even a price 1% above market value can seriously reduce a home’s marketability. It’s very important that you get your pricing right from the get-go and you’re not chasing the market, or you’ll struggle selling your home. &lt;strong&gt;The bottom line is that there is no longer a one-size-fits-all way to navigate this market,&lt;/strong&gt; regardless of whether you’re a buyer or a seller. This market is a skills-based market, and who you work with matters more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about today’s topic, please call or email me. I am always willing to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-some-homes-sell-and-others-dont.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-some-homes-sell-and-others-dont.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buying Before You Sell in Today’s Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jO9h69AocQQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Two options for people who need to buy a home before selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Selling your current home before buying a new one is the conventional way to move. However, depending on your situation, there will be times when buying before you sell is the better option. Whatever your reason, you should know that buying first comes with additional risks, such as paying two mortgages, if your current home takes a long time to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in a situation where you must buy first before selling, don’t worry. It’s not completely impossible, but it takes some strategic planning to make it happen. Here are two things you can do to help you buy before you sell:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make an offer with a home-sale contingency.&lt;/strong&gt; By including a home-sale contingency in your offer, you can purchase the new house once your existing one sells successfully. If your current home doesn’t sell within a certain time frame, you can cancel the purchase contract without any penalties. To sweeten the deal, your agent can explain to the seller that your house will likely sell fast in the current market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buying a new home before selling your existing one has its unique challenges.%20http://localhost:4000/buying-before-you-sell-in-todays-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buying a new home before selling your existing one has its unique challenges.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Finance with a bridge loan&lt;/strong&gt;. A bridge loan is a short-term, high-interest loan. When you buy with a bridge loan, you can use your existing home as collateral to get a loan for your new house. To close your bridge loan faster, try to align the closing dates of your buying and selling transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a new home before selling your existing one has its unique challenges, but if you can leverage these options and utilize the guidance of an experienced agent, you can come up with the best solutions for your situation. If you want more details about this topic or have any real estate concerns, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’ll be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buying-before-you-sell-in-todays-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buying-before-you-sell-in-todays-market.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank You for Supporting RISE</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tt_zA0rqTfk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;We’re more than halfway to our year-end goal of $10,000!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Holt Real Estate Team, giving back to the communities we serve is at the heart of our team’s mission, vision, values, and perspectives. At the beginning of the year, we announced our exciting new partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;https://risewisconsin.org/&quot;&gt;RISE Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt;, our official non-profit organization. We pledged to donate a portion of our profits from each closing to RISE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal for this year was not only to raise awareness for this great organization, but we also wanted to raise at least $10,000 for the center by the end of 2022. Thanks to your support, today &lt;strong&gt;we’re pleased to announce that we have already raised $6,000.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re making strides toward our year-end goal, and we are truly grateful for all your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to delivering on our promise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thank-you-for-supporting-rise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/thank-you-for-supporting-rise.html</guid>
        
        <category>Giving Back</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Local Market Updates You Have To Know</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r69t_TkhSa8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;What caused the rise in our inventory? It’s not what you might expect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been keeping up with the news, you’ve probably heard a lot of alarming headlines about the housing market. However, you need to remember that real estate is local. That’s why today I want to share some critical points about our Greater Madison market so that you know what’s actually happening locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can listen to my full explanation in the video above or skip to each topic using the timestamps provided:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:00 — Introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:39 — The impact of recession on the housing market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:44 — Recessions don’t automatically equal a housing crisis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:37 — The increase in inventory is due to a slowdown in the pace of sales&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:22 — Supply and demand are the driving factors of the housing market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:49 — There’s still a big deficit in available homes &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:12 — The impact of inflation on mortgage rates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:12 — Listen to reliable news about your local market &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:26 — Wrapping up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need more details about our Greater Madison housing market, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’m always willing to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/local-market-updates-you-have-to-know.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/local-market-updates-you-have-to-know.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
