<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joshua Holt: Madison Real Estate Agent Video Blog</title>
    <description>Our mission at Holt Real Estate Team is to be your best resource for Madison, WI real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Holt Real Estate Team, your professional Madison, WI Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 15:25:41 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 15:25:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Veterans Day</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hB9nCZjwhGI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;As a Veteran-owned business, we want to give thanks to our Veterans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veterans Day is just a couple of days away, so I want to thank all our Veterans for their service and wish them a happy Veterans Day. &lt;strong&gt;As a Veteran-owned business, we take great pride in being able to help our fellow Veterans with all of their real estate needs&lt;/strong&gt;, whether that’s buying, selling, or investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Community Champions Program is an additional incentive that we offer to Veterans who choose to buy, sell, or invest in real estate with us at the Holt Real Estate Team. If you’d like to learn additional information about that program, reach out to us, and we’ll gladly share more information with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t served but know a Veteran, please thank them for their service to our country and the lifestyle that we all get to enjoy. If you have any questions about the local real estate market, feel free to give us a call at 608 345-6594 or via email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:JDHolt@kw.com&quot;&gt;JDHolt@kw.com&lt;/a&gt;. We look forward to hearing from you. Happy Veterans day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/happy-veterans-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/happy-veterans-day.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips for a Happy &amp; Safe Halloween</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VAxd6P2csPU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a homeowner who expects trick-or-treaters to come to your door, here are a few safety tips to keep in mind this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Keep your walkways and/or porch well-lit.&lt;/strong&gt; That way, kids and their parents can reach your door safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Keep your pets out of sight.&lt;/strong&gt; Pets can often get stressed out by seeing so many strangers come to the door. Put them in another room to reduce their stress and prevent them from scaring anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Park your cars in the garage, if possible.&lt;/strong&gt; That ensures your trick-or-treaters will have enough room to get to your front door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Use flameless LED candles in your jack-o’-lanterns instead of real candles.&lt;/strong&gt; This eliminates the fire hazard that burning candles presents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Have a safe, fun, and happy Halloween!%20http://localhost:4000/tips-for-a-happy-safe-halloween.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Have a safe, fun, and happy Halloween!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you’re planning to go out into the neighborhood and trick or treat, here are a few points to follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Stick to neighborhoods with sidewalks.&lt;/strong&gt; It usually gets dark around that time, so finding areas with sidewalks means that you won’t have to walk in the streets. It might be a good idea to put reflective tape on your kids’ jackets or costumes to make sure that cars can see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Keep to the crosswalks.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t just dart across the road to get to the next home; if you or your children are wearing dark costumes, it might be hard for oncoming cars to see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Carry a flashlight with you.&lt;/strong&gt; Some driveways might be long and dark, so having a flashlight can come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Remind your kids not to enter a stranger’s home.&lt;/strong&gt; Have them stay on the front porch and in full view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Be mindful of the treats your kids receive&lt;/strong&gt;. You never know—someone might put a food item in their bag that your kids are allergic to, or they might slip in something that isn’t necessarily appropriate. Comb through the candy before letting them eat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you and yours have a safe, fun, and happy Halloween!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you feel like your home search is like hunting for a unicorn, give our team a call. We’ll be able to help you find the dream home you’re searching for at a great price.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 17:32:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tips-for-a-happy-safe-halloween.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tips-for-a-happy-safe-halloween.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Market Shift is Coming</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/k3ej-VtlPI8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;The market is shifting from a seller’s market to a more balanced market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked whether we’re starting to see a shift from the robust seller’s market we’ve experienced to a balanced market. &lt;strong&gt;The market is beginning to change.&lt;/strong&gt; Price adjustments and longer days on market are signs that we’re shifting from a seller’s market to a more balanced market. That means the market will become less competitive for buyers, and there won’t be bidding wars on every home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We're shifting from a seller's market to a more balanced market.%20http://localhost:4000/the-market-shift-is-coming.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re shifting from a seller’s market to a more balanced market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the pandemic began and interest rates plummeted, a lot of people decided they wanted to buy a home. Many of them were competing for specific areas. Now, people are starting to spread out, so demand won’t be so concentrated. Buyers should be able to make offers without waiving contingencies or using other strategies to stand out and there will be more options available. &lt;strong&gt;In today’s shifting market, buyers can now feel more confident that the home they want is the one they’ll be able to win. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been sitting on the sidelines for a while or you’ve felt burnt out by the current market, reach out to us and let us show you what’s really going on in our local market. We can set you up for success so that you can win your dream house. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 12:53:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-market-shift-is-coming.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-market-shift-is-coming.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Navigate VA Loans</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bwouk3U9RIY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are some nuances of VA loans that you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Veteran, I take a lot of pride in helping military Veterans with their home purchases. Today I’m talking with Joe Long from Guild Mortgage about some of the nuances to be aware of with the VA loan. He’s a great local lender, and he does a lot of business with Veterans as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:27 — Introducing today’s topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:19 — Meet with your lender and obtain your certificate of eligibility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:14 — VA loans and rural properties&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:49 — Wisconsin termite inspection requirement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:56 — VA appraisals in a nutshell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:39 — Purchasing a condo with a VA loan can be tricky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:33 — VA loans are eligible for up to four-unit properties&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:22 — You could be eligible for two VA loans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:56 — Wrapping up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate or the VA loan process, reach out to our team at 608-345-6594 or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jdholt@kw.com&quot;&gt;jdholt@kw.com&lt;/a&gt;. We look forward to hearing from you and helping in any way we can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 17:02:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-navigate-va-loans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-navigate-va-loans.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Savannah, Our Newest Team Member</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EJxQkTiXOL0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s my conversation with Savannah, our team’s new executive assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by Savannah Paukner, a new executive assistant for our team. I want to take a second to introduce her because if you decide to buy or sell with our team, you’ll probably be working with Savannah a lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So Savannah, what was your background before real estate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, my family and I were in Fort Leonard in Missouri while my husband finished his career in the Air Force. I was working for the government in the purchasing field, and before that, I worked in the county’s treasury department. I was doing back-end support work for the most part, so I have plenty of experience working with a lot of moving parts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When I saw you had a job opening, I knew it was a great opportunity.%20http://localhost:4000/introducing-savannah-our-newest-team-member.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When I saw you had a job opening, I knew it was a great opportunity.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I know your family just moved to Wisconsin a few months ago, so what made you want to get into real estate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you already know, when my family moved to Wisconsin, we worked with your team to buy a home. Even long-distance, the experience was fantastic, so when I saw you had a job opening, I saw it as a sign of a great opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your role here, and how will you interact with our clients?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m taking all the back-end support off the agents’ plates. If there’s any paperwork, appointments, or correspondence between agents and clients, I’ll be the one making sure everything is in order. In other words, I’ll be making sure our team fulfills our promise to give our clients the best experience possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all thrilled here at the Holt Real Estate Team to have Savannah on our team, and we’re especially excited for our clients to work with her. All of us are dedicated to providing you with the best service possible, so if you are looking to buy or sell a home, please give us a call or send us an email. We would love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 16:56:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/introducing-savannah-our-newest-team-member.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/introducing-savannah-our-newest-team-member.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Cost of Waiting To Buy</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fydz_dHw-l4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Waiting could cost you more in the long run than buying right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;House prices have been rising ever since 2013, and this past year, we saw incredible price appreciation. This also comes at a time when interest rates are extremely low. Today I’m joined by Joe Long of Guild Mortgage to discuss the cost of waiting for first-time homebuyers and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:18 — Introducing today’s topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:39 — Price appreciation since 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:22 — Low interest rates and affordability&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:15 — The reality of waiting and saving money&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:48 — PMI is not as expensive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:52 — How could home values drop?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:30 — Waiting is a losing strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:11 — Wrapping up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions, please feel free to reach out. I am always willing to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 14:13:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-cost-of-waiting-to-buy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-cost-of-waiting-to-buy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our New Team Member</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NIa883Rm6NQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Welcome the newest real estate agent on our team, Jonathan Gaspero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Gaspero is joining our team as an agent, and we wanted to introduce him to all of you. Here’s a quick Q&amp;amp;A with him so you can get to know him better:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your background from before you got into real estate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before real estate, I worked at Meredith Hospital. I was originally pursuing a career in healthcare administration and management, but I found my love for real estate and decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What got you connected to Keller Williams?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a good friend, David Perry, who got me into real estate. He kept trying to push me and get me to join his team, but I had other career goals at the time. It sounded like something I wanted to do, but it just wasn’t the right time. By the time I finally got my real estate license, he had moved to Las Vegas, but he said to check out Keller Williams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What made you decide that joining our team was the right route to take?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the support aspect of the team because I’d never done real estate before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you hoping to accomplish when working with a client?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to help them as best I can and provide the best service by responding quickly, being personable, and listening to their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the best way for a client to reach you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to me through Facebook or by phone or text at (608) 852-5656.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can reach our team directly at any time by phone at (608) 345-6594. You can also email any of us if you have questions. Please also check out our Facebook and Instagram. We look forward to the opportunity to help more people as we continue to grow our team. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or somebody you know is looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate in the greater Madison and South Central Wisconsin area, we’d love the opportunity to meet and see if we’re a good match to help you achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:28:48 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-new-team-member.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/our-new-team-member.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Increasing Housing Supply Means to You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p2To_pELoKo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s a quick update on the current housing supply situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears that housing supply may be on the rise, so what does that mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, an important factor in today’s housing market is the number of homes for sale. While inventory levels continue to sit near historic lows, there are indications that we may have hit the lowest point we’ll see and that we’re possibly working our way back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May, inventory was at 2.5 months of supply, which was up from 2.4 in April. That’s a trend we’re seeing on both the national and local levels; &lt;strong&gt;the months’ supply has increased every month since the beginning of the year.&lt;/strong&gt; Though we’re still nowhere near a balanced market (around six months of supply), we are seeing a slow but steady increase in homes for sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=More homes for sale mean that buyers have more options and sellers have more competition.%20http://localhost:4000/what-increasing-housing-supply-means-to-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“More homes for sale mean that buyers have more options and sellers have more competition.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That has left many buyers and sellers wondering about how this will affect their prospects. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re a buyer, this means that more options are arriving, so now may be the best time to act.&lt;/strong&gt; As the number of homes for sale goes up, the less competition there will be and the less intense the bidding wars will become. If you’ve been struggling to find a home, this news should bring you some hope and motivation to keep looking. Experts have been projecting that mortgage rates may begin to increase toward the end of the year, which will only make purchasing a home a bit less affordable as time passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a seller in today’s market, now is still a good time to sell. &lt;strong&gt;If you’ve been putting it off, don’t wait much longer.&lt;/strong&gt; This year’s month-over-month gains in the number of homes for sale have helped buyers, but we’re still very much in a seller’s market. More homes are expected to hit the market in the coming months, so selling this summer gives you a chance to get ahead of the competition and maximize your sales potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that more homes for sale mean that buyers have more options and sellers have more competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy or sell or if you have any questions about the local market, reach out to us. Let’s connect today so that we can discuss your options.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 14:03:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-increasing-housing-supply-means-to-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-increasing-housing-supply-means-to-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Tips for Prepping Your Home for a Vacation</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pnH2nxlLqRk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Make sure your home stays safe and sound during your vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you make sure your home is ready for your upcoming vacation? &lt;strong&gt;Here are 10 tips to ensure you don’t come back to any unwanted surprises:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Lock all of your doors and windows.&lt;/strong&gt; This may seem like the most obvious tip, but it can still be forgotten—especially locking the windows. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clear out your mailbox and put your mail on hold.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes any magazines, newspapers, or other subscriptions you have. Subscription boxes (e.g., meal deliveries) tend to be forgotten about the most, so make sure you put those on hold as well. You don’t want these boxes sitting on your front step letting people know you’re gone and/or spoiling because you’re not there to take them in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Use lights to create the illusion that someone is home.&lt;/strong&gt; With the advent of smart lighting, you can control some of your house lights with your phone. You can also use old-school timers—anything to make sure lights are coming on and off and creating the illusion that someone is home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Wait until after you get back home to upload any pictures or videos to your social media profiles.%20http://localhost:4000/10-tips-for-prepping-your-home-for-a-vacation.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Wait until after you get back home to upload any pictures or videos to your social media profiles.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Keep your yard maintained.&lt;/strong&gt; If a landscaping company takes care of your yard, make sure you keep that service scheduled while you’re away. Before you leave, you could also do some extra clipping around the yard so things don’t look overgrown while you’re gone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Leave a car in the driveway.&lt;/strong&gt; This creates the impression that someone is home and lessens the chance that your home becomes a target for burglars. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Hide and lock up your valuables.&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing should be in plain sight. If you have someone checking on your home while you’re away, have them double-check that your valuables are secure and stored away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Don’t broadcast your plans online&lt;/strong&gt;. Going on vacation is a lot of fun, and it’s only natural to want to share your experiences with people you know, but wait until after you get back home to upload any pictures or videos to your social media profiles. Also, think twice before checking into places online. You never know who’s checking that type of thing—especially if your profile is set to a public setting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Activate your security system (if you have one).&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t, perhaps try setting up some cameras. Even as decoys, they can act as deterrents. You don’t need to place your cameras inconspicuously, either. Put them out there so people can see that they’re there. Again, burglars are less likely to target your property if they think a close eye is being kept on it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Adjust your thermostat.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a smart thermostat, that can be set from your phone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Do what you can to prevent water damage.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re traveling during the summer, it might be OK for you to turn off your water main. If you’re traveling during the winter, you probably don’t want to do this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this topic or would like to know more about our local real estate market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 14:11:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/10-tips-for-prepping-your-home-for-a-vacation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/10-tips-for-prepping-your-home-for-a-vacation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Rent-Backs Benefit Buyers &amp; Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jfmHw2asf9Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Rent-backs benefit both buyers and sellers in this market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do seller rent-backs benefit buyers and sellers in this market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seller rent-backs (formally known as ‘post-close occupancies’) have been around for a while; they’re an arrangement when the seller continues living in the home that’s been sold and which the buyer now owns. They can last anywhere from one to 60 days if the buyer is purchasing the home as their primary residence. That said, this time frame can be limited by the buyer’s financing. If the buyer is purchasing the home as an investment property, the rent-back can last as long as needed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rent-backs benefit sellers in that they give them more time to get their future housing plans in order&lt;/strong&gt;. We’re seeing a lot more of this type of situation lately. For example, if a homeowner needs to sell their current home and purchase a new one, they may need the proceeds of the first sale to complete the second one. In our market, 60 days isn’t a very long time, but it can make a difference. If the seller’s closing date is close by and they just need a few extra days to get their affairs in order, the rent-back would only last a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In our current market, it’s not uncommon for buyers to offer free rent-backs to sellers.%20http://localhost:4000/why-rent-backs-benefit-buyers-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In our current market, it’s not uncommon for buyers to offer free rent-backs to sellers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rent-backs benefit buyers when they have a lease that doesn’t end for a while or they have some flexibility in their timeline&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, they can have the seller stay longer and pay rent. However, in our current market, it’s not uncommon for buyers to offer free rent-backs to sellers. They’re looking for any opportunity to make their offers stand out from the crowd. In less competitive markets of the past, a typical rent-back amount would be prorated per day according to the buyer’s daily carrying costs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the risks of a rent-back? The risk for a buyer is that their seller may not move out in time. This can obviously be a challenge if they’ve selected a certain day to move in. Other than that, though, the risks for both sides are minimal. My team and I have a specific addendum we use to document the terms of a rent-back period. Typically, a security deposit is held in escrow while the rent-back takes place. It’s also important that both parties document the condition of the property so that if there are any questions, they have something to refer back to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-rent-backs-benefit-buyers-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-rent-backs-benefit-buyers-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
