<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Madison Area Real Estate Journal</title>
    <description>Our mission at Holt Real Estate Team is to be your best resource for Madison Area real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Holt Real Estate Team, your professional Madison Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 10:35:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 10:35:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in Our Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ndvH2XfDqL8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Long of Guild Mortgage joins me today to dispel some common market misconceptions and share his perspective from the lending side of things. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s going to happen with the market in 2020 and beyond? Many homeowners remember losing value in their homes from 2008 to 2012, but since 2013 home values have been recovering. Since homes have been appreciating for so long, many believe it’s time for a market correction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to understand that &lt;strong&gt;the market fundamentals we have now are different than the ones we had back then.&lt;/strong&gt; Just because the market’s been appreciating for a while doesn’t mean there’s something wrong or properties will start losing value. From 2005 to 2008, we saw rapid appreciation that was unsustainable—prices rose as high as 10% per year. Historically, home values in Dane County appreciate 3% to 4% per year. &lt;em&gt;That’s&lt;/em&gt; sustainable, so if homes keep appreciating at that rate, they’ll outpace inflation and, theoretically, never cool down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you bought a home and something were to go wrong, you’d be fine long-term.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you bought a home and something were to go wrong, you’d be fine long-term.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2013, the pace of home value recovery increased rapidly, but now it’s slowing and we’re settling into a nice, pillowy landing. Last year, home values statewide rose about 5%, and this year they’re predicted to rise between 3% and 4%. &lt;strong&gt;Some might see this slowdown as a bad thing, but this return to normalcy is a good thing.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the average prediction of where the market’s headed in the next five years, if you purchased a $250,000 house now, it would appreciate by $47,500 by January 2025—a nice, slow pace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need a place to live no matter what, and you can either pay your landlord’s rent or your mortgage. Only one of you is getting that appreciation, so you might as well take advantage of that equity. Many people lost a lot of money during the previous recession, but the No. 1 reason people buy houses isn’t that it’s a financial investment but because they want to control where they live. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who lost value starting in 2008 got it all back by 2017. If you bought a home and something were to go wrong, you’d be fine long-term. You’ll still pay off your mortgage and come out with a lot of equity. If nothing goes wrong, you’ll come out &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; ahead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any lending questions, feel free to give Joe a call at (608) 729-5379 or email him at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jlong@guildmortgage.net&quot;&gt;jlong@guildmortgage.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have any other questions about the real estate market, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 16:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Legislative Action All Homeowners Should Follow</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gMfMPJiOka8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, I had the opportunity to go to our state capitol building for the annual Realtor® and Government Day. Today, I’m sharing my experience by recapping the three main topics discussed at the event, as well as sharing my insight on these matters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:29 - The issue of riparian water rights (2018 supreme court case regarding homeowners’ right to build a pier)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:33 - Legislation in the works prohibiting the habit of “chasing sales” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:45 - The lack of workforce housing in our area and proposed remedies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; 6:20 - Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in discussing these important topics in more detail, please feel free to reach out by phone or email. I’d love the opportunity to inform the homeowners in our great state and gain different perspectives on these issues. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 16:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/legislative-action-all-homeowners-should-follow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/legislative-action-all-homeowners-should-follow.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strategies to Help You Win in the Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OBLu6GZNH_w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most markets around the country have been experiencing historically low inventory, meaning that there just aren’t that many homes for sale in first-time homebuyers’ price ranges. It’s not that uncommon for a first-timer to end up in competition with one or even 10 other buyers, so we’ve become pretty crafty and strategic to make our buyers’ offers stand out to the seller. To help me lay out some potential roadmaps to success, Joe Long from Guild Mortgage joins me to discuss some of the strategies that he has seen work for homebuyers in our tricky seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along in the video above or else use the timestamps below to navigate the discussion in depth at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:28—Find out what’s important to the seller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:48—Consider your offer’s terms and contingencies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:08—Use a TBD underwrite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:52—Appraisal forgiveness and a few other tactics to entice a seller to accept your offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, for a home seller, the most important thing isn’t always pricing. Using a combination of these strategies can help you stand out from the crowd and win the home you want in our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the market to buy a home and you’d like to learn more about how we can help you beat the competition for a home you have your sights set on, reach out to us by phone or email. We’d be glad to help you discover tools and tricks to help you succeed in your goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/strategies-to-help-you-win-in-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/strategies-to-help-you-win-in-the-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy into the Recession Doom &amp; Gloom?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wxqFzJjutAw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you’ve heard a lot of buzz from people trying to predict when the next housing crash will be. While I do feel like there’s a good chance that we may see a small recession or some little blips in the economy, there is also good evidence to suggest that we probably won’t see a housing crash like what happened in 2008. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlike the last time that we did have a housing crash, credit has been tightened significantly.&lt;/strong&gt; Lenders are doing their due diligence before approving home loans. The notorious subprime mortgages that helped spur the ‘08 crash are far from the norm in today’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median price in our area went up 6.4% over 2019 to $295,000, all due to a lack of inventory. Our inventory remains low because people that invest in new building projects simply aren’t doing so as much. A lot of builders say they want to start on such projects, but lack the tradespeople needed to keep up with the high demand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Mortgage rates remain at near historic lows.%20http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-into-the-recession-doom-gloom.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Mortgage rates remain at near historic lows.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another reason why inventory is low boils down to demographics.&lt;/strong&gt; A majority of the homeowners now are baby boomers, and they’re simply holding onto their homes longer. This is squaring up directly against the millennial generation, which is primed to make the majority of home purchases in the nation. Not enough homes are available, so competition increases and prices follow suit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mortgage rates remain at or near historic lows. To put this in perspective, pretend you’re in the market for a $250,000 home. If you wanted to maintain that same monthly payment that you’re budgeting for, but mortgage rates were to increase by even 1%, your buying power would be reduced to about $220,000. Move when it makes sense for your particular situation, but know that it’s always wise to take advantage of really low rates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re trying to time your purchase by waiting for the next supposed crash, the chances are high that you’re going to miss out on opportunities. Is there a perfect time to buy or sell a home? Objectively, maybe or maybe not. Subjectively, the right time is whenever you decide. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re ready to buy or sell real estate here in the Madison area, I’d love a chance to talk to you. Give a call or shoot me an email so we can discuss how I can help you achieve your goals for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 16:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-into-the-recession-doom-gloom.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-into-the-recession-doom-gloom.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Take an Inventory of Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uz-f2k3xFp4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a homeowner, it’s very important that you do an inventory of the possessions in your home in the event that something catastrophic happens to it, like a fire. There’s no time like the present to do this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could you name the make, model, and price of all the TVs you own? Do you know where all the jewelry, trinkets, or collectibles are and how much they’re worth? This kind of thing can add up if something catastrophic does happen to your home, and it’s definitely something you don’t want to deal with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I have two main tips for you to remember when doing your home inventory.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;use your smartphone to go room by room and take pictures and video of every important item you want to catalog.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’re done doing that, &lt;strong&gt;use a cloud-based service to upload and store your photos and video.&lt;/strong&gt; In my opinion, Google Drive works best for this. If you already have a Google account, then it’s free. It has quite a bit of storage, and you can also utilize Google Sheets to further itemize your possessions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, the last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is to try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 10:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Decluttering After the Holiday Season</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oOam93P4WKQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you all had a wonderful holiday and are excited for the new year. If you’re like my family, now is the time you look to declutter your home as you prepare for the coming year, and I’ve got some tips to help you do that more easily today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t wait.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t let weeks pass by as your holiday items sit in the home without a proper place. I recommend getting on the task of decluttering right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Prioritize.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re struggling to find a place for one or more items that you have, consider whether the items are something that you need to hold on to. There may be certain items that are important to you and your family, but there may also be other items that you’ve acquired over the years that you don’t really use in your annual decorating. If that’s the case, it might be time to donate or resell those items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A lot of your extra gift wrap and trimmings are recyclable.%20http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A lot of your extra gift wrap and trimmings are recyclable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Organize gift wrap.&lt;/strong&gt; It can be very easy for rolls of gift wrap to get spread out and take up a lot of room. Now is a great time to go through and organize that gift wrap to make sure you’re not holding on to scraps of paper that won’t help you in the future. Maybe you could repurpose those for a craft project or something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Recycle.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that you’re not just tossing all of your extra gift wrap and trimmings in the trash. A lot of this stuff is recycled material and you want to properly dispose of it according to your local recycling priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Prepare for next year.&lt;/strong&gt; You may have things that you kept in storage and didn’t pull out for the holidays. I like to take this time of year to evaluate the inventory I have and see if any of them are ones I intend to hold onto in the future. It’s also just a good time to organize your stuff so that you know where everyone is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about this list or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 10:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seasons Greetings from the Holt Real Estate Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yWBAepuGbbw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all of us here at the Holt Real Estate Team: We wish you and your family the very best this holiday season. This is the time you should spend with your family and friends, and give joy and thanks for all that you have, so enjoy it! Speaking of giving thanks: We appreciate all of your support this year, and we love being able to help people make their real estate dreams come true. Here’s to helping even more of you in 2020! Thank you all so much, and happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 14:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-the-holt-real-estate-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-the-holt-real-estate-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everything You Need to Know About USDA Loans</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PXuzEEE_acU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a low- to moderate-income buyer, or just someone without a significant down payment saved up, then a USDA loan might be the perfect path to homeownership for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The USDA loan program allows homeowners to purchase a qualifying rural property for no money down.&lt;/strong&gt; Like any mortgage option, you will need to meet certain criteria, though. The primary qualifying factors are your income, for which limits will vary by area, as well as the location of the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The bottom line is that the USDA loan is a great option for those savvy enough to take advantage.%20http://localhost:4000/everything-you-need-to-know-about-usda-loans.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The bottom line is that the USDA loan is a great option for those savvy enough to take advantage.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rd.usda.gov/programs-services/single-family-housing-guaranteed-loan-program&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more and for access to a loan availability map showing what properties near you may qualify. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes located within Stoughton city limits, for example, are ineligible, but areas just to the north (near Madison) do qualify—as do properties in the Village of McFarland, the Village of Oregon, Deforest/Windsor/ Mount Horeb, Cambridge, and many other municipalities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that the USDA loan is a great option for those savvy enough to take advantage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 13:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/everything-you-need-to-know-about-usda-loans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/everything-you-need-to-know-about-usda-loans.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Thanksgiving Message From Our Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CU0D6DKTiaA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to take a moment today to say thank you. Thank you to all of you wonderful folks who have trusted us with your real estate needs in the Madison area. We also want to thank those of you who have partnered with our company to ensure that our clients’ experiences are second-to-none. We can’t thank you enough for all that you do to help our team grow and thrive. On behalf of everyone here at The Holt Real Estate Team, thank you for your support and we hope you have a wonderful Thanksgiving. To hear my full message, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-thanksgiving-message-from-our-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-thanksgiving-message-from-our-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons to Buy an Investment Property Before Becoming a Homeowner</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r6m5Fe4kGeE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently someone approached me to ask whether buying an investment property before buying their first primary residence was a good idea, and, actually, it very well may be. Here are five reasons why: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Interest rates are low.&lt;/strong&gt; Low interest rates mean greater purchasing power, which gives those looking to invest a unique opportunity to enjoy low monthly payments on their property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Homes are continuing to appreciate each year.&lt;/strong&gt; According to Core Logic’s value index, home values have increased every year for the past seven years. And, according to most experts, real estate is one of the safest (and wisest) investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you ever tire of renting your property out, or if you’re simply ready to become a homeowner, yourself, there is always the option for you to move into the home.%20http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-buy-an-investment-property-before-becoming-a-homeowner.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you ever tire of renting your property out, or if you’re simply ready to become a homeowner, yourself, there is always the option for you to move into the home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Real estate investing creates passive income.&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond just having someone else cover the expense of your monthly payments, renting out a property means that you can rely on your investment to generate passive income, as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Short-term rentals are popular right now.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if you aren’t interested in being a long-term landlord, short-term rentals are in high demand right now. Airbnb and VRBO have opened up numerous options for investors. Your investment property also doesn’t need to be local. You can purchase a rental property in a tourist “hot spot” and have someone else manage it for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. You can turn the investment into your primary residence later on.&lt;/strong&gt; If you ever tire of renting your property out, or if you’re simply ready to become a homeowner, yourself, there is always the option for you to move into the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-buy-an-investment-property-before-becoming-a-homeowner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-buy-an-investment-property-before-becoming-a-homeowner.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
