<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joshua Holt: Madison Real Estate Agent Video Blog</title>
    <description>Our mission at Holt Real Estate Team is to be your best resource for Madison, WI real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Holt Real Estate Team, your professional Madison, WI Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 12:56:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 12:56:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank You for Supporting RISE</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tt_zA0rqTfk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;We’re more than halfway to our year-end goal of $10,000!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Holt Real Estate Team, giving back to the communities we serve is at the heart of our team’s mission, vision, values, and perspectives. At the beginning of the year, we announced our exciting new partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;https://risewisconsin.org/&quot;&gt;RISE Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt;, our official non-profit organization. We pledged to donate a portion of our profits from each closing to RISE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal for this year was not only to raise awareness for this great organization, but we also wanted to raise at least $10,000 for the center by the end of 2022. Thanks to your support, today &lt;strong&gt;we’re pleased to announce that we have already raised $6,000.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re making strides toward our year-end goal, and we are truly grateful for all your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is looking to buy, sell, or invest in real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to delivering on our promise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thank-you-for-supporting-rise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/thank-you-for-supporting-rise.html</guid>
        
        <category>Giving Back</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Local Market Updates You Have To Know</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r69t_TkhSa8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;What caused the rise in our inventory? It’s not what you might expect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been keeping up with the news, you’ve probably heard a lot of alarming headlines about the housing market. However, you need to remember that real estate is local. That’s why today I want to share some critical points about our Greater Madison market so that you know what’s actually happening locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can listen to my full explanation in the video above or skip to each topic using the timestamps provided:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:00 — Introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:39 — The impact of recession on the housing market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:44 — Recessions don’t automatically equal a housing crisis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:37 — The increase in inventory is due to a slowdown in the pace of sales&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:22 — Supply and demand are the driving factors of the housing market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:49 — There’s still a big deficit in available homes &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:12 — The impact of inflation on mortgage rates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:12 — Listen to reliable news about your local market &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:26 — Wrapping up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need more details about our Greater Madison housing market, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’m always willing to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/local-market-updates-you-have-to-know.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/local-market-updates-you-have-to-know.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Advantages of Getting a Pre-inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yK-9YHXUbsU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Six reasons why getting a pre-inspection before selling is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you consider getting your home pre-inspected before you put it on the market? It may sound counterintuitive, but there are plenty of good reasons to inspect your home when selling. Today I’ll share a few reasons why having a pre-inspection is beneficial to you as a seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can watch my full explanation in the video above or skip to each topic using the timestamps provided:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:00 — Introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:50 — You have a better understanding of the true condition of your home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:12 — You’re ahead of repairs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:09 — You can price your home more accurately&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:46 — You can market your home better&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:24 — You can attract more serious buyers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:03 — You can deal with less negotiations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:16 — Sellers get more control while buyers have more peace of mind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:47 — Wrapping up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need more tips to help you put your best foot forward in the current market, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’ll be happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-advantages-of-getting-a-pre-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-advantages-of-getting-a-pre-inspection.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Truth About Our Supposed 'Housing Bubble'</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-aeUvdGvkjs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;The future of our market is uncertain, but prices likely won’t fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Are you worried about the future of our housing market? You aren’t alone—many clients have reached out to ask me questions about where our market is heading. The truth is that no one knows for sure, but by looking at the latest statistics and trends, we can get a pretty good idea of what the future holds. Today I want to talk about where our real estate market is heading and what it means for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So are we heading for a crash, a correction, or something else? First, none of the experts believe we’re heading for a crash, but I’ll talk more about that later. For a correction to occur, we would need to see a 10% decline in home values, according to Investopedia. Almost no markets around the country are experiencing that sort of decline, so we aren’t in a correction either. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to describe our current market is that we’re at a turning point. &lt;strong&gt;No one knows what will happen for sure because we’ve never seen a housing market like this before.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re coming out of an unprecedented pandemic; inflation is high, supply is low, and demand remains high. Although no one knows what comes next, it looks like sellers will continue to have the upper hand, at least in most markets. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=No experts believe we’re in a housing bubble or heading for a crash. %20http://localhost:4000/the-secret-about-our-supposed-housing-bubble.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“No experts believe we’re in a housing bubble or heading for a crash. ”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve heard on the news that our housing market is correcting, we’re in a housing bubble, or the market is about to collapse, don’t worry. If you check out the chart at 2:11 in the video, you’ll see that the average mortgage rate moves mostly in unison with the 10-year treasury yield. This means that when the Federal Reserve raises rates, it doesn’t have a direct impact on your mortgage interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As I said earlier, no experts believe we’re in a housing bubble or heading for a crash. Despite rising mortgage rates, &lt;strong&gt;we still have an extreme shortage of homes.&lt;/strong&gt; Millennial buyers are still entering the market in large numbers, so demand will remain high even as rates rise. Mortgage rates will likely level off after the initial shock, and many buyers will reenter the market if this occurs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about a recession? You may have heard in the news that the wider economy is heading for a recession, and that is probably true. However, a recession doesn’t mean housing prices will drop. If you look at the chart at 4:23, you’ll see that housing prices actually increased in four out of the last six recessions. The only significant outlier is the 2008 crash; however, our current market is very different from that one. &lt;strong&gt;The bottom line is that while a recession may be coming, our housing market will likely remain strong. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about today’s topic or anything else, please call or email me. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-secret-about-our-supposed-housing-bubble.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-secret-about-our-supposed-housing-bubble.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Will Rising Rates Cause Prices To Drop?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XsAP1BLguqI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s the impact that rising interest rates will have on home prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the recent substantial increase in mortgage interest rates, many homeowners have been asking, “Will this finally cause home prices to drop?” The answer isn’t cut and dry. In a market where rates are predicted to rise even further this year, buyer affordability could take a serious hit. To give you a better idea of whether your home is poised to lose value in the coming months, I’m going to address four key points that explain what’s happening to buyers in the real estate market and what you can expect in the future if you’re thinking about selling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. More expensive mortgages.&lt;/strong&gt; A higher interest rate means a more expensive loan payment, but the rate at which they’re rising is astounding. Rates are up 2% since the start of the year, which means the average homebuyer’s affordability has dropped by 20%. This has already priced some buyers out of the market, and if rates continue to rise as expected, it will price out even more of them. This is going to make the pool of potential buyers for your home much shallower, resulting in fewer offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Continued low supply will keep property values up.%20http://localhost:4000/will-rising-rates-cause-prices-to-drop.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Continued low supply will keep property values up.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Increased rental rates.&lt;/strong&gt; One often-overlooked factor in all of this is rental rates. As homeownership becomes more expensive and more out of reach for some buyers, rental demand is only going to increase, which means that rent prices will jump up as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Supply is still short.&lt;/strong&gt; Although homes are more expensive, the demand for them is still high. The increased interest rates have also caused home sellers to stay in their homes longer, and our typical spring and summer surge of inventory just isn’t happening right now. Low supply is good news for homeowners because it will keep your property values up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. We’re not headed for a crash.&lt;/strong&gt; Some buyers and sellers are rushing to the market in fear of an impending crash. However, there aren’t many parallels between this market and that of 2008 when the last crash occurred. That crisis was the result of irresponsible lending practices. Since then, underwriting standards have tightened significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current frenzied market has been brought on by basic supply and demand, and any kind of market crash is pretty unlikely. According to Brandon Haefele, CEO of Catalyst Mortgage, &lt;em&gt;“I think we’re now going to start seeing individual markets potentially have some slowdown…my reasoning is we still have extremely low inventory. But it’s not going to go the other way and crash.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although rising rates are going to cause some buyers to leave the market entirely, all of the evidence we’ve seen on the ground points to home values continuing to appreciate as long as supply remains this low. This is good news for you if you’re thinking about selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious about what your home could sell for in the current market, check out this home value calculator, which takes recent sales into account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hmbt.co/7HLD7m&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter your address here to find out what your home is worth right now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about selling your home or the real estate market in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/will-rising-rates-cause-prices-to-drop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/will-rising-rates-cause-prices-to-drop.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Debbie Lindquist Loves Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/exewKEmClDM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Meet Debbie Lindquist, a great agent and one of our new sales partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by Debbie Lindquist, a recent addition to our team as one of our sales partners. We’re excited to have her on our team, so we wanted to take some time and introduce her to you all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do before real estate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the important job of being a stay-at-home mom for eight years before I started working in real estate. Before that, I worked at a bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You got into real estate six years ago. How did you connect with Keller Williams?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I interviewed for an admin position for an agent here at KW. After my interview, I decided that I wouldn’t be happy sitting at a desk and doing paperwork; I could do that anywhere. My heart was more in real estate and helping people, so I decided to get my license and become an agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The goal at the end of the day is to have great relationships and help people.%20http://localhost:4000/why-debbie-lindquist-loves-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The goal at the end of the day is to have great relationships and help people.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you decide to join a team? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a solo agent for quite a long time, and it was a roller coaster. It was difficult, and I realized that I needed the support a team could give me. Even when I was on vacation, I was sitting in a hotel room, writing offers. I was never truly off of the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining a team has been awesome, and I love having the support. I think I was always meant to be on a team, so I probably should’ve done it a while ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I definitely feel like teams are the direction real estate is headed. What do you think?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree, and that fact had something to do with my decision to join a team as well. I could see that the market was changing, and I didn’t want to be left behind. As a solo agent, I wanted to be part of a group of people who have the same passion for real estate that I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you hope to accomplish with your clients?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to me is that my clients trust me and know that I have their back. They’re not just a number to me. I really care for them, and I want to help them succeed and be where they want to be. I want to meet great people and become friends with them. The goal at the end of the day is to have great relationships and help people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the best way to get in touch with you? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to work with me, you can give me a call at (608) 216-8933 or email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:debbielind@kw.com&quot;&gt;debbielind@kw.com&lt;/a&gt;. I’m also on social media; just search for my name and contact me. You can also get a hold of Josh and let him know that you want to work with me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can reach out to our team directly anytime at (608) 345-6594. We look forward to the opportunity to help more people as we grow our team, so if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell, we’d love the opportunity to meet them and see if we’d be a good match.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-debbie-lindquist-loves-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-debbie-lindquist-loves-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top Spring and Summer Home-Maintenance Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/o1X7qZOC6ck?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;My five best spring and summer preparation tips for your home in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get the most out of your home this spring and summer, start the process now with these five home-prep tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Clear debris from your yard.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes the dead leaves left over from last fall and any plants that didn’t survive the Wisconsin winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clean gutters and downspouts.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that everything is draining properly and no moisture is pooling around your home’s foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Check your windows.&lt;/strong&gt; Do you have any fogged seals? I can refer you to a great company that can fix it up. You want as much spring and summer sunshine as possible in your home, especially when buyers are seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Prepare for grilling season.&lt;/strong&gt; Clean your grill, wash outdoor furniture, and even stain your deck. Whether you’re hosting a barbecue or a buyer, you’ll be ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Ensure your HVAC system is working properly.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want to wait until it’s too late to notice something is wrong. If you don’t already follow a regular maintenance schedule for this system, today’s a great day to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about these tips or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 15:13:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/top-spring-and-summer-home-maintenance-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/top-spring-and-summer-home-maintenance-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Make it as a Homebuyer Today</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TS7btf42o40?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s how we’re helping clients successfully navigate the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been paying attention to the market, you know we have a lot of activity right now. Buyers have found this particular market challenging, so today we’re going to talk about how we’re helping our homebuyers win in this environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to watch the full video, or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:00 — My message for today’s buyers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:55 — Institutional buyers have changed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:37 — Why we want to meet with you before you start your search&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:22 — The importance of connecting with a great local lender&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:03 — Why we emphasize education with our buyers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:41 — How we help you understand what makes a good offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:28 — How we can get you under contract in this market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:07 — The final step of buying a home: getting clear to close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:31 — Final thoughts/wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know have any questions about buying a home or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-it-as-a-homebuyer-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-it-as-a-homebuyer-today.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Adjustable-Rate Mortgages Work?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dRtawxtM0cM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s what potential buyers should know about adjustable-rate mortgages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’re seeing rates continue to increase, I’ve had a bunch of folks ask me about the differences between adjustable-rate and fixed-rate mortgages. Today I’ll go over the pros and cons of adjustable-rate mortgages, or ARMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to watch the full video, or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:00 — Introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:25 — What’s an adjustable-rate mortgage, or ARM?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:20 — The advantages of using an ARM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:20 — The disadvantages of an ARM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:40 — Why I think we’ll see more ARMs as interest rates increase&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:05 — Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about mortgages, need a good lender, or have any other real estate-related questions, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. My team and I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 16:46:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-adjustable-rate-mortgages-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-adjustable-rate-mortgages-work.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everyone Can Win in This Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U7KiVYkfFbg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;We aren’t in a seller’s market; we’re in a market where everyone can win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard the terms seller’s market and buyer’s market before, but I think we’re currently in a different type of market altogether. What we’re in right now is a winner’s market. Typically, when you have less than six months of inventory, it’s a seller’s market. In that kind of market, home values will appreciate because there’s not enough supply to meet demand. When we have more than six months of inventory, it’s a buyer’s market, and home values tend to depreciate. However, it’s a little more complicated than that right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can watch the full video above or skip to each section using the timestamps provided:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:00 — Introducing today’s topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:42 — We’ve been in a seller’s market since 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:41 — You might have more equity than you think&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:50 — Why this market is here to stay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:11 — How buyers can make the most of this market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:18 — Everyone can win in this market&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:27 — Wrapping up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our local market, feel free to call me or my team at 608-345-6594. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/everyone-can-win-in-this-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/everyone-can-win-in-this-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
