<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joshua Holt: Madison Real Estate Agent Video Blog</title>
    <description>Our mission at Holt Real Estate Team is to be your best resource for Madison, WI real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Holt Real Estate Team, your professional Madison, WI Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 15:51:21 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 15:51:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Home Buying and Selling Works Right Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nkbvfuErRWg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the process of buying or selling a home look during the COVID-19 pandemic? I’ve been hearing that question a lot lately, and I’m going to dive into the topic today so that you have a clear, detailed answer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along in the video above or use the timestamps I’ve provided below to navigate the discussion at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:25- The first question home sellers should be asking themselves before deciding to take the leap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:15- A few more factors for home sellers to consider in order to enhance their experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:15- Advice for nervous buyers who are hesitant to purchase right now&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:05- How to embrace a more digital real estate market with the proper plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:55- A note about coronavirus addendums for both buyers and sellers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:50- Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions for me about buying, selling, or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email today. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 14:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-home-buying-and-selling-works-right-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-home-buying-and-selling-works-right-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Economy After COVID-19</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J_dOEpebjcc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human toll of the coronavirus pandemic may forever change families, yet the economic impact will rebound with a cycle of downturn followed by economic expansion, as we’ve seen play out in the U.S. economy many times before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to share what leading experts and current research indicate about the economic impact we’ll likely see as a result of COVID-19. Let’s start with a forecast of the U.S. Gross Domestic Product (GDP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at GDP (the measure of our country’s economic health), a survey of three leading financial institutions projects a sharp decline followed by a steep rebound in the second half of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A recent study from John Burns Consulting notes that past pandemics have created V-shaped economic recoveries, and had minimal impact on housing prices.&lt;/strong&gt; This certainly gives us hope and optimism regarding what is to come as this crisis passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This won’t last forever, and we will get back to growth mode—we’ve got this.%20http://localhost:4000/our-economy-after-covid-19.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This won’t last forever, and we will get back to growth mode—we’ve got this.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this historical analysis in mind, many business owners are also optimistically anticipating a bright economic return. A recent PricewaterhouseCoopers survey captures this confidence, &lt;strong&gt;noting 66% of surveyed business owners believe their companies will return to normal business rhythms within a month of the pandemic passing&lt;/strong&gt;, and 90% feel they should be back to normal operation one to three months afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From expert financial institutions to business leaders across the country, we can clearly see that a quick return to normal once the current crisis subsides is not too far away. In essence, this pandemic won’t last forever, and we will get back to growth mode—we’ve got this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lives and businesses are being impacted by COVID-19, but &lt;strong&gt;experts do see a light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/strong&gt; As the economy slows down due to the health crisis, we can take the guidance and advice from experts that this too will pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate, please feel free to reach out via phone or email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-economy-after-covid-19.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/our-economy-after-covid-19.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Sweet Tax Deductions When Selling a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SgcVgxN1YfQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be wondering if there are tax deductions you can take when selling a home. The answer is: You bet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, you may remember that 2018’s new tax code—aka the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act—changed some rules for homeowners. Rest assured that if you sold your home last year (or are planning to in the future), your tax deductions when you file with the IRS can still amount to sizable savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five different tax deductions you can take as a home seller:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Selling costs.&lt;/strong&gt; These deductions are allowed as long as they are directly tied to the sale of the home and you lived in the home for at least two out of the five years preceding the sale. Another caveat: The home must be a principal residence and not an investment property. These costs can include legal fees, title fees, advertising costs, commissions, and perhaps even staging costs. Just remember that you can’t deduct these costs in the same way as, say, mortgage interest. Instead, you subtract them from the sale price of your home, which in turn positively affects your capital gains tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I recommend consulting with your tax advisor for further clarification.%20http://localhost:4000/5-sweet-tax-deductions-when-selling-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I recommend consulting with your tax advisor for further clarification.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Home improvements and repairs.&lt;/strong&gt; If you renovated a few rooms to make your home more marketable (so you could fetch a higher sale price), you can deduct those upgrade costs as well. This includes painting the house or repairing the roof or water heater. There’s a catch, and it all boils down to timing: You can deduct those expenses as selling costs as long as they were made within 90 days of the closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Property taxes.&lt;/strong&gt; This deduction is capped at $10,000. So, if you were dutifully paying your property taxes up to the point when you sold your home, you can deduct the amount you paid in property taxes this year up to $10,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Mortgage interest.&lt;/strong&gt; As with property taxes, you can deduct the interest on your mortgage for the portion of the year you owned your home. Just remember that under the 2018 tax code, new homeowners (and home sellers) can deduct the interest on up to only $750,000 of mortgage debt. That is, unless you obtained your mortgage prior to December 15, 2017. If you did, you can deduct up to $1,000,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the mortgage interest and property taxes are itemized deductions. This means that, in order for it to work in your favor, all of your itemized deductions need to be greater than the new standard deduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Capital gains tax for sellers.&lt;/strong&gt; The rule isn’t technically a deduction (it’s an exclusion), but you’re still going to like it. As a reminder, capital gains are your profits from selling your home—whatever cash is left after paying off your expenses, plus any outstanding mortgage debt. These profits are taxed as income, but here’s the good news: You can exclude up to $250,000 of the capital gains from the sale if you’re single, and $500,000 if married. The only big catch is that you must have lived in your home at least two of the past five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want further clarification on these five sweet tax deductions, I recommend you consult with your tax advisor. If you have any real estate-related questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-sweet-tax-deductions-when-selling-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-sweet-tax-deductions-when-selling-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What the Coronavirus Means for Our Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uTJ8S-vgDJ0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you’re aware, there’s been a lot of talk in the news lately about the coronavirus, and many people have reached out to me wondering how this will impact our real estate market.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we try to predict what will happen in our local market, whether it’s due to the coronavirus or any other factor, &lt;strong&gt;we look to what’s happening on our nation’s coasts,&lt;/strong&gt; meaning markets like Los Angeles, New York City, and San Francisco. These are good leading indicators of trends that will eventually impact our market. When we see a shift in the luxury markets out on the coast, that’s something we’ll probably see in South Central Wisconsin sooner rather than later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If your home is valued above that or the $500,000 mark, I recommend listing it sooner rather than later.%20http://localhost:4000/what-the-coronavirus-means-for-our-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If your home is valued above that or the $500,000 mark, I recommend listing it sooner rather than later.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re buying or selling, if you’re concerned about the coronavirus’ impact on our market, &lt;strong&gt;my first piece of advice is to reach out to me.&lt;/strong&gt; We can talk about your goals and formulate a strategy to accomplish them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a seller, one thing we do know is that the median home price in Dane County is $285,000, so if your home is valued above that or the $500,000 mark, I recommend listing it sooner rather than later. We still have limited inventory and there are plenty of buyers, so strike while the iron is hot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, because of the volatility we’re seeing in the stock market due to the coronavirus, mortgage rates remain lower than last year. This is making the biggest impact below the $285,000 price point. Inventory is already tight in this market, and low interest rates will bring out more buyers and increase competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we don’t want to see happen is sellers thinking now is a great time to raise prices, because that might not play out how you imagine it. Like I said, I recommend first giving me a call so we can find out what your home is worth, make a plan, and capture the attention of all the buyers out there taking advantage of these low interest rates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, we’ll keep an eye on this situation. If you have any questions about this topic at all, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 12:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-the-coronavirus-means-for-our-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-the-coronavirus-means-for-our-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in Our Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ndvH2XfDqL8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Long of Guild Mortgage joins me today to dispel some common market misconceptions and share his perspective from the lending side of things. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s going to happen with the market in 2020 and beyond? Many homeowners remember losing value in their homes from 2008 to 2012, but since 2013 home values have been recovering. Since homes have been appreciating for so long, many believe it’s time for a market correction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to understand that &lt;strong&gt;the market fundamentals we have now are different than the ones we had back then.&lt;/strong&gt; Just because the market’s been appreciating for a while doesn’t mean there’s something wrong or properties will start losing value. From 2005 to 2008, we saw rapid appreciation that was unsustainable—prices rose as high as 10% per year. Historically, home values in Dane County appreciate 3% to 4% per year. &lt;em&gt;That’s&lt;/em&gt; sustainable, so if homes keep appreciating at that rate, they’ll outpace inflation and, theoretically, never cool down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you bought a home and something were to go wrong, you’d be fine long-term.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you bought a home and something were to go wrong, you’d be fine long-term.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2013, the pace of home value recovery increased rapidly, but now it’s slowing and we’re settling into a nice, pillowy landing. Last year, home values statewide rose about 5%, and this year they’re predicted to rise between 3% and 4%. &lt;strong&gt;Some might see this slowdown as a bad thing, but this return to normalcy is a good thing.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the average prediction of where the market’s headed in the next five years, if you purchased a $250,000 house now, it would appreciate by $47,500 by January 2025—a nice, slow pace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need a place to live no matter what, and you can either pay your landlord’s rent or your mortgage. Only one of you is getting that appreciation, so you might as well take advantage of that equity. Many people lost a lot of money during the previous recession, but the No. 1 reason people buy houses isn’t that it’s a financial investment but because they want to control where they live. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who lost value starting in 2008 got it all back by 2017. If you bought a home and something were to go wrong, you’d be fine long-term. You’ll still pay off your mortgage and come out with a lot of equity. If nothing goes wrong, you’ll come out &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; ahead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any lending questions, feel free to give Joe a call at (608) 729-5379 or email him at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jlong@guildmortgage.net&quot;&gt;jlong@guildmortgage.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have any other questions about the real estate market, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 16:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Legislative Action All Homeowners Should Follow</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gMfMPJiOka8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, I had the opportunity to go to our state capitol building for the annual Realtor® and Government Day. Today, I’m sharing my experience by recapping the three main topics discussed at the event, as well as sharing my insight on these matters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:29 - The issue of riparian water rights (2018 supreme court case regarding homeowners’ right to build a pier)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:33 - Legislation in the works prohibiting the habit of “chasing sales” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:45 - The lack of workforce housing in our area and proposed remedies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; 6:20 - Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in discussing these important topics in more detail, please feel free to reach out by phone or email. I’d love the opportunity to inform the homeowners in our great state and gain different perspectives on these issues. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 16:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/legislative-action-all-homeowners-should-follow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/legislative-action-all-homeowners-should-follow.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strategies to Help You Win in the Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OBLu6GZNH_w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most markets around the country have been experiencing historically low inventory, meaning that there just aren’t that many homes for sale in first-time homebuyers’ price ranges. It’s not that uncommon for a first-timer to end up in competition with one or even 10 other buyers, so we’ve become pretty crafty and strategic to make our buyers’ offers stand out to the seller. To help me lay out some potential roadmaps to success, Joe Long from Guild Mortgage joins me to discuss some of the strategies that he has seen work for homebuyers in our tricky seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along in the video above or else use the timestamps below to navigate the discussion in depth at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:28—Find out what’s important to the seller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:48—Consider your offer’s terms and contingencies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4:08—Use a TBD underwrite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:52—Appraisal forgiveness and a few other tactics to entice a seller to accept your offer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, for a home seller, the most important thing isn’t always pricing. Using a combination of these strategies can help you stand out from the crowd and win the home you want in our market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in the market to buy a home and you’d like to learn more about how we can help you beat the competition for a home you have your sights set on, reach out to us by phone or email. We’d be glad to help you discover tools and tricks to help you succeed in your goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/strategies-to-help-you-win-in-the-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/strategies-to-help-you-win-in-the-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy into the Recession Doom &amp; Gloom?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wxqFzJjutAw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you’ve heard a lot of buzz from people trying to predict when the next housing crash will be. While I do feel like there’s a good chance that we may see a small recession or some little blips in the economy, there is also good evidence to suggest that we probably won’t see a housing crash like what happened in 2008. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlike the last time that we did have a housing crash, credit has been tightened significantly.&lt;/strong&gt; Lenders are doing their due diligence before approving home loans. The notorious subprime mortgages that helped spur the ‘08 crash are far from the norm in today’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median price in our area went up 6.4% over 2019 to $295,000, all due to a lack of inventory. Our inventory remains low because people that invest in new building projects simply aren’t doing so as much. A lot of builders say they want to start on such projects, but lack the tradespeople needed to keep up with the high demand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Mortgage rates remain at near historic lows.%20http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-into-the-recession-doom-gloom.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Mortgage rates remain at near historic lows.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another reason why inventory is low boils down to demographics.&lt;/strong&gt; A majority of the homeowners now are baby boomers, and they’re simply holding onto their homes longer. This is squaring up directly against the millennial generation, which is primed to make the majority of home purchases in the nation. Not enough homes are available, so competition increases and prices follow suit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mortgage rates remain at or near historic lows. To put this in perspective, pretend you’re in the market for a $250,000 home. If you wanted to maintain that same monthly payment that you’re budgeting for, but mortgage rates were to increase by even 1%, your buying power would be reduced to about $220,000. Move when it makes sense for your particular situation, but know that it’s always wise to take advantage of really low rates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re trying to time your purchase by waiting for the next supposed crash, the chances are high that you’re going to miss out on opportunities. Is there a perfect time to buy or sell a home? Objectively, maybe or maybe not. Subjectively, the right time is whenever you decide. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re ready to buy or sell real estate here in the Madison area, I’d love a chance to talk to you. Give a call or shoot me an email so we can discuss how I can help you achieve your goals for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 16:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-into-the-recession-doom-gloom.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-into-the-recession-doom-gloom.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Take an Inventory of Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uz-f2k3xFp4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a homeowner, it’s very important that you do an inventory of the possessions in your home in the event that something catastrophic happens to it, like a fire. There’s no time like the present to do this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could you name the make, model, and price of all the TVs you own? Do you know where all the jewelry, trinkets, or collectibles are and how much they’re worth? This kind of thing can add up if something catastrophic does happen to your home, and it’s definitely something you don’t want to deal with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I have two main tips for you to remember when doing your home inventory.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;use your smartphone to go room by room and take pictures and video of every important item you want to catalog.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’re done doing that, &lt;strong&gt;use a cloud-based service to upload and store your photos and video.&lt;/strong&gt; In my opinion, Google Drive works best for this. If you already have a Google account, then it’s free. It has quite a bit of storage, and you can also utilize Google Sheets to further itemize your possessions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, the last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is to try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 10:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Decluttering After the Holiday Season</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oOam93P4WKQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you all had a wonderful holiday and are excited for the new year. If you’re like my family, now is the time you look to declutter your home as you prepare for the coming year, and I’ve got some tips to help you do that more easily today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t wait.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t let weeks pass by as your holiday items sit in the home without a proper place. I recommend getting on the task of decluttering right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Prioritize.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re struggling to find a place for one or more items that you have, consider whether the items are something that you need to hold on to. There may be certain items that are important to you and your family, but there may also be other items that you’ve acquired over the years that you don’t really use in your annual decorating. If that’s the case, it might be time to donate or resell those items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A lot of your extra gift wrap and trimmings are recyclable.%20http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A lot of your extra gift wrap and trimmings are recyclable.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Organize gift wrap.&lt;/strong&gt; It can be very easy for rolls of gift wrap to get spread out and take up a lot of room. Now is a great time to go through and organize that gift wrap to make sure you’re not holding on to scraps of paper that won’t help you in the future. Maybe you could repurpose those for a craft project or something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Recycle.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that you’re not just tossing all of your extra gift wrap and trimmings in the trash. A lot of this stuff is recycled material and you want to properly dispose of it according to your local recycling priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Prepare for next year.&lt;/strong&gt; You may have things that you kept in storage and didn’t pull out for the holidays. I like to take this time of year to evaluate the inventory I have and see if any of them are ones I intend to hold onto in the future. It’s also just a good time to organize your stuff so that you know where everyone is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about this list or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 10:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
