<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joshua Holt: Madison Real Estate Agent Video Blog</title>
    <description>Our mission at Holt Real Estate Team is to be your best resource for Madison, WI real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Holt Real Estate Team, your professional Madison, WI Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 12:54:01 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 12:54:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy and Sell Homes Simultaneously</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/te9Flxr2A68?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the median sale price in our area up 13.9% year to date, many homeowners want to capitalize on the market by selling. When you need to buy a new home at the same time, that’s where things can get tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers are regularly seeing multiple offers, few to no contingencies, and quick sales. Most people, especially families with kids, don’t want to move twice. &lt;strong&gt;If you have the vision and motivation to buy and sell in this market, we can make it happen.&lt;/strong&gt; These are the questions you need to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Can you afford to buy without selling your current home first?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Can you borrow against the equity in your current home?&lt;/strong&gt; The average home in Wisconsin has gained $19,000 in equity over the past year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We don’t know when a market shift might occur.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-homes-simultaneously.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We don’t know when a market shift might occur.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Can you sell your current property first and find temporary housing?&lt;/strong&gt; A short-term rental, family or friend, or short-term hotel are all options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Can you sell first and negotiate a delayed closing or rent-back?&lt;/strong&gt; This allows you to get the proceeds from your home sale to buy your next home without having to move twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Can you list your home subject to finding suitable housing?&lt;/strong&gt; This is something we’re starting to see more and more in this market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that buyers are more flexible than they used to be, but we don’t know how long that will last or when a market shift might occur. If you have any questions for us or are looking to buy or sell in the near future, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 11:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-homes-simultaneously.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-homes-simultaneously.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Buying in a Seller’s Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X3X7JOJzLt8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an incredibly strong seller’s market right now, and competition among buyers is fierce. If you’re thinking about starting the home search, there are a few things you’ll want to keep in mind. &lt;strong&gt;Here are five tips for buying a home while in a seller’s market:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Qualify for the lowest mortgage rate you can.&lt;/strong&gt; Home prices have been high, and they still may rise by another 5.7% by the end of the year. Thankfully, record-low interest rates can help offset some of the cost. There are also ways you can make the rate even better: Before you go to the lender, work on boosting your credit score, paying down debt, settling overdue accounts, and alerting credit bureaus of any errors. Putting forth a higher down payment can also help your rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Get pre-approved before starting your search.&lt;/strong&gt; It may seem a good idea to search online and try to schedule an appointment when you find your dream house. Unfortunately, most sellers won’t even let you in the door unless you can prove you have the financial ability to purchase their home. So, meet with a lender and get your pre-approval established before you try to go to showings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Though we may be a seller’s market, that doesn’t mean finding and winning a home is impossible.%20http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-buying-in-a-sellers-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Though we may be a seller’s market, that doesn’t mean finding and winning a home is impossible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Work with an experienced agent.&lt;/strong&gt; There are a lot of agents out there, but many only commit to real estate as a hobby or part-time gig. Not all of them will have the skills needed to help you navigate the market successfully. Find a Realtor who has the experience, tools, and information that buyers and sellers need in order to win. For example, The Holt Real Estate team can tour properties on your behalf, find little-known homes that are hitting the market soon, and represent you through every part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Consider buying when the market isn’t so hot.&lt;/strong&gt; Most experts predict the market will cool off a bit later in the year. As more people get vaccinated, it’s likely that many sellers will feel comfortable enough to finally put their homes on the market. In fact, an economist from Realtor.com says that the 2021 market will be more hospitable toward buyers as new construction ramps up and more listings arrive. If you can wait a few more months to buy, it may be a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Make your offer stand out.&lt;/strong&gt; In this market, you’ll want to pull out all the stops to make an attractive offer. However, a good offer isn’t all about price. You should also be flexible with your closing day, and you can perhaps give the seller extra time to move out after the deal is complete. You can remove contingencies and add more to your earnest money deposit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though we may be a seller’s market, that doesn’t mean finding and winning a home is impossible. If you have any questions or would like more information about our market, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 13:32:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-buying-in-a-sellers-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-buying-in-a-sellers-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Misconceptions About Seller’s Markets</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UUGfxGGqxks?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following real estate market news, you likely know we’re in a red-hot seller’s market, homes are selling for way over asking price, sellers are receiving great terms and conditions, and things are currently a little crazy. Due to everything that’s going on, I’m sharing four common misconceptions about a strong seller’s market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. You must plan for your next home before listing your current one.&lt;/strong&gt; I believe this misconception is what’s keeping most people from putting their houses on the market right now. Many people think they can’t list their property for sale until they already have their next home lined up. In reality, in the present market, sellers control more terms and conditions than usual. Asking for an extended closing date or negotiating a post-closing occupancy of up to 60 days gives sellers time to find their next house after they’ve secured an offer on their current one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The home’s condition doesn’t matter.&lt;/strong&gt; Plenty of people think they can just list their property in any condition and it’ll sell quickly. Sometimes an as-is sale makes sense and is the best approach, but that isn’t normally the case. In truth, the condition still sells the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Houses in the best condition will sell quicker and for the most money. When you hear that people are getting wildly high offers and excellent terms, it’s because their properties are in their best conditions. You may need to paint, clean, declutter, and do all the other things to prepare the home that you would do in any market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In the present market, sellers control more terms and conditions than usual.%20http://localhost:4000/4-misconceptions-about-sellers-markets.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In the present market, sellers control more terms and conditions than usual.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You can price your home above market value.&lt;/strong&gt; In our market, it’s crucial to set an appropriate asking price. Buyers are already concerned about overpaying and fatigued by what they’ve been experiencing out in the market. If you list your house higher than it should be, tons of buyers will simply avoid it. Ultimately, you’ll be playing catch-up and will probably sell for less than you would have if you’d priced it correctly from the beginning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You don’t need a Realtor.&lt;/strong&gt; Since everything’s selling so quickly, there’s a temptation to sell your property on your own and save a little money. However, homes are receiving multiple offers and a slew of showings, and you need an expert in your corner who knows how to help you manage the process. Real estate agents qualify buyers before they walk through the house so that only those capable of making an offer are allowed to view it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the offers start pouring in, you need someone who can help negotiate the best terms for your situation. It’s not always about the highest price; numerous other things go into an offer. You may also be tempted to use a discount broker who will just list the property on the MLS and leave the rest of the work to you. However, if you want to maximize your position in today’s market, you need an expert agent that will provide the world-class marketing your home deserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this market or how to sell your house, you can always give us a call or send an email. We’d love to talk to you about what your home is worth and how we’d maximize your position in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-misconceptions-about-sellers-markets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-misconceptions-about-sellers-markets.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Top Spring Cleaning Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cAg-tGxKBI0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re thinking about listing your home for sale this spring or you’re already in your forever home, these spring cleaning tips can be of value to any homeowner: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Windows.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure that you take time to clean not only the outsides of your windows but also the insides; buyers will check out both. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Curb appeal.&lt;/strong&gt; Walk around the perimeter of your home and tackle any areas that need to be cleaned, trimmed, or repainted. Oftentimes, you’ll find debris and buildup leftover from winter. Also, take a look at your front door—has it seen better days? A fresh coat of paint could bring it back to life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you truly looked at the address numbers on your house? Straighten them if they’re misaligned and make sure they’re not faded. While you’re at it, test your exterior lights to make sure everything is in working order. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The kitchen receives a lot of traffic, so it should receive some extra attention when cleaning.%20http://localhost:4000/my-top-spring-cleaning-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The kitchen receives a lot of traffic, so it should receive some extra attention when cleaning.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Kitchen.&lt;/strong&gt; This is easily the top priority inside your home. Focus on your appliances; do a good refrigerator and freezer clean-out, run a clean cycle on the dishwasher, etc. The kitchen receives a lot of traffic, so it should receive some extra attention when cleaning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Bathrooms.&lt;/strong&gt; No one likes deep cleaning toilets, sinks, and tile floors, but it’s a must. If you have fabric shower curtains, run those through a gentle wash cycle. Or, if yours are older shower curtains, perhaps it’s time to replace them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, these are just some great starting points; we have a fairly comprehensive spring cleaning checklist that we’d be more than happy to share with you. If you’re interested in receiving a copy of that or have any questions about the spring selling season, give us a call or send an email. We’d love to hear from you and find out how we can be of service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-top-spring-cleaning-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/my-top-spring-cleaning-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Sellers Can Deal With Low Appraisals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dbgK0X4CN0I?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when an appraisal comes in short? This is certainly an appropriate concern in our current real estate market, as prices look like they’re on a never-ending upward trajectory. As a seller, you have three options when an appraiser doesn’t value your home for the price you agreed to sell it for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;check the appraisal for human error.&lt;/strong&gt; Mistakes can happen, so perhaps something got miscalculated. Take a thorough look through your home’s appraisal and see whether there are any issues that could’ve caused it to come in low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything checks out, your next option is to &lt;strong&gt;prepare a rebuttal with the help of your agent.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes this works, sometimes it doesn’t. In any case, your agent can evaluate the comparable properties the appraiser used and see whether they were justified. If possible, they can also prepare their own list of comparable properties that can bring the appraisal up to where you need it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It can be challenging to get any adjustments made in an appraisal.%20http://localhost:4000/how-sellers-can-deal-with-low-appraisals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It can be challenging to get any adjustments made in an appraisal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, depending on where things are in the contract-to-close period, don’t assume that the buyer actually wants the appraisal to come in low, because that could adversely impact them as well. I’ll be honest with you: It can be challenging to get any adjustments made in an appraisal. Oftentimes, appraisers will choose to stick to their guns, but a rebuttal is still a shot worth taking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If a rebuttal doesn’t work, you’ll have to return to the negotiating table&lt;/strong&gt; and see if you and the buyer can still make the transaction work. Who knows, maybe all you need is a slight adjustment to turn things into a win-win situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, give me a call or send me an email. I’m always available to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 06:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-sellers-can-deal-with-low-appraisals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-sellers-can-deal-with-low-appraisals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Reasons NOT to Wait Until Spring to Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aQhsQ4vhCS4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I met with a client of mine who had been debating whether to wait a few months into the spring market to list their home or do it now. I shared with them these four reasons why now might be the absolute best time to act: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Motivated buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; When your home’s listed on the mid- to late-winter market, you’ll be encountering far more serious buyers than those you’d be attracting in spring. They’ve already taken the steps to ensure they’re pre-approved, they know exactly what they want, and they most likely have life circumstances that necessitate purchasing a home as soon as possible (e.g., job relocation). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Less competition.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people still buy into the conventional wisdom that says it’s best to take a home off the market around the holidays and/or during the Wisconsin winter months. This predictable behavior results in even less inventory in a market that’s already dealing with an inventory shortage. Contrary to popular belief, people do still have to buy when the temperatures bottom out and snow covers the ground. Just by &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; on the market now, you’ll capture a larger share of this motivated buyer pool. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can enjoy everything the spring market has to offer right now but with even more advantages.%20http://localhost:4000/4-reasons-not-to-wait-until-spring-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can enjoy everything the spring market has to offer right now but with even more advantages.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The spring market has already started.&lt;/strong&gt; Truth be told, real estate is no longer as dominated by seasonality as it once was. We’re encountering extremely high demand on every one of our current listings, which proves that sellers can now find themselves firmly in the driver’s seat even in wintertime. By listing now, you’ll be able to find buyers who are more willing to accommodate your needs. Forget about having to negotiate for favorable terms—the buyers will be &lt;em&gt;leading&lt;/em&gt; with highly attractive terms. Given our market conditions, buyers are willing to do what it takes to get into a home they love. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You can show off your home’s unique features.&lt;/strong&gt; Perhaps you have a charming fireplace to light up when these shorter days give way to darkness. Maybe you have a cozy living room that lends itself well to buyers’ visions of staying nice and warm with loved ones as they watch the first snowfall. Alternatively, it could be the case that your landscaping isn’t quite where it needs to be; a little snow cover will conveniently blanket any eyesores. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus reason: low inventory. Yes, I already touched on this, but I can’t stress it enough: We’re dealing with &lt;em&gt;the lowest inventory that we have &lt;u&gt;ever&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;seen.&lt;/em&gt; So, as long as they are no other major life factors preventing you from putting your home on the market today, then you’ll benefit greatly from getting ahead of the so-called “best selling season” of spring. You can enjoy everything the spring market has to offer right now but with even more advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like help getting the selling process started, please reach out via phone or email anytime. It would be our pleasure to guide you through all that’s required to make your home market-ready. We have the tools to help you sell quickly and for top dollar so that you can move on to the next chapter of your life with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 13:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-reasons-not-to-wait-until-spring-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-reasons-not-to-wait-until-spring-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Appraisals vs. Inspections</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zf8vIMDqr2c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference between an appraisal and an inspection? In the simplest terms, a home’s appraisal calculates its value, while an inspection determines its condition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the purpose of an appraisal? When you apply for a mortgage (or, occasionally, when you’re using cash to purchase), &lt;strong&gt;an unbiased appraisal is the best way to confirm the value of the home&lt;/strong&gt; based on the sale price, regardless of what you’re willing to pay for it. This is especially critical in today’s seller’s market where low inventory is increasing bidding wars and pushing prices upward. However, your lender will only allow you to borrow based on the true value of the home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In the simplest terms, a home’s appraisal calculates its value, while an inspection determines its condition.%20http://localhost:4000/appraisals-vs-inspections.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In the simplest terms, a home’s appraisal calculates its value, while an inspection determines its condition.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A home inspection, meanwhile, determines the current state, safety, and condition of the home before you finalize the sale. If any issue were to come up (e.g., the condition of the roof or A/C unit), it counts as an opportunity for the buyer and seller to negotiate the terms of the sale before closing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that the appraisal and inspection are critical steps in purchasing a home. Of course, they’re not steps you need to take alone. &lt;strong&gt;We at the Holt Real Estate Team are here to guide you every step of the way&lt;/strong&gt;, from the beginning of your home search to the closing table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to purchase a home, give us a call or send an email. My team and I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:20:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/appraisals-vs-inspections.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/appraisals-vs-inspections.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Do You Live in Your Home While Selling It?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_VAYjgIGwwQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of putting your home on the market, you might be wondering: How can I live in my home while trying to sell it? Here are five steps to follow that will make things easier and less stressful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Start packing now.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s best to start packing up any items you don’t need daily and get them out of the way so they’re not taking up space. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sell, donate, or give it away.&lt;/strong&gt; Moving is a great opportunity to purge yourself of things you’ve collected over the years that you don’t use anymore or won’t miss if they’re gone. I recommend selling, donating, or giving these things away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Get squeaky clean.&lt;/strong&gt; Now is the time to ensure your home shines, so deep clean as much as possible. It’s been proven that homes that show well due to being clean and well-kept generate higher offers than those that are dirty and unkept. If you list your home with The Holt Real Estate Team, we’ll enlist the service of professional cleaners to clean your home before taking its listing photos so it looks its absolute best. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s been proven that homes that are clean and well-kept generate higher offers.%20http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-live-in-your-home-while-selling-it.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s been proven that homes that are clean and well-kept generate higher offers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Maintain your privacy and security.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you don’t leave out any personal documents or valuable items during showings and open houses. Pack these things up and store them in a secure location. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Involve your kids.&lt;/strong&gt; You wouldn’t believe how motivated kids can get when you attach something fun to a chore. You can make a game out of packing away their toys, for example. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to professional cleaning services, if you list with our team, you’ll get professional staging, photography, video, and a comprehensive marketing plan. This guarantees that we’ll sell your home for the best price in the exact timeline you need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 16:07:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-live-in-your-home-while-selling-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-live-in-your-home-while-selling-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Will Shape Our Market in 2021?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2_3cqrv7fp4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite everything, the housing market was one sector of the economy that performed consistently well throughout 2020. What do experts think this coming year will bring? Here are four trends to watch out for: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Prices will continue to rise.&lt;/strong&gt; If inventory remains as low as it has, it’s possible that prices will continue to go up. The median sold price for properties in our area was $315,000 this year—a 6.8% increase compared to 2019. Inventory also further declined by 26.3% year over year. Despite a quick burst of new listings toward the end of the summer (perhaps due to a delay in the market caused by the pandemic), a dwindling supply of houses is great news for sellers but not so much for buyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Suburbs will reign supreme.&lt;/strong&gt; We talked about this trend early this year, and it looks like it will continue. As more and more folks find out that it’s easier for them to work remotely or that proximity to where they work isn’t as important, they’ll look to buy homes farther and farther away from city centers. Many people are starting to look toward neighboring counties or smaller communities where they can get a bigger bang for their buck. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Historically low rates have brought buyers out en masse, which has caused low inventory, rising prices, and a flurry of activity.%20http://localhost:4000/q-what-will-shape-our-market-in-2021.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Historically low rates have brought buyers out en masse, which has caused low inventory, rising prices, and a flurry of activity.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Increased builder confidence.&lt;/strong&gt; Builders are becoming more confident in their futures, and we’re now seeing more and more new construction starts happening than we’ve seen in the past few years. Also, buyers who aren’t finding what they’re looking for in the resale market are turning to the new construction market as an alternative to find a home that fits their needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Mortgage rates will remain low.&lt;/strong&gt; Mortgage rates hit several record lows throughout 2020, and this trend seems likely to continue—at least during the early part of 2021. Historically low rates have brought buyers out en masse, which has caused low inventory, rising prices, and a flurry of activity. We’re no longer seeing a seasonality in our market. Instead, buyers are buying when they need to buy and sellers are selling when they need to sell. Buyers, especially, are trying hard to capitalize on these low mortgage rates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about our local real estate market or there’s a topic you’d like to see me cover in a future video, call or email me anytime. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 16:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-will-shape-our-market-in-2021.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-will-shape-our-market-in-2021.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays From the Holt Team</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oPDLczs2qM8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to take a moment to wish you and yours a happy holiday season. We hope that you’re able to enjoy this wonderful time of year and spend time with those you love and care about deeply—whether it’s in person or from a distance. Thank you for your continued support of our business this year and in the past. We love being able to help people turn their real estate dreams into reality. We look forward to serving you for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be a busier time in the year for most folks, but please know that we are always here for you. If you ever have any questions, need any assistance, or would like additional guidance, you can always give us a call. If we don’t hear from you before 2021, have a happy New Year’s!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 16:03:13 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/happy-holidays-from-the-holt-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/happy-holidays-from-the-holt-team.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
