<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Madison Area Real Estate Podcast with Joshua Holt</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holt Real Estate Team - your professional Madison Area Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Joshua Holt</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-07-25 14:59:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Joshua Holt</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>jdholt@kw.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Joshua Holt</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Madison Area Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holt Real Estate Team - your professional Madison Area Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest News and Notes From Our Summer Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-latest-news-and-notes-from-our-summer-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-19 11:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/The+Latest+News+and+Notes+From+Our+Summer+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the latest news on our Dane County market and beyond?  

Much like the last few months and years, we’re seeing a scarcity of inventory in certain segments of our market. Conditions continue to bode well for sellers, but we’re also seeing some changes that may signal greater opportunities for buyers. 

Recently, Dane County has seen an uptick in the number of homes on the market, both in terms of single-family homes and condos: 1,000 single-family properties and 225 condos are currently listed. 

Another recent development is homes are spending more time on the market. For single-family homes, the average days on market is 67 days, and the average condo is sitting on the market for a little over 120 days.  

I’m constantly being asked about inventory and justifiably so. The amount of inventory we have is a prime indicator of whether we’re in a seller’s market, a buyer’s market, or a balanced market. We’re firmly in a seller’s market at the moment, and though our inventory situation is showing modest signs of going the opposite direction or toward a balanced state, we’re still nowhere near where we’d like to be.  

In the up-to-$200,000 price point, we have just 0.85 months’ worth of inventory, which means homes priced around there are flying off the market. When we move up to the $200,000 to $350,000 range, inventory is slightly higher with 1.4 months’ worth. Inventory doubles in the $350,000 to $500,000 range, and rises still in the luxury market to 5.3 months’ worth. 

“Conditions continue to bode well for sellers, but we’re also seeing some changes that may signal greater opportunities for buyers.”

As for median sales price, single-family homes are selling for $319,000 right now. Contrast that with the median price for these homes in the spring, which was $300,000. The median sale price for condos has slightly increased to $200,000. 

Now, I know not everyone lives in or is focused on the numbers for Dane County, so let’s quickly run through the numbers for the larger South Central Wisconsin region:


  Regional inventory is at 2.8 months’ worth
  Regional median sales price for single-family homes has fallen a bit to $232,000
  Regional median sales price for condos is at about $190,000 


Lastly and surprisingly, our interest rates are still unbelievably low: They’re currently sub-4% for a 30-year fixed mortgage. Even as home prices increase, it’s still a great time to get into a new home and secure an interest rate in the low-4% range.   

If you’re a seller who’s looking to move up, our current market is rife with opportunities to do so. You’ll find that conditions are favorable to sell your home, and the availability of homes provides more flexibility for you as a buyer as well. 

If you have any questions about the area’s real estate market or if there’s a topic you’d like me to feature on a future video, reach out to me by phone at 608-345-6594 or by email at JDHolt@KW.com. I look forward to hearing from you! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/The+Latest+News+and+Notes+From+Our+Summer+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/The+Latest+News+and+Notes+From+Our+Summer+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re halfway through the year, which makes it a good time to bring you an update on our summer market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re halfway through the year, which makes it a good time to bring you an update on our summer market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy and Sell a Home at the Same Time</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-05 12:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+at+the+Same+Time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you currently own a home and are thinking of selling it and buying a new one, you might be daunted by the process of juggling both transactions. Luckily, I’m here to give you a few tips on how to navigate the process.

First, talk to your lender. Before you even begin to look at homes, you should make sure that all of your finances are in order. You’ll want to ensure that nothing has changed in your financial picture that you’re not aware of and to figure out your options. 

“Before you even begin to look at homes, you should make sure that all of your finances are in order.”

There are three ways to go about handling both these transactions at once:

1. Sell your current home first. To do this, you’ll need to list your home on the market at an appropriate price that you know will help it sell quickly. This can be an advantageous way to go about it, since a lot of sellers will be hesitant to accept an offer that’s contingent on you selling your current home.

Once you close on the sale of your current home, you could potentially do a rent-back agreement, in which the purchasers of your home agree to let you live there for a predetermined period of time for rent. This would allow you time to find and purchase a new home to move into.

2. Buy your new home first. In this situation, you might be saddled with two concurrent mortgages, so it may not be ideal, depending on your financial situation.

3. Buy and sell in the same day. It might be tricky, but it is possible to plan things in such a way that you can close on the sale of your current home and the purchase of your new home in the same day. Of course, this doesn’t give you much time to move, so you may have to plan ahead.

If you have any questions about today’s topic or about the local real estate market, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you currently currently own a home and are thinking of buying a new one, the process can be difficult to navigate. Here are a few tips to help.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you currently currently own a home and are thinking of buying a new one, the process can be difficult to navigate. Here are a few tips to help.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Enhance Your Home’s Appeal to Buyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-enhance-your-homes-appeal-to-buyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-21 14:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Enhance+Your+Homes+Appeal+to+Buyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you’re a home seller looking to create the best first impression on potential buyers, there are a number of different strategies to follow:

1. Start by improving the curb appeal. Start from the street and work your way in. This includes looking at things like your driveway, the exterior landscaping, and the exterior of the home in general. Look at the outside of the property from a buyer’s perspective to make sure that it looks the best it possibly can. This way, when potential buyers drive or walk by the home, they’ll get the impression your home is well-maintained.

2. Have a clean entryway. Make sure that your doormat is clean, your front door is freshly painted and presentable, and that your doorbell is in working order. The color of your door should complement your home, and if possible, the neighborhood at large.

3. Eliminate any odors. You don’t want potential buyers to walk into your home, only to be smacked in the face by the odor of pets, cigarette smoke, and even chemical smells—be careful to limit your use of deodorizers and fragrances, which can turn off potential buyers. The key when it comes to scent is balance.

“Be careful to limit your use of deodorizers and fragrances, which can turn off potential buyers.”

4. Deep clean the house. If you really want to create a great first impression, you’ll need to take the time to deep clean your entire home, meaning you should clean the carpets, floors, and all other surfaces. And don’t forget to dust! You don’t want to give buyers the impression that you’re not maintaining your home as well as you could be. They may wonder if there are other areas you’re neglecting when it comes to home care.

5. Declutter your home. You don’t want to have various piles of your possessions lying around the home, especially if they take up floor space. Be sure to clean out and organize your storage areas, like your closets and cabinets. This is a good time to go through your things and purge those items you no longer need, want, or use. This will make your home seem neater and more accessible to a buyer.

6. Repaint. Now, I don’t mean that you need to repaint the entire exterior or interior of your home, although there are studies that show you can recoup one-and-a-half to two times your investment in your resale price if you do. What I’m focusing on here, though, is making sure that you’ve touched up any nicks, dings, or chips in your paint. Be sure to use a neutral color palette if you want to appeal to the widest pool of buyers!

If you’re thinking about selling your home in today’s market and you have any questions about what you can do to sell quickly and for top dollar, feel free to reach out to me. I’m always here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Enhance+Your+Homes+Appeal+to+Buyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Enhance+Your+Homes+Appeal+to+Buyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What can you do to make sure that you’re truly creating the best first impression for your home? Find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What can you do to make sure that you’re truly creating the best first impression for your home? Find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Downsize Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-downsize-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-07 10:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Downsize+Your+Home_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Downsizing is the process of moving from a larger home to a smaller one. Why might people do this? As it turns out, there are many reasons:

Most often, people downsize when there has been a life-changing occurrence, such as when the kids graduate and move away, or maybe you’re on the verge of retirement. 

It could also be that you just realize that managing a home of a certain size is more work, stress, and money than you can handle, and so a smaller home simply seems more feasible for you. This is especially true for elderly homeowners, and even for those who lead lifestyles that are simply too busy to allow them to juggle home maintenance with their lives.

“If you’re on a larger lot that requires continuous landscaping and maintenance, perhaps that means it’s time to look for something a little more manageable.”

Especially for those whose kids have moved away from home, another reason to downsize is the realization that you just have too much space that you don’t use. That goes for the outside, as well; if you’re on a larger lot that requires continuous landscaping and maintenance, perhaps that means it’s time to look for something a little more manageable. 

Lastly, there are financial benefits to downsizing your home. If you’ve lived in your home for a long time, you’ve probably built up a fair amount of equity. Now could be the most opportune time to put your home on the market and make the move using the money you have tied up in the home.

If you have any questions or comments about downsizing, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Downsize+Your+Home_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Downsize+Your+Home_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do know if it’s time to downsize your home? Learn the signs right here.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do know if it’s time to downsize your home? Learn the signs right here.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling on Your Own vs. Hiring a Real Estate Professional</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/selling-on-your-own-vs-hiring-a-real-estate-professional.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-24 11:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+On+Your+Own+vs.+Hiring+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you’re weighing the decision to hire a real estate professional to help you sell your home versus just doing it by yourself, there are four key points to keep in mind that will help you make your final decision about which route to go:

1. Contracts and paperwork. Regardless of who’s doing the selling, you’re still entering into a legally binding contract with the other party when you do sell it. If you’re not using a real estate professional to help you, you’ll want to have a real estate attorney review the contracts for you so that you can be sure that your transaction is legally compliant.

2. Marketing your home. The goal of most sellers is to get their listing in front of as many qualified buyers’ eyes as possible. In this day and age, you can do a lot on your own to give your listing exposure, particularly with social media. However, did you know that there are literally thousands of websites out there that real estate professionals post your listings to if you work with them? Chances are you don’t have the time or resources to post to that many sites!

“Selling a home is about more than just the dollars and cents—you also need to think about the amount of time you have to dedicate to the logistics.”

3. Pricing your home accurately. The reality is that you only have one shot to make a great initial impression. If you price your home too high when you first put it on the market, it will probably sit stagnant on the market, causing people to wonder what’s wrong with it. It’s a surefire way to reduce the amount of activity your home will see. The same is true if you price it too low. Many people like to go online to check home values, but there’s really no better way to get the true value of your home than to talk to a real estate professional (like myself). We can do a comparative market analysis (CMA) to help you discern what people would be willing to pay for your home.

4. The value of your time. A lot of folks don’t always think of how much time it takes to sell a home. Regardless of whether you sell yours on your own or if you hire an agent, there are things you’ll need to do in order to make sure the sale goes your way, like getting the property in show-ready condition. When you work with a real estate professional, they’ll handle all the particulars of the transaction for you, like scheduling showings and negotiating with the buyers and their agents. You likely have your own career to deal with, and you probably won’t be available when a buyer wants to see your home. Further still, we vet your buyers to make sure they’re qualified to actually be able to purchase the home. Selling a home is about more than just the dollars and cents—you also need to think about the amount of time you have to dedicate to the logistics.

If you have any questions about today’s topic or if you’re in need of a real estate professional to help you with your own home sale, feel free to give me a call or send an email. I’d be glad to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+On+Your+Own+vs.+Hiring+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+On+Your+Own+vs.+Hiring+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s the difference between hiring a real estate professional to help you sell your home and just selling it by yourself? Today I’ll discuss my answer to this question.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s the difference between hiring a real estate professional to help you sell your home and just selling it by yourself? Today I’ll discuss my answer to this question.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Buyer Tips for Navigating Our Current Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-buyer-tips-for-navigating-our-current-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-09 14:59:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Buyer+Tips+for+Navigating+Our+Current+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

These four tips will aid you in better navigating the current real estate market as a homebuyer:

1. Consider submitting a larger earnest money deposit with your offer. There might not be an industry standard for this, but the earnest money is a good faith deposit that accompanies your offer and will speak volumes about your enthusiasm and seriousness about buying the property. By putting in a few thousand dollars extra, then, you’ll let the seller know that you’re a strong and serious buyer. 

2. Show the sellers that you are qualified to purchase their home. Probably most important of all, you need to show that you’ve taken the steps to meet with a lender and not only get pre-qualified, but pre-approved as well. A pre-approval, again, solidly demonstrates that you’re a serious and able buyer.  

“Put your best foot forward when making your offer to the extent that you’re comfortable.”

3. Give the sellers time to move and find out what terms are important to them. With good communication, your agent can help you with this. Whether the seller wants to have an expedient close and move-out or they need extra time, it’ll look good if you can accommodate the timetable that works best for them. 

4. Write your best offer! In this moment’s market, it won’t serve you well to write a lowball offer in the hopes that you’ll negotiate higher. Instead of counting on the seller’s willingness to negotiate and counter back, put your best foot forward when making your offer to the extent that you’re comfortable. In other words, decide how high you’re willing to go, so that if the home sold for more than that, you’d be comfortable walking away. Most sellers won’t have the appetite to go back and forth if another buyer sets themselves apart by making their best offer from the outset. 

If you’re looking to purchase a home in the Greater Madison area, I’d be happy to help. I’m an Accredited Buyer’s Representative, which means I have additional education to best help buyers navigate the market of the moment. Let’s make your dream of homeownership come true! Please give me a call at 608-345-6594 or email me at JDHolt@KW.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Buyer+Tips+for+Navigating+Our+Current+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Buyer+Tips+for+Navigating+Our+Current+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Realizing the dream of homeownership means navigating the purchase process adeptly. Today’s four buyer tips will help you do so.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Realizing the dream of homeownership means navigating the purchase process adeptly. Today’s four buyer tips will help you do so.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>April Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/april-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-12 11:31:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/April/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+April+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There’s not really a one-size-fits-all answer to the question, “How is the market?” It depends on whether you’re looking to buy or sell, what your price point is, where you’re looking to live, and much more. These factors all play a part, so let’s see what the latest numbers have to say for each.

In the Greater Dane County area, we’re expecting home prices to increase. Right now, the median price of a single-family home is $300,000, and condos are around $195,000.

Inventory is illustrated in terms of how many months it would take for all currently listed homes to sell. Six months of inventory is a balanced market; anything above that is a buyer’s market, and anything below is a seller’s market. 

“Ultimately, it’s still a great market for buyers and sellers alike.”

As of now, we have an average of 1.5 months’ worth of inventory. Homes in the $200,000 price range only have two weeks of inventory. The $200,000 to $350,000 range has one month of inventory. At $350,000 to $500,000, there are 2.5 months of inventory—things tend to soften as price points increase. Over $500,000, there are 4.5 months of inventory.

There are about 800 single-family homes currently on the market. On average, they take 87 days to sell. Interest rates are in the low 4% range for a 30-year fixed rate mortgage, so ultimately, it’s still a great market for buyers and sellers alike.

Making the most out of our market, however, depends on who you have working as your real estate professional. I’d be more than happy to help you find a great deal on the perfect home or make a sale for top dollar. If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/April/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+April+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/April/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+April+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What do the latest stats tell us about our market? Let’s find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What do the latest stats tell us about our market? Let’s find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To My Blog!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-31 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Our market remains busy, and it’s still an opportune time to command a high price selling your home.  

I know what’s happening in the Madison area, specifically pertaining to home values, that will directly affect you.

So, I’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated.

They will be valuable and useful in helping you stay on top of what’s happening in the community.

Check back because content will be coming soon!

I’m excited to keep you updated on what’s happening in the Madison area!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My monthly messages will provide you with market updates, tips, and other educational information having to do with our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My monthly messages will provide you with market updates, tips, and other educational information having to do with our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Joshua Holt</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Joshua Holt</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holt Real Estate Team - your professional Madison Area Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
