<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Madison, WI Real Estate Podcast with Joshua Holt</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holt Real Estate Team - your professional Madison, WI Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Joshua Holt</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2021-06-08 12:26:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Joshua Holt</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>jdholt@kw.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Joshua Holt</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Madison, WI Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holt Real Estate Team - your professional Madison, WI Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons We’re Not in a Housing Bubble</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-were-not-in-a-housing-bubble.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-05-21 16:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/5+Reasons+We%E2%80%99re+Not+in+a+Housing+Bubble.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Fear not, buyer and sellers—here are five reasons we’re not in a housing bubble:

1. Mortgage lending standards are stricter than they were prior to the last housing crash. It was much easier to get a mortgage back then. Today it’s simply much tougher to qualify. If you look at the graph at 0:43 in the video, you’ll understand why. The easiest way to understand that graph is this: The higher the number, the easier it is to get a mortgage. 

2. Prices are not soaring out of control. Though price appreciation has been quite strong recently, it’s nowhere near the kind of rise we saw before the crash. The average annual appreciation is around 3.6%, and although our average is higher than this historic norm, it’s not accelerating beyond control as it did in the early 2000s. 

3. There’s not a surplus of homes on the market. On the contrary, we have a home shortage. A balanced market has around six months of supply. Anything more is an overabundance, which causes prices to depreciate. Anything less is a shortage, which will lead to continued appreciation. As you can see at 1:39, there were simply too many homes on the market in 2007 compared to right now. Further fueling this shortage is the drastic decrease in new construction homes. Over the previous decade, we saw significantly fewer homes built compared to the previous decades that led up to the housing crash. 

“Unless we find a way to solve the housing shortage issue, we won’t see a bubble burst anytime soon.”

4. Homes became too expensive to buy in 2007—they’re more affordable now. The affordability formula factors into a home’s price, the wages earned by the purchaser, and the mortgage rate. If you flash back to 14 years ago, prices were high, wages were low, and mortgage rates were more than 6% on average. While prices are still high today, wages have increased and mortgage rates are closer to 3%. Compared to 2006, a lower percentage of median income is needed to purchase a median-priced home. 

5. People are equity rich now instead of tapped out. Prior to the bubble, homeowners were treating their homes like an ATM. Many were withdrawing their equity as soon as it built up and using it for things that weren’t necessarily housing-related. They learned their lesson in the process. Today’s homeowners aren’t tapping into their equity in that fashion. Over 50% of the homes in the country have over 50% equity. 

As you can see, we’re not in a housing bubble. It’s a simple matter of supply and demand. We don’t have enough homes on the market to meet the demand. That’s why prices continue to increase, and it’s why people’s equity positions continue to increase as well. Unless we find a way to solve the housing shortage issue, we won’t see a bubble burst anytime soon. 

If you have questions about this topic or there’s anything else I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/5+Reasons+We%E2%80%99re+Not+in+a+Housing+Bubble.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/5+Reasons+We%E2%80%99re+Not+in+a+Housing+Bubble.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re anxious about a housing bubble, don’t be.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re anxious about a housing bubble, don’t be.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy and Sell Homes Simultaneously</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-homes-simultaneously.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-05-07 11:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/How+to+Buy+and+Sell+Homes+Simultaneously.mp4</guid>
        <description>

With the median sale price in our area up 13.9% year to date, many homeowners want to capitalize on the market by selling. When you need to buy a new home at the same time, that’s where things can get tricky.

Sellers are regularly seeing multiple offers, few to no contingencies, and quick sales. Most people, especially families with kids, don’t want to move twice. If you have the vision and motivation to buy and sell in this market, we can make it happen. These are the questions you need to consider:

1. Can you afford to buy without selling your current home first?

2. Can you borrow against the equity in your current home? The average home in Wisconsin has gained $19,000 in equity over the past year. 

“We don’t know when a market shift might occur.”

3. Can you sell your current property first and find temporary housing? A short-term rental, family or friend, or short-term hotel are all options.

4. Can you sell first and negotiate a delayed closing or rent-back? This allows you to get the proceeds from your home sale to buy your next home without having to move twice.

5. Can you list your home subject to finding suitable housing? This is something we’re starting to see more and more in this market.

The reality is that buyers are more flexible than they used to be, but we don’t know how long that will last or when a market shift might occur. If you have any questions for us or are looking to buy or sell in the near future, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/How+to+Buy+and+Sell+Homes+Simultaneously.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/How+to+Buy+and+Sell+Homes+Simultaneously.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are some considerations to make when buying/selling simultaneously.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are some considerations to make when buying/selling simultaneously.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Buying in a Seller’s Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-buying-in-a-sellers-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-04-23 13:32:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/5+Tips+for+Buying+in+a+Seller%E2%80%99s+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s an incredibly strong seller’s market right now, and competition among buyers is fierce. If you’re thinking about starting the home search, there are a few things you’ll want to keep in mind. Here are five tips for buying a home while in a seller’s market:

1. Qualify for the lowest mortgage rate you can. Home prices have been high, and they still may rise by another 5.7% by the end of the year. Thankfully, record-low interest rates can help offset some of the cost. There are also ways you can make the rate even better: Before you go to the lender, work on boosting your credit score, paying down debt, settling overdue accounts, and alerting credit bureaus of any errors. Putting forth a higher down payment can also help your rate.

2. Get pre-approved before starting your search. It may seem a good idea to search online and try to schedule an appointment when you find your dream house. Unfortunately, most sellers won’t even let you in the door unless you can prove you have the financial ability to purchase their home. So, meet with a lender and get your pre-approval established before you try to go to showings.

“Though we may be a seller’s market, that doesn’t mean finding and winning a home is impossible.”

3. Work with an experienced agent. There are a lot of agents out there, but many only commit to real estate as a hobby or part-time gig. Not all of them will have the skills needed to help you navigate the market successfully. Find a Realtor who has the experience, tools, and information that buyers and sellers need in order to win. For example, The Holt Real Estate team can tour properties on your behalf, find little-known homes that are hitting the market soon, and represent you through every part of the process.

4. Consider buying when the market isn’t so hot. Most experts predict the market will cool off a bit later in the year. As more people get vaccinated, it’s likely that many sellers will feel comfortable enough to finally put their homes on the market. In fact, an economist from Realtor.com says that the 2021 market will be more hospitable toward buyers as new construction ramps up and more listings arrive. If you can wait a few more months to buy, it may be a good idea.

5. Make your offer stand out. In this market, you’ll want to pull out all the stops to make an attractive offer. However, a good offer isn’t all about price. You should also be flexible with your closing day, and you can perhaps give the seller extra time to move out after the deal is complete. You can remove contingencies and add more to your earnest money deposit.

Though we may be a seller’s market, that doesn’t mean finding and winning a home is impossible. If you have any questions or would like more information about our market, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/5+Tips+for+Buying+in+a+Seller%E2%80%99s+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/5+Tips+for+Buying+in+a+Seller%E2%80%99s+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how you can secure a better outcome in your upcoming home purchase.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how you can secure a better outcome in your upcoming home purchase.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Misconceptions About Seller’s Markets</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-misconceptions-about-sellers-markets.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-04-09 15:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/4+Misconceptions+About+Seller%E2%80%99s+Markets.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’ve been following real estate market news, you likely know we’re in a red-hot seller’s market, homes are selling for way over asking price, sellers are receiving great terms and conditions, and things are currently a little crazy. Due to everything that’s going on, I’m sharing four common misconceptions about a strong seller’s market:

1. You must plan for your next home before listing your current one. I believe this misconception is what’s keeping most people from putting their houses on the market right now. Many people think they can’t list their property for sale until they already have their next home lined up. In reality, in the present market, sellers control more terms and conditions than usual. Asking for an extended closing date or negotiating a post-closing occupancy of up to 60 days gives sellers time to find their next house after they’ve secured an offer on their current one.

2. The home’s condition doesn’t matter. Plenty of people think they can just list their property in any condition and it’ll sell quickly. Sometimes an as-is sale makes sense and is the best approach, but that isn’t normally the case. In truth, the condition still sells the home. 

Houses in the best condition will sell quicker and for the most money. When you hear that people are getting wildly high offers and excellent terms, it’s because their properties are in their best conditions. You may need to paint, clean, declutter, and do all the other things to prepare the home that you would do in any market.

“In the present market, sellers control more terms and conditions than usual.”

3. You can price your home above market value. In our market, it’s crucial to set an appropriate asking price. Buyers are already concerned about overpaying and fatigued by what they’ve been experiencing out in the market. If you list your house higher than it should be, tons of buyers will simply avoid it. Ultimately, you’ll be playing catch-up and will probably sell for less than you would have if you’d priced it correctly from the beginning. 

4. You don’t need a Realtor. Since everything’s selling so quickly, there’s a temptation to sell your property on your own and save a little money. However, homes are receiving multiple offers and a slew of showings, and you need an expert in your corner who knows how to help you manage the process. Real estate agents qualify buyers before they walk through the house so that only those capable of making an offer are allowed to view it. 

When the offers start pouring in, you need someone who can help negotiate the best terms for your situation. It’s not always about the highest price; numerous other things go into an offer. You may also be tempted to use a discount broker who will just list the property on the MLS and leave the rest of the work to you. However, if you want to maximize your position in today’s market, you need an expert agent that will provide the world-class marketing your home deserves.

If you have any questions about this market or how to sell your house, you can always give us a call or send an email. We’d love to talk to you about what your home is worth and how we’d maximize your position in the market.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/4+Misconceptions+About+Seller%E2%80%99s+Markets.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/4+Misconceptions+About+Seller%E2%80%99s+Markets.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are the top four seller’s market misconceptions you shouldn’t believe.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are the top four seller’s market misconceptions you shouldn’t believe.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>My Top Spring Cleaning Tips</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-top-spring-cleaning-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-03-19 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/My+Top+Spring+Cleaning+Tips.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Whether you’re thinking about listing your home for sale this spring or you’re already in your forever home, these spring cleaning tips can be of value to any homeowner: 

1. Windows. Make sure that you take time to clean not only the outsides of your windows but also the insides; buyers will check out both. 

2. Curb appeal. Walk around the perimeter of your home and tackle any areas that need to be cleaned, trimmed, or repainted. Oftentimes, you’ll find debris and buildup leftover from winter. Also, take a look at your front door—has it seen better days? A fresh coat of paint could bring it back to life. 

When was the last time you truly looked at the address numbers on your house? Straighten them if they’re misaligned and make sure they’re not faded. While you’re at it, test your exterior lights to make sure everything is in working order. 

“The kitchen receives a lot of traffic, so it should receive some extra attention when cleaning.”

3. Kitchen. This is easily the top priority inside your home. Focus on your appliances; do a good refrigerator and freezer clean-out, run a clean cycle on the dishwasher, etc. The kitchen receives a lot of traffic, so it should receive some extra attention when cleaning. 

4. Bathrooms. No one likes deep cleaning toilets, sinks, and tile floors, but it’s a must. If you have fabric shower curtains, run those through a gentle wash cycle. Or, if yours are older shower curtains, perhaps it’s time to replace them. 

Of course, these are just some great starting points; we have a fairly comprehensive spring cleaning checklist that we’d be more than happy to share with you. If you’re interested in receiving a copy of that or have any questions about the spring selling season, give us a call or send an email. We’d love to hear from you and find out how we can be of service.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/My+Top+Spring+Cleaning+Tips.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/My+Top+Spring+Cleaning+Tips.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are four simple tips to help you get started on your spring cleaning.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are four simple tips to help you get started on your spring cleaning.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Sellers Can Deal With Low Appraisals</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-sellers-can-deal-with-low-appraisals.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-03-05 06:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/How+Sellers+Can+Deal+With+Low+Appraisals.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What happens when an appraisal comes in short? This is certainly an appropriate concern in our current real estate market, as prices look like they’re on a never-ending upward trajectory. As a seller, you have three options when an appraiser doesn’t value your home for the price you agreed to sell it for.

First, check the appraisal for human error. Mistakes can happen, so perhaps something got miscalculated. Take a thorough look through your home’s appraisal and see whether there are any issues that could’ve caused it to come in low.

If everything checks out, your next option is to prepare a rebuttal with the help of your agent. Sometimes this works, sometimes it doesn’t. In any case, your agent can evaluate the comparable properties the appraiser used and see whether they were justified. If possible, they can also prepare their own list of comparable properties that can bring the appraisal up to where you need it to be.

“It can be challenging to get any adjustments made in an appraisal.”

Of course, depending on where things are in the contract-to-close period, don’t assume that the buyer actually wants the appraisal to come in low, because that could adversely impact them as well. I’ll be honest with you: It can be challenging to get any adjustments made in an appraisal. Oftentimes, appraisers will choose to stick to their guns, but a rebuttal is still a shot worth taking.

If a rebuttal doesn’t work, you’ll have to return to the negotiating table and see if you and the buyer can still make the transaction work. Who knows, maybe all you need is a slight adjustment to turn things into a win-win situation.

As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, give me a call or send me an email. I’m always available to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/How+Sellers+Can+Deal+With+Low+Appraisals.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/How+Sellers+Can+Deal+With+Low+Appraisals.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s what sellers can do in the event of a low appraisal.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s what sellers can do in the event of a low appraisal.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Reasons NOT to Wait Until Spring to Sell</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-reasons-not-to-wait-until-spring-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-02-19 13:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Recently, I met with a client of mine who had been debating whether to wait a few months into the spring market to list their home or do it now. I shared with them these four reasons why now might be the absolute best time to act: 

1. Motivated buyers. When your home’s listed on the mid- to late-winter market, you’ll be encountering far more serious buyers than those you’d be attracting in spring. They’ve already taken the steps to ensure they’re pre-approved, they know exactly what they want, and they most likely have life circumstances that necessitate purchasing a home as soon as possible (e.g., job relocation). 

2. Less competition. Many people still buy into the conventional wisdom that says it’s best to take a home off the market around the holidays and/or during the Wisconsin winter months. This predictable behavior results in even less inventory in a market that’s already dealing with an inventory shortage. Contrary to popular belief, people do still have to buy when the temperatures bottom out and snow covers the ground. Just by being on the market now, you’ll capture a larger share of this motivated buyer pool. 

“You can enjoy everything the spring market has to offer right now but with even more advantages.”

3. The spring market has already started. Truth be told, real estate is no longer as dominated by seasonality as it once was. We’re encountering extremely high demand on every one of our current listings, which proves that sellers can now find themselves firmly in the driver’s seat even in wintertime. By listing now, you’ll be able to find buyers who are more willing to accommodate your needs. Forget about having to negotiate for favorable terms—the buyers will be leading with highly attractive terms. Given our market conditions, buyers are willing to do what it takes to get into a home they love. 

4. You can show off your home’s unique features. Perhaps you have a charming fireplace to light up when these shorter days give way to darkness. Maybe you have a cozy living room that lends itself well to buyers’ visions of staying nice and warm with loved ones as they watch the first snowfall. Alternatively, it could be the case that your landscaping isn’t quite where it needs to be; a little snow cover will conveniently blanket any eyesores. 

Bonus reason: low inventory. Yes, I already touched on this, but I can’t stress it enough: We’re dealing with the lowest inventory that we have ever seen. So, as long as they are no other major life factors preventing you from putting your home on the market today, then you’ll benefit greatly from getting ahead of the so-called “best selling season” of spring. You can enjoy everything the spring market has to offer right now but with even more advantages.

If you’d like help getting the selling process started, please reach out via phone or email anytime. It would be our pleasure to guide you through all that’s required to make your home market-ready. We have the tools to help you sell quickly and for top dollar so that you can move on to the next chapter of your life with confidence.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are the four main reasons why you shouldn’t wait till spring to list.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are the four main reasons why you shouldn’t wait till spring to list.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Appraisals vs. Inspections</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/appraisals-vs-inspections.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-02-05 16:20:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/Appraisals+vs.+Inspections.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the difference between an appraisal and an inspection? In the simplest terms, a home’s appraisal calculates its value, while an inspection determines its condition. 

What’s the purpose of an appraisal? When you apply for a mortgage (or, occasionally, when you’re using cash to purchase), an unbiased appraisal is the best way to confirm the value of the home based on the sale price, regardless of what you’re willing to pay for it. This is especially critical in today’s seller’s market where low inventory is increasing bidding wars and pushing prices upward. However, your lender will only allow you to borrow based on the true value of the home. 

“In the simplest terms, a home’s appraisal calculates its value, while an inspection determines its condition.”

A home inspection, meanwhile, determines the current state, safety, and condition of the home before you finalize the sale. If any issue were to come up (e.g., the condition of the roof or A/C unit), it counts as an opportunity for the buyer and seller to negotiate the terms of the sale before closing. 

The bottom line is that the appraisal and inspection are critical steps in purchasing a home. Of course, they’re not steps you need to take alone. We at the Holt Real Estate Team are here to guide you every step of the way, from the beginning of your home search to the closing table.

If you’re looking to purchase a home, give us a call or send an email. My team and I would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/Appraisals+vs.+Inspections.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2021/Appraisals+vs.+Inspections.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Appraisals and inspections are two separate things; here’s the difference.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Appraisals and inspections are two separate things; here’s the difference.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Do You Live in Your Home While Selling It?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-live-in-your-home-while-selling-it.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2021-01-22 16:07:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q_+How+Do+You+Live+in+Your+Home+While+Selling+It_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking of putting your home on the market, you might be wondering: How can I live in my home while trying to sell it? Here are five steps to follow that will make things easier and less stressful:

1. Start packing now. It’s best to start packing up any items you don’t need daily and get them out of the way so they’re not taking up space. 

2. Sell, donate, or give it away. Moving is a great opportunity to purge yourself of things you’ve collected over the years that you don’t use anymore or won’t miss if they’re gone. I recommend selling, donating, or giving these things away. 

3. Get squeaky clean. Now is the time to ensure your home shines, so deep clean as much as possible. It’s been proven that homes that show well due to being clean and well-kept generate higher offers than those that are dirty and unkept. If you list your home with The Holt Real Estate Team, we’ll enlist the service of professional cleaners to clean your home before taking its listing photos so it looks its absolute best. 

“It’s been proven that homes that are clean and well-kept generate higher offers.”

4. Maintain your privacy and security. Make sure you don’t leave out any personal documents or valuable items during showings and open houses. Pack these things up and store them in a secure location. 

5. Involve your kids. You wouldn’t believe how motivated kids can get when you attach something fun to a chore. You can make a game out of packing away their toys, for example. 

In addition to professional cleaning services, if you list with our team, you’ll get professional staging, photography, video, and a comprehensive marketing plan. This guarantees that we’ll sell your home for the best price in the exact timeline you need. 

If you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q_+How+Do+You+Live+in+Your+Home+While+Selling+It_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q_+How+Do+You+Live+in+Your+Home+While+Selling+It_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are five tips that will make living in a for-sale home easier.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are five tips that will make living in a for-sale home easier.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Will Shape Our Market in 2021?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-will-shape-our-market-in-2021.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-12-28 16:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q_+What+Will+Shape+Our+Market+in+2021_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Despite everything, the housing market was one sector of the economy that performed consistently well throughout 2020. What do experts think this coming year will bring? Here are four trends to watch out for: 

1. Prices will continue to rise. If inventory remains as low as it has, it’s possible that prices will continue to go up. The median sold price for properties in our area was $315,000 this year—a 6.8% increase compared to 2019. Inventory also further declined by 26.3% year over year. Despite a quick burst of new listings toward the end of the summer (perhaps due to a delay in the market caused by the pandemic), a dwindling supply of houses is great news for sellers but not so much for buyers. 

2. Suburbs will reign supreme. We talked about this trend early this year, and it looks like it will continue. As more and more folks find out that it’s easier for them to work remotely or that proximity to where they work isn’t as important, they’ll look to buy homes farther and farther away from city centers. Many people are starting to look toward neighboring counties or smaller communities where they can get a bigger bang for their buck. 

“Historically low rates have brought buyers out en masse, which has caused low inventory, rising prices, and a flurry of activity.”

3. Increased builder confidence. Builders are becoming more confident in their futures, and we’re now seeing more and more new construction starts happening than we’ve seen in the past few years. Also, buyers who aren’t finding what they’re looking for in the resale market are turning to the new construction market as an alternative to find a home that fits their needs. 

4. Mortgage rates will remain low. Mortgage rates hit several record lows throughout 2020, and this trend seems likely to continue—at least during the early part of 2021. Historically low rates have brought buyers out en masse, which has caused low inventory, rising prices, and a flurry of activity. We’re no longer seeing a seasonality in our market. Instead, buyers are buying when they need to buy and sellers are selling when they need to sell. Buyers, especially, are trying hard to capitalize on these low mortgage rates. 

As always, if you have questions about our local real estate market or there’s a topic you’d like to see me cover in a future video, call or email me anytime. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q_+What+Will+Shape+Our+Market+in+2021_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q_+What+Will+Shape+Our+Market+in+2021_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are four trends you can expect to see in our 2021 real estate market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are four trends you can expect to see in our 2021 real estate market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays From the Holt Team</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/happy-holidays-from-the-holt-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-12-14 16:03:13 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’d like to take a moment to wish you and yours a happy holiday season. We hope that you’re able to enjoy this wonderful time of year and spend time with those you love and care about deeply—whether it’s in person or from a distance. Thank you for your continued support of our business this year and in the past. We love being able to help people turn their real estate dreams into reality. We look forward to serving you for years to come.

This may be a busier time in the year for most folks, but please know that we are always here for you. If you ever have any questions, need any assistance, or would like additional guidance, you can always give us a call. If we don’t hear from you before 2021, have a happy New Year’s!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We hope you and your family have a wonderful holiday!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We hope you and your family have a wonderful holiday!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: Do You Still Buy Into These 5 Selling Myths?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-do-you-still-buy-into-these-5-selling-myths.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-12-04 12:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There are plenty of delightful myths and legends surrounding the holiday season—mistletoes, toy-making elves, and a jolly, red-suited gift-bearer to name a few. Such tales add cheer and nostalgia to the season, but some myths can spoil the season. Here are the five most common home-selling myths that sellers should leave out in the snow this year: 

Myth No. 1: Buyers are waiting to enter the market

The truth is, interest rates remain near record lows, so buyers are out there searching in earnest for the right home that they can purchase at the right rate. With so many unknowns (e.g., a new administration in the White House and several viable COVID-19 vaccines on the horizon), buyers aren’t betting that these insanely low rates will hang around much longer. 

Myth No. 2: Fall and winter are just bad times to sell 

There really isn’t as much seasonality to the real estate market as there used to be; people will make a move when it’s the right time for them to do so. That’s why I always tell people that the only “right time” to buy a home is when it makes the most sense for their specific circumstances. 

“American homeowners on the whole have greater equity positions, which means they can walk away from their property if things get dicey.”

Myth No. 3: Home prices are decreasing 

Unfortunately, if you’re a buyer, that isn’t the case at all. Sellers, on the other hand, have a lot to smile about: We’re continuing to see year-over-year increases in sales prices. In fact, we’re up 5.5% from where we were at this time last year. 

Myth No. 4: You won’t be able to show your home

We take great pride in prioritizing everyone’s health and safety by implementing special systems and processes. We have ways to show your home to potential buyers virtually (an increasingly popular option), and in the event that people do come through your home, we’re taking extra steps to ensure that a) those buyers are completely qualified, and b) everyone is following CDC guidelines. That means we’re vetting people for symptoms, requiring them to wear masks and gloves inside the home, minimizing the amount of contact they’ll have with surfaces, and using sanitizer. 

Myth No. 5: The real estate market is going to crash

What’s happening now in the real estate market is completely different from the situation that led to the 2008 collapse and subsequent Great Recession. Mortgage lending is much, much more responsible, and American homeowners, on the whole, have greater equity positions, which gives them plenty of options to recoup some of their equity should they find themselves in mortgage trouble. The U.S. economy is certainly stronger in some sectors than in others, and real estate has proven itself to be one of the titanic forces holding things up as COVID-19 wreaks havoc. According to basic supply and demand relationships, we won’t see a market crash anytime soon. 

I hope you found value in today’s blog. We’re always here to answer your questions about buying or selling real estate, so please reach out via phone or email. We also welcome you to share topics that you’d like to see covered in a future blog; our mission is to provide value to you. Stay safe this holiday season, and we’ll see you next time!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s the truth behind popular selling myths that may be holding you back.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s the truth behind popular selling myths that may be holding you back.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Are You Most Thankful For?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-are-you-most-thankful-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-19 14:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I wanted to share with you a message of thanks and gratitude. I know this year has been unlike any other year before it; we’ve all faced so many new challenges, and we all had to get used to living with ongoing uncertainty. That’s why it’s more important than ever for me to thank everyone who has made a big impact on us and our business by allowing us to help them with their real estate needs.

We truly appreciate everyone who worked with us to buy, sell, or invest in real estate in 2020. We also want to thank our vendor partners, including our inspectors, lenders, and title companies; we’ve started some great relationships this year. To all the contractors who helped our clients get the most out of their home sale or make their new house feel more like home, we sincerely thank you too. 

I hope that all of you have a wonderful holiday season; it won’t be a typical celebration this year, but it can certainly still be joyous. Happy Thanksgiving!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s to a wonderful Thanksgiving 2020!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s to a wonderful Thanksgiving 2020!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Can You Save Money as a Homeowner?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-save-money-as-a-homeowner.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-06 14:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q%3A+How+Can+You+Save+Money+as+a+Homeowner%3F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Even if you’re not planning on selling your home anytime soon, here are four ways you can save money as a homeowner right now:

1. Reach out to your insurance agent. Most homeowners simply renew their initial homeowners insurance policy every time it comes up for renewal without examining it to see how they can save money. They also sometimes forget to ensure that they have an adequate amount of coverage for their home. I suggest reaching out to your agent to see how you can save money with your current policy. You can also reach out to me and I’d be happy to discuss how our service, Keller Covered, can save you money on your homeowners insurance premiums. 

2. Install a smart thermostat. These products have been around for a while now, and they’ve only gotten better at programming the preferred climate in your home. They’ve also been proven to help you save money on your monthly utility bills, so this is definitely something you should look into as we get closer to winter. 

“If you need recommendations for service providers who can help with these tips, don’t hesitate to reach out to me.”

3. Get a home warranty. I know what you may be thinking: “Josh, isn’t that an expense?” While there is a cost to having a home warranty (usually a few hundred dollars), it covers many big-ticket repair items. If something breaks in your air conditioning, plumbing, or electrical system, having that repair cost covered will save you a substantial amount of money.

4. Get a home inspection. Getting a home inspection is something people usually do when they buy a home, but getting a home inspection after you own the home is beneficial, too. The inspector can evaluate areas of your home you might be unaware of and spot some much-needed repairs. This way, you can fix them before they become a much bigger issue down the road. 

Of course, if you need recommendations for service providers who can help with these tips, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to show you our list of service providers and help you save money. 

Lastly, I want to remind you that the Holt Real Estate Team is still offering our real estate checkups. Your home is your biggest asset, so don’t neglect its health. Just give us a call, and we’ll evaluate your home and expenses; we’ll tell you how to maximize your homeownership goals. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q%3A+How+Can+You+Save+Money+as+a+Homeowner%3F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q%3A+How+Can+You+Save+Money+as+a+Homeowner%3F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are four tips that will help you save money as a homeowner.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are four tips that will help you save money as a homeowner.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Can We Expect From the Future of Our Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-can-we-expect-from-the-future-of-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-10-23 11:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Can+We+Expect+From+the+Future+of+Our+Market_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

To help you understand today’s market update, I’d like to share some insights from the National Association of Realtors’ chief economist Lawrence Yun. He was recently asked for his prognosis for the upcoming housing market based on how things have progressed so far in 2020. In response, he said:


  “Cooler weather won’t chill the housing market’s rally, as strong existing home sales and record-high pending home sales in August indicate no homebuying slowdown [this] fall. Further, the striking market turnaround since the early days of the coronavirus pandemic has brought a resurgence in bidding wars and has proved housing’s resilience in an unusual and volatile year. […] But a mix of surging buyer demand and low inventory puts the industry in uncharted territory.”

  “The median home price has soared to an all-time height of $300,000, threatening to choke off first-time buyers from the market and depress the national homeownership rate. More homebuilding is necessary to relieve some of the market pressures. New home sales hit more than 1,000,000 year to date in September—an encouraging sign. However, lumber shortages are pushing up new home prices by an average of $14,000 since April.”


“We have now experienced a year-over-year increase in median sold prices every month since March of 2016.”

So what does that mean for us locally?

Despite the pandemic, home sales in our region have kept pace with 2019. The continued lack of inventory puts upward pressure on home prices. Year to date, our median home price is up by 5.5% over last year. We have now experienced a year-over-year increase in median sold prices every month since March of 2016.

So what can we expect from the future?

Interest rates are likely to remain low, which will keep demand high. Despite the variables that the pandemic has thrown into the mix, housing stats remain aligned to the seasonal trends of previous years, which gives us insight into what we can possibly expect in the coming winter months.

If you have any questions about the market or how the conditions affect your buying and selling prospects, please reach out to us. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Can+We+Expect+From+the+Future+of+Our+Market_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Can+We+Expect+From+the+Future+of+Our+Market_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s an update on what’s going on in our real estate market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s an update on what’s going on in our real estate market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Renovations Should I Make Before Selling?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-renovations-should-i-make-before-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-10-09 15:02:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Renovations+Should+I+Make+Before+Selling_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about putting your home on the market at any point in the near future, I’ve got some great tips to share with you today. There are upgrades and renovations you can make to increase your home’s sale price and get a great return on your investment, but there are also common upgrades and renovations that won’t do either of those things.

I don’t typically recommend big, expensive upgrades right before selling. If you plan on living in the home for a while longer and enjoying them, though, it makes more sense. Here are the things that will bring you a good return as a seller:

1. Kitchen. This typically sells the home for most buyers. You don’t necessarily need to renovate the entire room, but any updates you do make will give you a great bang for your buck.

2. Energy-saving features. A lot of buyers are looking for energy efficiency, so if you have older appliances that aren’t as efficient, you may want to replace them. You could also update windows to become more energy efficient as well. Anything you can do to lower the energy cost for a future buyer is a good call. 

3. Curb appeal. If you have old, cracked paint chips on your siding, it’s a good idea to put a fresh coat on or replace that siding. New siding and new paint give sellers one of the best returns on their investment.

4. Front door. It’s what sticks out first to a buyer when they show up to your home. You don’t have to replace the door, either. A fresh coat of paint could do wonders.

“Your money can be spent more wisely than on a new deck.”

Those are the main updates I recommend, but here are a few that I don’t:

1. Bathroom. A full bathroom remodel or the addition of a new bathroom typically isn’t worth what it costs. The average return is only about 56%.

2. Deck. Having a deck is nice, but building one before you sell isn’t a good idea. Buyers aren’t really looking for decks in particular. Your money could be better spent somewhere else.

3. Master suite. Everyone thinks people want that magazine-worthy, luxurious master suite. When it comes down to it, though, people would rather pay for the home without one than with one. On average, a master suite addition can cost over $100,000 and only results in about a 64% ROI.

If you have any questions for me about what you should do to your home before selling, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Renovations+Should+I+Make+Before+Selling_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Renovations+Should+I+Make+Before+Selling_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are three renovations to circle and three to avoid before selling.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are three renovations to circle and three to avoid before selling.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: Having a Tough Time Navigating Our Seller’s Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-having-a-tough-time-navigating-our-sellers-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-09-25 11:50:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Having+a+Tough+Time+Navigating+Our+Sellers+Market_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

After helping out a first-time homebuyer recently, I realized the advice I gave could be incredibly helpful for others to have. So today, I’d like to share the five tips you should know when navigating a seller’s market like the one we’re currently experiencing:

1. Be decisive. If you’re going to come out on top, you’ll need to be ready to make decisions. Time is critical in a seller’s market, and often, getting your dream home simply means being the first person in line. If you see the perfect home come on the market, don’t wait until the weekend for a showing. Set something up as soon as possible—if you can’t, I’d be happy to help set up a virtual showing for you. Speaking of which, you want an accessible, speedy real estate agent like me on your side. A responsive agent is a must-have in these markets where buyers need to act quickly.

2. Submit a clean offer. This may not be the best time to submit an offer with a long list of contingencies. Contingencies could mean the difference between getting the home of your dreams and missing out on it. A seller may be more interested in wrapping things up quickly instead of fetching a higher price but losing out on time. Think about dropping or at least modifying traditional contingencies; your offer may look more appealing because it means there’s a lower chance of you backing out of the deal. 

However, there are still ways to protect yourself. You can get your loan completely underwritten by your lender, for example.

“If you’re going to come out on top, you’ll need to be ready to make decisions.”

3. Let go of perfection. Inventory is limited right now, but demand is incredibly high. This situation means it’s less likely that you’ll find the perfect home, but that’s perfectly fine. Often, it’s better to settle with a good home and make it perfect instead of waiting forever for a property that may never come. Even when inventory expands, it’s rare for the “perfect” home to appear.

4. Be disciplined with your budget. Things can get competitive among buyers, and it’s easy to get carried away and offer more than you’re comfortable with. You may get so attached to a house that you go well above your budget, so set a maximum price point and stick with it. Sure, you may not get the house you were interested in, but you’re also skipping out on the years of financial stress that comes from overextending your budget.

5. Offer more earnest money. Earnest money is similar to a deposit and is provided alongside your offer. It shows you’re serious, but you’re able to get the money back if the deal doesn’t go through. Buyers in our market usually offer 1% of the purchase price, but it’s a good idea to offer more in a hot market. It shows you’re more interested and are less likely to back out of the transaction.

If you’re thinking about jumping into the market and buying a home, let’s set up a free consultation and go over what you’re looking for, what you can afford, and what your current home (if you have one) is worth. Whether it’s in person or via phone call, Zoom meeting, or some other virtual means, I’d be happy to walk you through your specific home buying situation. To set up a consultation, just give me a call at (608) 345-6594 or email JDHolt@KW.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Having+a+Tough+Time+Navigating+Our+Sellers+Market_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Having+a+Tough+Time+Navigating+Our+Sellers+Market_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>These tips will help you beat the competition, even in a seller’s market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>These tips will help you beat the competition, even in a seller’s market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Else Besides Price Should You Consider Before Buying?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-else-besides-price-should-you-consider-before-buying.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-09-04 16:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Else+Besides+Price+Should+You+Consider+Before+Buying_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When most folks search for a new home, they naturally start by looking at prices. It’s important to consider what else impacts the purchase before making a decision, though. It’s not just the price that matters, but the overall cost of owning the home.

Today this cost is largely impacted by low mortgage rates. Low rates are making homes more affordable now than at any time since 2016. These rates are offsetting rising home prices because it’s less expensive to borrow money. In essence, purchasing a home while rates are this low may save you significantly over the life of your mortgage loan. 

What are the experts saying about home affordability? NAR Chief Economist Lawrence Yun says, “Although housing prices have consistently moved higher, when the favorable mortgage rates are factored in, an overall home purchase was more affordable in 2020’s second quarter compared to one year ago.” 

“Purchasing a home while rates are this low may save you significantly over the life of your mortgage loan.”

According to Mortgage News Daily, “Those shopping for a home can afford 10% more home than they could have one year ago while keeping their monthly payment unchanged. This translates into nearly $32,000 more buying power when looking at a median-priced home.”

So again, when purchasing a home, think about the overall cost of ownership—not just the price. Homes on your wish list may be more affordable than you think. 

If you’d like to discuss how affordability plays a role in our local market and your long-term homeownership goals, give me a call. If you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Else+Besides+Price+Should+You+Consider+Before+Buying_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+What+Else+Besides+Price+Should+You+Consider+Before+Buying_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When buying a home, there’s more to think about than just price.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When buying a home, there’s more to think about than just price.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: Have You Considered Writing a Letter?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-have-you-considered-writing-a-letter.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-08-21 13:13:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Have+You+Considered+Writing+a+Letter_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you considering buying a home in this extremely hot real estate market? These days, we’re frequently seeing multiple offers on properties, and it can be stressful for all parties involved. We have one particular tip we give our buyers that often helps them win the house of their dreams. 

Consider writing a love letter to the seller about why you want to buy the house and what features you love. This will help your offer stand out amongst the competition. This letter should be written by you, the buyer, not the real estate agent. When a seller is comparing lots of offers, your letter is something different for them to consider. It may touch them emotionally and make them take a closer look at the rest of your offer. 

Let us know via phone or email if you’re interested in making a move or have any other questions. We would love to share all of our other tips and tricks with you that have helped our buyers win.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Have+You+Considered+Writing+a+Letter_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Have+You+Considered+Writing+a+Letter_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s why you should write a letter to the seller about the home you want.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s why you should write a letter to the seller about the home you want.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: Which Closing Costs Should You Prepare for as a Seller?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-which-closing-costs-should-you-prepare-for-as-a-seller.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-08-07 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Which+Closing+Costs+Should+You+Prepare+for+as+a+Seller_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Aside from your agent’s commission, there are four closing costs to prepare for when selling your home: 

1. Owner’s title policy. This is included in most real estate transactions so the property will transfer freely and clearly to the buyer’s name. Lenders will require this, and any buyer will want to know that their new home is theirs without issue. Typically, this fee is based on the home’s sale price. For example, the fee for a $300,000 home will typically be $1,000 to $1,200, depending on which title company you work with. If you’re able to provide the policy from when you purchased the home, you may get a discount. 

2. State transfer tax. This tax is required by the state of Wisconsin and amounts to roughly $3 per $1,000 of the sale price. Again, if we use the example of a $300,000 home, the transfer tax would be $900. 

“I’d be happy to prepare you a complimentary, no-obligation home value analysis.”

3. Additional title fees. These include the deep preparation, special assessment search, gap endorsement, and mortgage payoff fees. Each of these tends to be fixed costs (i.e., not tied to the sale price) and range from a little less than $100 to slightly more depending on the item. 

4. Property tax proration. If you close on your home sale at the end of the year as opposed to the beginning, this will be a larger amount. For example, if you sell at the end of August and your property tax is around $6,000, you’d pay $4,000. 

There may be other fees to account for based on your situation, so if you’d like to know more about this topic, give me a call and I’d be happy to prepare you a complimentary, no-obligation home value analysis and seller net sheet. 

As always, if you have any other real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me as well. I’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Which+Closing+Costs+Should+You+Prepare+for+as+a+Seller_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+Which+Closing+Costs+Should+You+Prepare+for+as+a+Seller_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are four closing costs you should prepare for when selling.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are four closing costs you should prepare for when selling.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Does Radon Testing Work?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-does-radon-testing-work.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-07-24 13:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+How+Does+Radon+Testing+Work_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve recently had some clients ask me questions about radon. They want to know how you test for it, what it is, and what to do if you do have high levels of radon. We’re going to cover all of that information today.

Radon is a cancer-causing, radioactive gas. The problem is that it’s tasteless, odorless, and invisible, but you can test for it. The Surgeon General has warned that radon is the second leading cause of lung cancer today behind smoking. 

In Wisconsin, the action level for high radon is a level of 4.0 pCi/L or higher. That aligns with the EPA guidelines. The action level is not a safe level, however, as there are no safe levels of radon gas. 

“You can fix high levels of radon via a mitigation system.”

Testing is the only way to know your home’s radon levels. There are no immediate symptoms that will alert you of the presence of radon. It typically takes years of exposure before any problems surface. If you’re dealing with a real estate transaction, your home inspector can typically also perform a radon test and get your results within a few days.

If you’re a homeowner who didn’t include a radon testing contingency when you made the offer on the home and you’re curious about the levels, there are many DIY testing kits that you can buy for under $20. 

If you do have high radon, you can fix the problem. It’s best to rely on a professional, especially  when dealing with something this dangerous. The presence of radon gas can be remediated with the installation of a radon mitigation system. These systems vent the radon gas from below the basement floor in your home and use a fan to expel the gas. These systems typically cost between $700 and $1,500 to install in your home.

If you have questions for me about testing for radon or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+How+Does+Radon+Testing+Work_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Q-+How+Does+Radon+Testing+Work_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Radon is a deadly, invisible gas. Here’s how to protect your home from it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Radon is a deadly, invisible gas. Here’s how to protect your home from it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Seller Setbacks to Avoid</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-seller-setbacks-to-avoid.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-07-10 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/5+Seller+Setbacks+to+Avoid.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, I’ve been working a lot with first-time homeowners who are now looking to become first-time home sellers. As such, I wanted to share some common seller setbacks I’ve seen and how you can best prepare for them. 

If you think back to the purchase of your current home, you’ll likely remember that there were several things that sent you into a panic but which turned out to be totally normal parts of the process. In hindsight, you may even laugh at how you thought something like that scary inspection report would prove to be a colossal setback. Nevertheless, knowledge is power, so here is what you’ll want to know about the selling process: 

1. Leave emotions out of the transaction. As a home seller, you’ll likely experience surprisingly strong feelings about your home. Emotions may make you feel better in the short term, but feelings won’t last; always think about the big picture and your personal goals before changing course. 

2. Make sure your home is impeccable, even before staging. You may feel very confident in your taste and decor, but it’s important to remember that anything that fills your home is a potential distraction for buyers. It’s nothing personal, though it may feel that way. 

3. Consider a pre-inspection before you list. A pre-listing inspection will turn up things you should definitely repair, potential problems you might not even know exist, and provide clear answers on the exact condition of your home. If you’re concerned about cost, I’ll advise you on the changes that are worth the money and the things that are likely okay to leave as is. 

4. Handling lowball offers well. Though we’re not seeing many of these in the market of the moment, they do still occur, so it’s good to be aware of them. There’s a difference between an offer that’s slightly below asking price and one that’s tens of thousands of dollars below it. 

Lowball offers can be a form of real-time feedback about your home; if a range of buyers submit low offers, it may point to a clear issue that you’ve overlooked, and therefore it forces an opportunity to address that. 

5. Understand that everything is negotiable. Buyers may want all sorts of concessions and contingencies. It might be helpful to think of your home sale as another ordinary transaction, like buying a car. Negotiation in a car sale is a no brainer, so transfer that mentality to your home sale. Just as an auto dealer wouldn’t accept any ol’ offer, you don’t have to give in on every ask, either. 

Selling your home for the first time is an opportunity to learn about real estate. The more you know before you sell, the bigger the advantage you’ll have in the end; you’ll be calm, focused, and determined when it comes to decisions that benefit your sale. 

If you have questions on this or any other topic, please feel free to reach out via phone or email. I’m always here to be a resource for you, so let me know how I can be of assistance!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/5+Seller+Setbacks+to+Avoid.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/5+Seller+Setbacks+to+Avoid.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how to avoid hang-ups and heartaches while selling your home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how to avoid hang-ups and heartaches while selling your home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Evolution of Home Buying</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-evolution-of-home-buying.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-12 14:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/The+Evolution+of+Home+Buying.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The way we work has always influenced where we live and what type of home we buy. The Bureau of Labor Statistics reported that in the past year, 25% of the workforce worked from home at least part of the time. Based on the world we live in, that statistic will likely only increase. Due to remote work, we’re spending more time at home than ever before, and this is changing the criteria we use when shopping for a home. 

Specifically, remote work is changing the way people buy homes in three important ways:

1. It’s expanding the geography of the home search. Since they’re not tied to a specific commute time to the office, buyers are looking further away from city centers to find their home. They’re also prioritizing lower taxes and school districts over distance from work. 

“Due to remote work, we’re spending more time at home than ever before, and this is changing the criteria we use when shopping for a home.”

2. It’s causing more buyers to look for dedicated office space. For many years, buyers’ focus centered on open concept floor plans, and many still prefer this type of floor plan. However, more and more are looking for a dedicated, private space they can make into an office. Perhaps it’s an actual office space, an additional bedroom, or extra space in the basement or attic that they can convert. Conversely, they’re no longer prioritizing things like home gyms and theaters. 

3. It’s causing more buyers to settle down for the long haul. Back in the 1980s, people moved and sold their homes every five or six years. Now that average has increased to nine to 12 years. It’s more important for modern buyers to get the space they need right now instead of moving later on to get that space. 

In closing, it’s likely that companies will continue to offer flexible working arrangements, thereby giving greater freedom to prospective buyers. Sellers who modify their listing by adding a private home office may find themselves at a great advantage. 

If you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/The+Evolution+of+Home+Buying.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/The+Evolution+of+Home+Buying.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Remote work is changing the home buying experience in three key ways.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Remote work is changing the home buying experience in three key ways.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Post-Coronavirus Moving Trends</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/post-coronavirus-moving-trends.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-29 12:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Post-Coronavirus+Moving+Trends.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The coronavirus pandemic is sure to have long-reaching consequences in all walks of life, but some of these consequences might surprise you. 

For example, the pandemic might completely overturn recent trends regarding where people choose to live. Over the last three decades, people have increasingly preferred cities over suburbs. Recent studies show that each new generation of young people has been more and more likely to move to cities, and many opt to stay in those cities even after getting married and starting a family. 

Post-coronavirus, this may well change. The most obvious reason is health. Urban areas are more crowded and involve more human interaction, which means greater exposure to potential viruses. Also, shelter-in-place orders are harder to bear in an urban environment. By comparison, a house in the suburbs can offer more space, a backyard, and easier access to areas where you can exercise and spend time safely outdoors.

“Demand is rising, with Zillow and Realtor.com both reporting increased search traffic and buyer inquiries.”

Additionally, workplaces are changing. Many people will continue to work from home after the pandemic subsides. Along with falling gas prices, this makes long commutes a smaller issue than it had been in the past. 

A recent Harris Poll showed that 46% of city-dwellers are considering a move, compared to just 26% of suburban residents and 21% of rural residents. 

While home sales nearly came to a halt at the end of March, that’s now changing. Demand is rising, with Zillow and Realtor.com both reporting increased search traffic and buyer inquiries. In the Madison area, I can certainly vouch for an increase in activity. 

Granted, this situation changes daily, but I stay on top of the local Madison area market. Whether you’re thinking of buying, selling, or just need some advice, give me a call or shoot me an email and I’d be happy to guide you. I hope you and your family stay safe and healthy. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Post-Coronavirus+Moving+Trends.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Post-Coronavirus+Moving+Trends.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>COVID-19 may overturn recent trends regarding where people choose to live.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>COVID-19 may overturn recent trends regarding where people choose to live.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for a Safe Move During This Time</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-tips-for-a-safe-move-during-this-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-15 14:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/3+Tips+for+a+Safe+Move+During+This+Time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, several folks have asked me about how they can keep their families safe during the moving process right now. Since the COVID-19 pandemic is ongoing, I have three tips for you to help make your move safe and healthy:

1. It’s worth spending a bit of extra money. The American Moving and Storage Association recommends passing on free, recycled boxes from supermarkets and liquor stores. Instead, get new moving boxes and packing tape. The reason is simple: Less chance of exposure to the virus. Stock up on adequate disinfectants and wipes for yourself, your moving truck, and any shared equipment you might be using.  

If you can afford it and it makes sense for your situation, hire a company that will handle the move for you safely and strategically. Many moving companies currently provide virtual estimates and contactless moving, which reduces risk significantly.

“Disinfect high-contact points such as doorknobs and countertops.”

2. Preparation is more important than ever. A move often becomes a messy and disorganized affair. Now is the time to make it as neat as possible. Pack up everything and prepare it in advance of the actual move. By minimizing moving time, you’re minimizing contact and exposure. If you’re doing the move yourself, make sure to clean the truck and any shared moving bins or boxes. If you’re hiring a moving company, then spend the time to vet them. You’ll want to know what specific measures they’re using to deal with the pandemic—both with their equipment and their employees. 

3. Respect the threat. A move can be a frustrating experience. However, this is no time to throw caution to the wind and get careless. That means ongoing advice about social distancing, gloves, masks, and hygiene still applies. For example, if you are working with a moving company, make sure they have access to a sink with soap or hand sanitizer. Additionally, make sure to disinfect high-contact points such as doorknobs and countertops once the move is complete.

Moving isn’t always the most pleasant experience and this pandemic situation certainly doesn’t help, but it is possible to move safely in today’s market. If you have any questions about your move or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/3+Tips+for+a+Safe+Move+During+This+Time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/3+Tips+for+a+Safe+Move+During+This+Time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re considering a move right now, here are some helpful tips.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re considering a move right now, here are some helpful tips.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Home Buying and Selling Works Right Now</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-home-buying-and-selling-works-right-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-01 14:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/How+Home+Buying+and+Selling+Works+Right+Now.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How does the process of buying or selling a home look during the COVID-19 pandemic? I’ve been hearing that question a lot lately, and I’m going to dive into the topic today so that you have a clear, detailed answer. 

Feel free to follow along in the video above or use the timestamps I’ve provided below to navigate the discussion at your leisure:

0:25- The first question home sellers should be asking themselves before deciding to take the leap

1:15- A few more factors for home sellers to consider in order to enhance their experience

3:15- Advice for nervous buyers who are hesitant to purchase right now

5:05- How to embrace a more digital real estate market with the proper plan

5:55- A note about coronavirus addendums for both buyers and sellers

6:50- Wrapping things up

If you have any further questions for me about buying, selling, or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email today. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/How+Home+Buying+and+Selling+Works+Right+Now.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/How+Home+Buying+and+Selling+Works+Right+Now.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Although the way people buy and sell homes has changed, it hasn’t stopped us from continuing to help our clients reach their real estate goals. Here’s how we’re operating in this new normal.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Although the way people buy and sell homes has changed, it hasn’t stopped us from continuing to help our clients reach their real estate goals. Here’s how we’re operating in this new normal.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Economy After COVID-19</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-economy-after-covid-19.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-20 15:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Our+Economy+After+COVID-19.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The human toll of the coronavirus pandemic may forever change families, yet the economic impact will rebound with a cycle of downturn followed by economic expansion, as we’ve seen play out in the U.S. economy many times before.

Today I’d like to share what leading experts and current research indicate about the economic impact we’ll likely see as a result of COVID-19. Let’s start with a forecast of the U.S. Gross Domestic Product (GDP).

When looking at GDP (the measure of our country’s economic health), a survey of three leading financial institutions projects a sharp decline followed by a steep rebound in the second half of this year.

A recent study from John Burns Consulting notes that past pandemics have created V-shaped economic recoveries, and had minimal impact on housing prices. This certainly gives us hope and optimism regarding what is to come as this crisis passes.

“This won’t last forever, and we will get back to growth mode—we’ve got this.”

With this historical analysis in mind, many business owners are also optimistically anticipating a bright economic return. A recent PricewaterhouseCoopers survey captures this confidence, noting 66% of surveyed business owners believe their companies will return to normal business rhythms within a month of the pandemic passing, and 90% feel they should be back to normal operation one to three months afterward.

From expert financial institutions to business leaders across the country, we can clearly see that a quick return to normal once the current crisis subsides is not too far away. In essence, this pandemic won’t last forever, and we will get back to growth mode—we’ve got this. 

Lives and businesses are being impacted by COVID-19, but experts do see a light at the end of the tunnel. As the economy slows down due to the health crisis, we can take the guidance and advice from experts that this too will pass.

If you have any questions about real estate, please feel free to reach out via phone or email. We would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Our+Economy+After+COVID-19.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Our+Economy+After+COVID-19.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What will our economy look like once the coronavirus pandemic has passed? Here’s what experts say.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What will our economy look like once the coronavirus pandemic has passed? Here’s what experts say.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Sweet Tax Deductions When Selling a Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-sweet-tax-deductions-when-selling-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-03 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/5+Sweet+Tax+Deductions+When+Selling+a+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

You may be wondering if there are tax deductions you can take when selling a home. The answer is: You bet!

Sure, you may remember that 2018’s new tax code—aka the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act—changed some rules for homeowners. Rest assured that if you sold your home last year (or are planning to in the future), your tax deductions when you file with the IRS can still amount to sizable savings.

Here are five different tax deductions you can take as a home seller:

1. Selling costs. These deductions are allowed as long as they are directly tied to the sale of the home and you lived in the home for at least two out of the five years preceding the sale. Another caveat: The home must be a principal residence and not an investment property. These costs can include legal fees, title fees, advertising costs, commissions, and perhaps even staging costs. Just remember that you can’t deduct these costs in the same way as, say, mortgage interest. Instead, you subtract them from the sale price of your home, which in turn positively affects your capital gains tax.

“I recommend consulting with your tax advisor for further clarification.”

2. Home improvements and repairs. If you renovated a few rooms to make your home more marketable (so you could fetch a higher sale price), you can deduct those upgrade costs as well. This includes painting the house or repairing the roof or water heater. There’s a catch, and it all boils down to timing: You can deduct those expenses as selling costs as long as they were made within 90 days of the closing.

3. Property taxes. This deduction is capped at $10,000. So, if you were dutifully paying your property taxes up to the point when you sold your home, you can deduct the amount you paid in property taxes this year up to $10,000.

4. Mortgage interest. As with property taxes, you can deduct the interest on your mortgage for the portion of the year you owned your home. Just remember that under the 2018 tax code, new homeowners (and home sellers) can deduct the interest on up to only $750,000 of mortgage debt. That is, unless you obtained your mortgage prior to December 15, 2017. If you did, you can deduct up to $1,000,000.

Note that the mortgage interest and property taxes are itemized deductions. This means that, in order for it to work in your favor, all of your itemized deductions need to be greater than the new standard deduction.

5. Capital gains tax for sellers. The rule isn’t technically a deduction (it’s an exclusion), but you’re still going to like it. As a reminder, capital gains are your profits from selling your home—whatever cash is left after paying off your expenses, plus any outstanding mortgage debt. These profits are taxed as income, but here’s the good news: You can exclude up to $250,000 of the capital gains from the sale if you’re single, and $500,000 if married. The only big catch is that you must have lived in your home at least two of the past five years.

If you want further clarification on these five sweet tax deductions, I recommend you consult with your tax advisor. If you have any real estate-related questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/5+Sweet+Tax+Deductions+When+Selling+a+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/5+Sweet+Tax+Deductions+When+Selling+a+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Selling a home offers many different benefits from a tax perspective. Here are five of them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Selling a home offers many different benefits from a tax perspective. Here are five of them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What the Coronavirus Means for Our Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-the-coronavirus-means-for-our-real-estate-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-20 12:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/What+the+Coronavirus+Means+for+Our+Real+Estate+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As you’re aware, there’s been a lot of talk in the news lately about the coronavirus, and many people have reached out to me wondering how this will impact our real estate market.  

When we try to predict what will happen in our local market, whether it’s due to the coronavirus or any other factor, we look to what’s happening on our nation’s coasts, meaning markets like Los Angeles, New York City, and San Francisco. These are good leading indicators of trends that will eventually impact our market. When we see a shift in the luxury markets out on the coast, that’s something we’ll probably see in South Central Wisconsin sooner rather than later. 

“If your home is valued above that or the $500,000 mark, I recommend listing it sooner rather than later.”

Whether you’re buying or selling, if you’re concerned about the coronavirus’ impact on our market, my first piece of advice is to reach out to me. We can talk about your goals and formulate a strategy to accomplish them. 

If you’re a seller, one thing we do know is that the median home price in Dane County is $285,000, so if your home is valued above that or the $500,000 mark, I recommend listing it sooner rather than later. We still have limited inventory and there are plenty of buyers, so strike while the iron is hot. 

On the flip side, because of the volatility we’re seeing in the stock market due to the coronavirus, mortgage rates remain lower than last year. This is making the biggest impact below the $285,000 price point. Inventory is already tight in this market, and low interest rates will bring out more buyers and increase competition. 

What we don’t want to see happen is sellers thinking now is a great time to raise prices, because that might not play out how you imagine it. Like I said, I recommend first giving me a call so we can find out what your home is worth, make a plan, and capture the attention of all the buyers out there taking advantage of these low interest rates. 

Moving forward, we’ll keep an eye on this situation. If you have any questions about this topic at all, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I’m here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/What+the+Coronavirus+Means+for+Our+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/What+the+Coronavirus+Means+for+Our+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>With the coronavirus dominating the news feed lately, I’ll fill you in on how it’s impacting our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>With the coronavirus dominating the news feed lately, I’ll fill you in on how it’s impacting our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in Our Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-05 16:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Whats+Happening+in+Our+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Joe Long of Guild Mortgage joins me today to dispel some common market misconceptions and share his perspective from the lending side of things. 

What’s going to happen with the market in 2020 and beyond? Many homeowners remember losing value in their homes from 2008 to 2012, but since 2013 home values have been recovering. Since homes have been appreciating for so long, many believe it’s time for a market correction. 

It’s important to understand that the market fundamentals we have now are different than the ones we had back then. Just because the market’s been appreciating for a while doesn’t mean there’s something wrong or properties will start losing value. From 2005 to 2008, we saw rapid appreciation that was unsustainable—prices rose as high as 10% per year. Historically, home values in Dane County appreciate 3% to 4% per year. That’s sustainable, so if homes keep appreciating at that rate, they’ll outpace inflation and, theoretically, never cool down. 

“If you bought a home and something were to go wrong, you’d be fine long-term.”

After 2013, the pace of home value recovery increased rapidly, but now it’s slowing and we’re settling into a nice, pillowy landing. Last year, home values statewide rose about 5%, and this year they’re predicted to rise between 3% and 4%. Some might see this slowdown as a bad thing, but this return to normalcy is a good thing. 

Based on the average prediction of where the market’s headed in the next five years, if you purchased a $250,000 house now, it would appreciate by $47,500 by January 2025—a nice, slow pace. 

You need a place to live no matter what, and you can either pay your landlord’s rent or your mortgage. Only one of you is getting that appreciation, so you might as well take advantage of that equity. Many people lost a lot of money during the previous recession, but the No. 1 reason people buy houses isn’t that it’s a financial investment but because they want to control where they live. 

Those who lost value starting in 2008 got it all back by 2017. If you bought a home and something were to go wrong, you’d be fine long-term. You’ll still pay off your mortgage and come out with a lot of equity. If nothing goes wrong, you’ll come out way ahead. 

If you have any lending questions, feel free to give Joe a call at (608) 729-5379 or email him at jlong@guildmortgage.net. If you have any other questions about the real estate market, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Whats+Happening+in+Our+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Whats+Happening+in+Our+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Home appreciation is slowing down, but this return to normalcy is a good thing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Home appreciation is slowing down, but this return to normalcy is a good thing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Legislative Action All Homeowners Should Follow</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/legislative-action-all-homeowners-should-follow.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-24 16:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Legislative+Action+All+Homeowners+Should+Follow.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Earlier this month, I had the opportunity to go to our state capitol building for the annual Realtor® and Government Day. Today, I’m sharing my experience by recapping the three main topics discussed at the event, as well as sharing my insight on these matters. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: 

1:29 - The issue of riparian water rights (2018 supreme court case regarding homeowners’ right to build a pier)

3:33 - Legislation in the works prohibiting the habit of “chasing sales” 

4:45 - The lack of workforce housing in our area and proposed remedies

 6:20 - Wrapping things up 

If you’re interested in discussing these important topics in more detail, please feel free to reach out by phone or email. I’d love the opportunity to inform the homeowners in our great state and gain different perspectives on these issues. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Legislative+Action+All+Homeowners+Should+Follow.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Legislative+Action+All+Homeowners+Should+Follow.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The Realtor® and Government Day event at our state capitol building opened my eyes. Here’s what property-related legislation is being discussed and how Realtors® are going to bat for homeowners.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The Realtor® and Government Day event at our state capitol building opened my eyes. Here’s what property-related legislation is being discussed and how Realtors® are going to bat for homeowners.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Strategies to Help You Win in the Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/strategies-to-help-you-win-in-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-07 16:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Strategies+to+Help+You+Win+in+the+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Most markets around the country have been experiencing historically low inventory, meaning that there just aren’t that many homes for sale in first-time homebuyers’ price ranges. It’s not that uncommon for a first-timer to end up in competition with one or even 10 other buyers, so we’ve become pretty crafty and strategic to make our buyers’ offers stand out to the seller. To help me lay out some potential roadmaps to success, Joe Long from Guild Mortgage joins me to discuss some of the strategies that he has seen work for homebuyers in our tricky seller’s market.

Feel free to follow along in the video above or else use the timestamps below to navigate the discussion in depth at your leisure:

1:28—Find out what’s important to the seller

2:48—Consider your offer’s terms and contingencies

4:08—Use a TBD underwrite

5:52—Appraisal forgiveness and a few other tactics to entice a seller to accept your offer

Remember, for a home seller, the most important thing isn’t always pricing. Using a combination of these strategies can help you stand out from the crowd and win the home you want in our market.

If you’re in the market to buy a home and you’d like to learn more about how we can help you beat the competition for a home you have your sights set on, reach out to us by phone or email. We’d be glad to help you discover tools and tricks to help you succeed in your goals.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Strategies+to+Help+You+Win+in+the+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Strategies+to+Help+You+Win+in+the+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m joined by Joe Long from Guild Mortgage to discuss some of the strategies that he has seen work for homebuyers in the challenging market we’ve been facing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m joined by Joe Long from Guild Mortgage to discuss some of the strategies that he has seen work for homebuyers in the challenging market we’ve been facing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Buy into the Recession Doom & Gloom?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/should-you-buy-into-the-recession-doom-gloom.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-24 16:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Should+You+Buy+into+the+Recession+Doom+%26+Gloom_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m sure you’ve heard a lot of buzz from people trying to predict when the next housing crash will be. While I do feel like there’s a good chance that we may see a small recession or some little blips in the economy, there is also good evidence to suggest that we probably won’t see a housing crash like what happened in 2008. 

Unlike the last time that we did have a housing crash, credit has been tightened significantly. Lenders are doing their due diligence before approving home loans. The notorious subprime mortgages that helped spur the ‘08 crash are far from the norm in today’s market. 

The median price in our area went up 6.4% over 2019 to $295,000, all due to a lack of inventory. Our inventory remains low because people that invest in new building projects simply aren’t doing so as much. A lot of builders say they want to start on such projects, but lack the tradespeople needed to keep up with the high demand. 

“Mortgage rates remain at near historic lows.”

Another reason why inventory is low boils down to demographics. A majority of the homeowners now are baby boomers, and they’re simply holding onto their homes longer. This is squaring up directly against the millennial generation, which is primed to make the majority of home purchases in the nation. Not enough homes are available, so competition increases and prices follow suit. 

Mortgage rates remain at or near historic lows. To put this in perspective, pretend you’re in the market for a $250,000 home. If you wanted to maintain that same monthly payment that you’re budgeting for, but mortgage rates were to increase by even 1%, your buying power would be reduced to about $220,000. Move when it makes sense for your particular situation, but know that it’s always wise to take advantage of really low rates. 

If you’re trying to time your purchase by waiting for the next supposed crash, the chances are high that you’re going to miss out on opportunities. Is there a perfect time to buy or sell a home? Objectively, maybe or maybe not. Subjectively, the right time is whenever you decide. 

So if you’re ready to buy or sell real estate here in the Madison area, I’d love a chance to talk to you. Give a call or shoot me an email so we can discuss how I can help you achieve your goals for 2020.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Should+You+Buy+into+the+Recession+Doom+%26+Gloom_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/Should+You+Buy+into+the+Recession+Doom+%26+Gloom_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s what you need to know about the 2020 real estate market, and whether there will be a ‘perfect time’ to buy or sell.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s what you need to know about the 2020 real estate market, and whether there will be a ‘perfect time’ to buy or sell.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Take an Inventory of Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-take-an-inventory-of-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-10 10:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/How+to+Take+an+Inventory+of+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a homeowner, it’s very important that you do an inventory of the possessions in your home in the event that something catastrophic happens to it, like a fire. There’s no time like the present to do this. 

Could you name the make, model, and price of all the TVs you own? Do you know where all the jewelry, trinkets, or collectibles are and how much they’re worth? This kind of thing can add up if something catastrophic does happen to your home, and it’s definitely something you don’t want to deal with. 

That being said, I have two main tips for you to remember when doing your home inventory.  

“The last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth.”

First, use your smartphone to go room by room and take pictures and video of every important item you want to catalog. 

After you’re done doing that, use a cloud-based service to upload and store your photos and video. In my opinion, Google Drive works best for this. If you already have a Google account, then it’s free. It has quite a bit of storage, and you can also utilize Google Sheets to further itemize your possessions. 

Like I said, the last thing you want to do in the event of a home disaster is to try to remember all the items you owned and estimate what they were worth. 

If you have more questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/How+to+Take+an+Inventory+of+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2020/How+to+Take+an+Inventory+of+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It’s time for you to take an inventory of your home, and here’s how you can get started.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It’s time for you to take an inventory of your home, and here’s how you can get started.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Decluttering After the Holiday Season</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tips-for-decluttering-after-the-holiday-season.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-27 10:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/December/5+Tips+for+Decluttering+After+the+Holiday+Season.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I hope you all had a wonderful holiday and are excited for the new year. If you’re like my family, now is the time you look to declutter your home as you prepare for the coming year, and I’ve got some tips to help you do that more easily today:

1. Don’t wait. Don’t let weeks pass by as your holiday items sit in the home without a proper place. I recommend getting on the task of decluttering right away.

2. Prioritize. If you’re struggling to find a place for one or more items that you have, consider whether the items are something that you need to hold on to. There may be certain items that are important to you and your family, but there may also be other items that you’ve acquired over the years that you don’t really use in your annual decorating. If that’s the case, it might be time to donate or resell those items.

“A lot of your extra gift wrap and trimmings are recyclable.”

3. Organize gift wrap. It can be very easy for rolls of gift wrap to get spread out and take up a lot of room. Now is a great time to go through and organize that gift wrap to make sure you’re not holding on to scraps of paper that won’t help you in the future. Maybe you could repurpose those for a craft project or something else.

4. Recycle. Make sure that you’re not just tossing all of your extra gift wrap and trimmings in the trash. A lot of this stuff is recycled material and you want to properly dispose of it according to your local recycling priorities.

5. Prepare for next year. You may have things that you kept in storage and didn’t pull out for the holidays. I like to take this time of year to evaluate the inventory I have and see if any of them are ones I intend to hold onto in the future. It’s also just a good time to organize your stuff so that you know where everyone is. 

If you have any questions for me about this list or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/December/5+Tips+for+Decluttering+After+the+Holiday+Season.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/December/5+Tips+for+Decluttering+After+the+Holiday+Season.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Start your year off right with a little less holiday clutter in 2020. Here are five tips that will help you out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Start your year off right with a little less holiday clutter in 2020. Here are five tips that will help you out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Seasons Greetings from the Holt Real Estate Team</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/seasons-greetings-from-the-holt-real-estate-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-13 14:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

From all of us here at the Holt Real Estate Team: We wish you and your family the very best this holiday season. This is the time you should spend with your family and friends, and give joy and thanks for all that you have, so enjoy it! Speaking of giving thanks: We appreciate all of your support this year, and we love being able to help people make their real estate dreams come true. Here’s to helping even more of you in 2020! Thank you all so much, and happy holidays!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We wish you and your family the very best this holiday season.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We wish you and your family the very best this holiday season.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Everything You Need to Know About USDA Loans</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/everything-you-need-to-know-about-usda-loans.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-26 13:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/November/Everything+You+Need+to+Know+About+USDA+Loans.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a low- to moderate-income buyer, or just someone without a significant down payment saved up, then a USDA loan might be the perfect path to homeownership for you. 

The USDA loan program allows homeowners to purchase a qualifying rural property for no money down. Like any mortgage option, you will need to meet certain criteria, though. The primary qualifying factors are your income, for which limits will vary by area, as well as the location of the property.

“The bottom line is that the USDA loan is a great option for those savvy enough to take advantage.”

You can click here to learn more and for access to a loan availability map showing what properties near you may qualify. 

Homes located within Stoughton city limits, for example, are ineligible, but areas just to the north (near Madison) do qualify—as do properties in the Village of McFarland, the Village of Oregon, Deforest/Windsor/ Mount Horeb, Cambridge, and many other municipalities. 

The bottom line is that the USDA loan is a great option for those savvy enough to take advantage. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/November/Everything+You+Need+to+Know+About+USDA+Loans.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/November/Everything+You+Need+to+Know+About+USDA+Loans.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the USDA loan and what makes it such a great deal for those who qualify? Let’s discuss.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the USDA loan and what makes it such a great deal for those who qualify? Let’s discuss.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Thanksgiving Message From Our Team</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-thanksgiving-message-from-our-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-18 16:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I wanted to take a moment today to say thank you. Thank you to all of you wonderful folks who have trusted us with your real estate needs in the Madison area. We also want to thank those of you who have partnered with our company to ensure that our clients’ experiences are second-to-none. We can’t thank you enough for all that you do to help our team grow and thrive. On behalf of everyone here at The Holt Real Estate Team, thank you for your support and we hope you have a wonderful Thanksgiving. To hear my full message, watch this short video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We couldn’t be more grateful for all of your support this year. Here’s our message to all of you this Thanksgiving season.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We couldn’t be more grateful for all of your support this year. Here’s our message to all of you this Thanksgiving season.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons to Buy an Investment Property Before Becoming a Homeowner</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-reasons-to-buy-an-investment-property-before-becoming-a-homeowner.html</link>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-23 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/5+Reasons+to+Buy+an+Investment+Property+Before+Becoming+a+Homeowner.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently someone approached me to ask whether buying an investment property before buying their first primary residence was a good idea, and, actually, it very well may be. Here are five reasons why: 

1. Interest rates are low. Low interest rates mean greater purchasing power, which gives those looking to invest a unique opportunity to enjoy low monthly payments on their property. 

2. Homes are continuing to appreciate each year. According to Core Logic’s value index, home values have increased every year for the past seven years. And, according to most experts, real estate is one of the safest (and wisest) investments.

“If you ever tire of renting your property out, or if you’re simply ready to become a homeowner, yourself, there is always the option for you to move into the home.”

3. Real estate investing creates passive income. Beyond just having someone else cover the expense of your monthly payments, renting out a property means that you can rely on your investment to generate passive income, as well. 

4. Short-term rentals are popular right now. Even if you aren’t interested in being a long-term landlord, short-term rentals are in high demand right now. Airbnb and VRBO have opened up numerous options for investors. Your investment property also doesn’t need to be local. You can purchase a rental property in a tourist “hot spot” and have someone else manage it for you. 

5. You can turn the investment into your primary residence later on. If you ever tire of renting your property out, or if you’re simply ready to become a homeowner, yourself, there is always the option for you to move into the home. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/5+Reasons+to+Buy+an+Investment+Property+Before+Becoming+a+Homeowner.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/5+Reasons+to+Buy+an+Investment+Property+Before+Becoming+a+Homeowner.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is it a good idea for those who haven’t bought their first home yet to buy a rental property? Actually, it may be, and here are five reasons why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is it a good idea for those who haven’t bought their first home yet to buy a rental property? Actually, it may be, and here are five reasons why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Preparing Your Home for Our Fall Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-preparing-your-home-for-our-fall-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-27 11:57:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/4+Tips+for+Preparing+Your+Home+for+Our+Fall+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The temperature is dropping, leaves are changing color, and pumpkin spice is everywhere you look. With fall color and produce back in season, you might be tempted to load up your house with both. However, if you plan to sell your home this fall, you might want to exercise some restraint. In the eyes of buyers, less is more. Here are four tips to consider: 

1. Pay attention to your fall-themed curb appeal. While too many fall decorations can distract attention away from your home’s best features, a few tasteful accents can produce an inviting atmosphere. Take the time to rake and round up fallen leaves and do general yard care. Buyers may give you a pass if they see your lawn is blanketed with leaves, but that doesn’t mean your home will make a good impression. 

“While too many fall decorations can distract attention away from your home’s best features, a few tasteful accents can produce an inviting atmosphere.”

2. Go easy on the gory Halloween decorations. Decorating your home with fake blood, guts, and skeletons might just be part of getting into the holiday spirit for you, but you never know what kind of reaction you’ll get from buyers. Some may be amused, but some may be frightened, and anything that has the potential to turn off a buyer is a no-no when listing your home. Play it safe with your decor choices, so you can appeal to the masses. 

3. Let in the light. It’s always a good idea to pull back the curtains and allow natural light to help you showcase your home. With shorter days in the fall and winter, you want to make sure you maximize the amount of light flooding into your home. This way, your home will appear larger. 

4. Make the space inviting. As the weather cools off, a warm and cozy atmosphere will give buyers a warm and cozy feeling. Place plush throws on your couch and beds and add fall-accented pillows to your couch and chairs as well. 

If you have any questions about selling your home or about real estate in general, or there’s a topic you’d like me to cover in a future video, feel free to give me a call at 608-345-6594 or you can email me at JDHolt@KW.com. I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/4+Tips+for+Preparing+Your+Home+for+Our+Fall+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/4+Tips+for+Preparing+Your+Home+for+Our+Fall+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you planning to sell your home this fall? If so, these four tips will give your home a tasteful and pleasant feel.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you planning to sell your home this fall? If so, these four tips will give your home a tasteful and pleasant feel.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Keep Your Yard Fresh This Winter</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-keep-your-yard-fresh-this-winter.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-13 15:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/How+to+Keep+Your+Yard+Fresh+This+Winter.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The other day, I was speaking with a friend of mine about their yard and gave them some advice about what they can do to make sure it stays in tip-top shape through the fall and winter as they prepare for a possible spring sale. Here are eight helpful tips that you can use to keep your yard in good shape:

1.  Fertilization and weed control. This helps reduce the stress your lawn will endure over the summer, and weed control will take care of those fall weeds as well. 

2. Aerate your yard. It should be overseeded as well. Aeration prepares it for winter and promotes healthy growth for spring. Overseeding helps fill in any bare spots and helps your lawn recover from the summer.

3. Rake and pick up leaves. This will reduce possible insect and disease damage over the winter. It’s also a good time to remove any dead or unsafe branches in your yard.

“Roots have a better chance to establish in the fall.”

4. The final mow of the season. Set your mower to the lowest height recommended for your grass on the last mow of the year to reduce the ability of diseases to affect them in the winter.

5. Plant trees and shrubs. In the fall, it gives roots a chance to establish in a lower-stress, moist environment.

6. Cut back and divide perennials. This will result in a more established plant next spring.

7. Add some fall color. Hearty mums are a great choice.

8. Plant spring bulbs. To ensure vibrant, early spring color in your landscaping, be sure to plant your bulbs in the fall.

If you have any questions for me about these tips or about anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/How+to+Keep+Your+Yard+Fresh+This+Winter.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/September/How+to+Keep+Your+Yard+Fresh+This+Winter.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Even though fall and winter are right around the corner, it's a great time to start preparing your yard for next year. Here are eight tips to help you do that.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Even though fall and winter are right around the corner, it's a great time to start preparing your yard for next year. Here are eight tips to help you do that.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Value of Having an Agent in Your Corner</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-value-of-having-an-agent-in-your-corner.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-29 17:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/The+Value+of+Having+an+Agent+in+Your+Corner.mp4</guid>
        <description>

To be honest, purchasing new construction isn’t all that different from purchasing an existing home in an established neighborhood. Of course, for either purchase, there’s a lot of value that having the support of a professional agent can bring you when making such an important (and expensive) decision.

If you visited a model home on the weekend and talked to the on-site sales agent, you likely wouldn’t be talking to an agent who had your best interests at heart. What I mean by that is that particular agent is likely employed by or represents the builder and their fiduciary responsibility is to them.

When you hire an agent of your own, you get the advocacy of someone who does have your best interests at heart and who will help you navigate the intricacies of negotiation, paperwork, terms, conditions, and every other aspect of the real estate process in order to ensure that you’re getting the best benefits from your purchase.

For example, builders may offer discounts, savings, or incentives if you work with their lender or select specific upgrades and finishes; as agents in your corner, we’ll make sure that those incentives truly are savings and won’t come back to bite you later on.

“As agents in your corner, we’ll make sure that the builder’s incentives truly are savings and won’t come back to bite you later on.”

Something else to take into consideration is how long you plan to live in the home. If, for whatever reason, this home ends up not being your forever home and you decide to resell it later on, your agent can also advise you on which upgrades you can do to increase your future resale value and which ones may actually decrease or not improve that value.

One of the biggest things an agent on your side can help you with is researching the builder: how they work, the quality of their products, their building programs, the incentives they offer, and their sales history.

And finally, it typically doesn’t cost you any extra money to hire an agent like myself to represent you. Like any seller in a real estate transaction, the builder will be the one who ends up paying for your agent’s commission. If you’re not working with an agent, don’t assume they will just pass that difference on to you as cost savings, often they may use that money instead for marketing or just for profit. I’ve found that most of the builders in our market are “agent-friendly” and like working with buyers that have representation; the key thing is that we, the agents, need to be the ones who introduce you to the builder, not the other way around. If you have more questions on that, send me a message and we can talk more.

If you see value in having an agent like myself represent you in the purchase of a new construction property, and are looking to buy a brand-new home, reach out to us. We’d love to have your back in the transaction.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/The+Value+of+Having+an+Agent+in+Your+Corner.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/The+Value+of+Having+an+Agent+in+Your+Corner.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why do you need the help of a Realtor to buy a new construction property? Today I’ll explain.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why do you need the help of a Realtor to buy a new construction property? Today I’ll explain.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Successfully Sell After a Failed Listing Attempt</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-successfully-sell-after-a-failed-listing-attempt.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-16 15:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/How+to+Successfully+Sell+After+a+Failed+Listing+Attempt.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There’s a common misconception among sellers (and even some real estate agents) that all it takes to sell a home is to stick a sign in the yard and wait for the offers to roll in. However, this couldn’t be further from the truth. Many sellers who attempt this route end up with expired listings.

So what do you do after this has happened to you? What does it take to make your second attempt at listing successful?

First, it’s important to realize that you’re not alone. Year to Date in Dane County, 10.68% of single-family home listings and 6.46% of all condo listings expired. 

But why?

There are actually a number of factors that can contribute to a listing’s success (or its failure). Chief among these factors are price, condition, and location, but also marketing. The marketing an agent uses to advertise a home can make or break its ability to sell. 

“Your agent needs to actively seek out buyers, rather than waiting for buyers to come to them.”

An effective marketing plan must include professional photography (and videography), an enticing description on its online listing, and adequate exposure. Your agent should use every available method to reach buyers, including social media advertising, print advertising, open houses, among other things. 

Proactive prospecting, in particular, is critical. In other words, your agent needs to actively seek out buyers, rather than waiting for buyers to come to them. 

If the agent you’re working with can’t do these things for you and your home, then it’s time to seek out a more experienced, knowledgeable professional. Our team would be happy to fill that role for you. So, if you or someone you know is looking to sell, please reach out to us. We can help you sell quickly and for top dollar, within a time frame that works for you. 

As always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me or my team a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/How+to+Successfully+Sell+After+a+Failed+Listing+Attempt.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/How+to+Successfully+Sell+After+a+Failed+Listing+Attempt.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If your listing expired once, there are a few steps you and your agent must take to ensure your second try is more successful. Find out what those steps are today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If your listing expired once, there are a few steps you and your agent must take to ensure your second try is more successful. Find out what those steps are today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Become a Homeowner?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-become-a-homeowner.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-02 12:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/Why+Become+a+Homeowner_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Just the other day, a renter I know who’s never been a homeowner asked me an interesting question: Is homeownership still one of the greatest ways to secure one’s financial future? The answer is a resounding yes. 

When you’re stepping into the market to buy a home for the first time, it’s easy to fix your attention on price and what your monthly mortgage payment will be, and understandably so. 

Up to this point, you’ve known exactly how much you were going to pay in rent each month, and now you’re trying to figure out how much house you can afford given your monthly budget.

Beyond price and your monthly payment, it’s also important to think about the home’s future value, or appreciation, over the life of your mortgage. When you sell your home, the majority of your profits will come from the equity you’ve gained between the time you bought the home and the years you’ve lived in the home. 

Although the market ebbs and flows and home values can ebb and flow with it, the value of real estate is always increasing, and there’s no real indication that will change anytime soon.

“The sooner you start paying off your mortgage, the better your financial circumstances will be later in life.”

Another advantage of becoming a homeowner early in life is that, more than likely, you’ll be able to pay off your mortgage during your working years. When you enter into retirement on a fixed income, having to continue paying on a mortgage can interfere with your ability to maintain your desired lifestyle. The sooner you start paying off your mortgage, the better your financial circumstances will be later in life.

Finally, for those who struggle to save money, owning a home is a means by which you can achieve this. Think of it as a kind of forced savings. As a homeowner, you’ll be forced to put away enough money to stay on top of your mortgage, cover your monthly expenses, and so on. All the while, your home’s value will grow, and that equity will pay dividends when you sell it down the line. 

If you have any questions about our local market or real estate in general or if there’s a topic you’d like me to cover in a future video, reach out to me by phone at 608-345-6594 or you can email me at JDHolt@KW.com. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/Why+Become+a+Homeowner_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/August/Why+Become+a+Homeowner_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is homeownership still one of the greatest ways to secure one’s financial future? It absolutely is and today I’ll discuss just a few reasons why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is homeownership still one of the greatest ways to secure one’s financial future? It absolutely is and today I’ll discuss just a few reasons why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest News and Notes From Our Summer Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-latest-news-and-notes-from-our-summer-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-19 11:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/The+Latest+News+and+Notes+From+Our+Summer+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the latest news on our Dane County market and beyond?  

Much like the last few months and years, we’re seeing a scarcity of inventory in certain segments of our market. Conditions continue to bode well for sellers, but we’re also seeing some changes that may signal greater opportunities for buyers. 

Recently, Dane County has seen an uptick in the number of homes on the market, both in terms of single-family homes and condos: 1,000 single-family properties and 225 condos are currently listed. 

Another recent development is homes are spending more time on the market. For single-family homes, the average days on market is 67 days, and the average condo is sitting on the market for a little over 120 days.  

I’m constantly being asked about inventory and justifiably so. The amount of inventory we have is a prime indicator of whether we’re in a seller’s market, a buyer’s market, or a balanced market. We’re firmly in a seller’s market at the moment, and though our inventory situation is showing modest signs of going the opposite direction or toward a balanced state, we’re still nowhere near where we’d like to be.  

In the up-to-$200,000 price point, we have just 0.85 months’ worth of inventory, which means homes priced around there are flying off the market. When we move up to the $200,000 to $350,000 range, inventory is slightly higher with 1.4 months’ worth. Inventory doubles in the $350,000 to $500,000 range, and rises still in the luxury market to 5.3 months’ worth. 

“Conditions continue to bode well for sellers, but we’re also seeing some changes that may signal greater opportunities for buyers.”

As for median sales price, single-family homes are selling for $319,000 right now. Contrast that with the median price for these homes in the spring, which was $300,000. The median sale price for condos has slightly increased to $200,000. 

Now, I know not everyone lives in or is focused on the numbers for Dane County, so let’s quickly run through the numbers for the larger South Central Wisconsin region:


  Regional inventory is at 2.8 months’ worth
  Regional median sales price for single-family homes has fallen a bit to $232,000
  Regional median sales price for condos is at about $190,000 


Lastly and surprisingly, our interest rates are still unbelievably low: They’re currently sub-4% for a 30-year fixed mortgage. Even as home prices increase, it’s still a great time to get into a new home and secure an interest rate in the low-4% range.   

If you’re a seller who’s looking to move up, our current market is rife with opportunities to do so. You’ll find that conditions are favorable to sell your home, and the availability of homes provides more flexibility for you as a buyer as well. 

If you have any questions about the area’s real estate market or if there’s a topic you’d like me to feature on a future video, reach out to me by phone at 608-345-6594 or by email at JDHolt@KW.com. I look forward to hearing from you! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/The+Latest+News+and+Notes+From+Our+Summer+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/The+Latest+News+and+Notes+From+Our+Summer+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re halfway through the year, which makes it a good time to bring you an update on our summer market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re halfway through the year, which makes it a good time to bring you an update on our summer market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Buy and Sell a Home at the Same Time</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-buy-and-sell-a-home-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-05 12:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+at+the+Same+Time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you currently own a home and are thinking of selling it and buying a new one, you might be daunted by the process of juggling both transactions. Luckily, I’m here to give you a few tips on how to navigate the process.

First, talk to your lender. Before you even begin to look at homes, you should make sure that all of your finances are in order. You’ll want to ensure that nothing has changed in your financial picture that you’re not aware of and to figure out your options. 

“Before you even begin to look at homes, you should make sure that all of your finances are in order.”

There are three ways to go about handling both these transactions at once:

1. Sell your current home first. To do this, you’ll need to list your home on the market at an appropriate price that you know will help it sell quickly. This can be an advantageous way to go about it, since a lot of sellers will be hesitant to accept an offer that’s contingent on you selling your current home.

Once you close on the sale of your current home, you could potentially do a rent-back agreement, in which the purchasers of your home agree to let you live there for a predetermined period of time for rent. This would allow you time to find and purchase a new home to move into.

2. Buy your new home first. In this situation, you might be saddled with two concurrent mortgages, so it may not be ideal, depending on your financial situation.

3. Buy and sell in the same day. It might be tricky, but it is possible to plan things in such a way that you can close on the sale of your current home and the purchase of your new home in the same day. Of course, this doesn’t give you much time to move, so you may have to plan ahead.

If you have any questions about today’s topic or about the local real estate market, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/July/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Buy+and+Sell+a+Home+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you currently currently own a home and are thinking of buying a new one, the process can be difficult to navigate. Here are a few tips to help.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you currently currently own a home and are thinking of buying a new one, the process can be difficult to navigate. Here are a few tips to help.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Enhance Your Home’s Appeal to Buyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-enhance-your-homes-appeal-to-buyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-21 14:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Enhance+Your+Homes+Appeal+to+Buyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you’re a home seller looking to create the best first impression on potential buyers, there are a number of different strategies to follow:

1. Start by improving the curb appeal. Start from the street and work your way in. This includes looking at things like your driveway, the exterior landscaping, and the exterior of the home in general. Look at the outside of the property from a buyer’s perspective to make sure that it looks the best it possibly can. This way, when potential buyers drive or walk by the home, they’ll get the impression your home is well-maintained.

2. Have a clean entryway. Make sure that your doormat is clean, your front door is freshly painted and presentable, and that your doorbell is in working order. The color of your door should complement your home, and if possible, the neighborhood at large.

3. Eliminate any odors. You don’t want potential buyers to walk into your home, only to be smacked in the face by the odor of pets, cigarette smoke, and even chemical smells—be careful to limit your use of deodorizers and fragrances, which can turn off potential buyers. The key when it comes to scent is balance.

“Be careful to limit your use of deodorizers and fragrances, which can turn off potential buyers.”

4. Deep clean the house. If you really want to create a great first impression, you’ll need to take the time to deep clean your entire home, meaning you should clean the carpets, floors, and all other surfaces. And don’t forget to dust! You don’t want to give buyers the impression that you’re not maintaining your home as well as you could be. They may wonder if there are other areas you’re neglecting when it comes to home care.

5. Declutter your home. You don’t want to have various piles of your possessions lying around the home, especially if they take up floor space. Be sure to clean out and organize your storage areas, like your closets and cabinets. This is a good time to go through your things and purge those items you no longer need, want, or use. This will make your home seem neater and more accessible to a buyer.

6. Repaint. Now, I don’t mean that you need to repaint the entire exterior or interior of your home, although there are studies that show you can recoup one-and-a-half to two times your investment in your resale price if you do. What I’m focusing on here, though, is making sure that you’ve touched up any nicks, dings, or chips in your paint. Be sure to use a neutral color palette if you want to appeal to the widest pool of buyers!

If you’re thinking about selling your home in today’s market and you have any questions about what you can do to sell quickly and for top dollar, feel free to reach out to me. I’m always here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Enhance+Your+Homes+Appeal+to+Buyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Enhance+Your+Homes+Appeal+to+Buyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What can you do to make sure that you’re truly creating the best first impression for your home? Find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What can you do to make sure that you’re truly creating the best first impression for your home? Find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Downsize Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-downsize-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-07 10:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Downsize+Your+Home_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Downsizing is the process of moving from a larger home to a smaller one. Why might people do this? As it turns out, there are many reasons:

Most often, people downsize when there has been a life-changing occurrence, such as when the kids graduate and move away, or maybe you’re on the verge of retirement. 

It could also be that you just realize that managing a home of a certain size is more work, stress, and money than you can handle, and so a smaller home simply seems more feasible for you. This is especially true for elderly homeowners, and even for those who lead lifestyles that are simply too busy to allow them to juggle home maintenance with their lives.

“If you’re on a larger lot that requires continuous landscaping and maintenance, perhaps that means it’s time to look for something a little more manageable.”

Especially for those whose kids have moved away from home, another reason to downsize is the realization that you just have too much space that you don’t use. That goes for the outside, as well; if you’re on a larger lot that requires continuous landscaping and maintenance, perhaps that means it’s time to look for something a little more manageable. 

Lastly, there are financial benefits to downsizing your home. If you’ve lived in your home for a long time, you’ve probably built up a fair amount of equity. Now could be the most opportune time to put your home on the market and make the move using the money you have tied up in the home.

If you have any questions or comments about downsizing, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Downsize+Your+Home_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/June/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Downsize+Your+Home_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do know if it’s time to downsize your home? Learn the signs right here.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do know if it’s time to downsize your home? Learn the signs right here.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling on Your Own vs. Hiring a Real Estate Professional</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/selling-on-your-own-vs-hiring-a-real-estate-professional.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-24 11:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+On+Your+Own+vs.+Hiring+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you’re weighing the decision to hire a real estate professional to help you sell your home versus just doing it by yourself, there are four key points to keep in mind that will help you make your final decision about which route to go:

1. Contracts and paperwork. Regardless of who’s doing the selling, you’re still entering into a legally binding contract with the other party when you do sell it. If you’re not using a real estate professional to help you, you’ll want to have a real estate attorney review the contracts for you so that you can be sure that your transaction is legally compliant.

2. Marketing your home. The goal of most sellers is to get their listing in front of as many qualified buyers’ eyes as possible. In this day and age, you can do a lot on your own to give your listing exposure, particularly with social media. However, did you know that there are literally thousands of websites out there that real estate professionals post your listings to if you work with them? Chances are you don’t have the time or resources to post to that many sites!

“Selling a home is about more than just the dollars and cents—you also need to think about the amount of time you have to dedicate to the logistics.”

3. Pricing your home accurately. The reality is that you only have one shot to make a great initial impression. If you price your home too high when you first put it on the market, it will probably sit stagnant on the market, causing people to wonder what’s wrong with it. It’s a surefire way to reduce the amount of activity your home will see. The same is true if you price it too low. Many people like to go online to check home values, but there’s really no better way to get the true value of your home than to talk to a real estate professional (like myself). We can do a comparative market analysis (CMA) to help you discern what people would be willing to pay for your home.

4. The value of your time. A lot of folks don’t always think of how much time it takes to sell a home. Regardless of whether you sell yours on your own or if you hire an agent, there are things you’ll need to do in order to make sure the sale goes your way, like getting the property in show-ready condition. When you work with a real estate professional, they’ll handle all the particulars of the transaction for you, like scheduling showings and negotiating with the buyers and their agents. You likely have your own career to deal with, and you probably won’t be available when a buyer wants to see your home. Further still, we vet your buyers to make sure they’re qualified to actually be able to purchase the home. Selling a home is about more than just the dollars and cents—you also need to think about the amount of time you have to dedicate to the logistics.

If you have any questions about today’s topic or if you’re in need of a real estate professional to help you with your own home sale, feel free to give me a call or send an email. I’d be glad to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+On+Your+Own+vs.+Hiring+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+On+Your+Own+vs.+Hiring+a+Real+Estate+Professional.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s the difference between hiring a real estate professional to help you sell your home and just selling it by yourself? Today I’ll discuss my answer to this question.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s the difference between hiring a real estate professional to help you sell your home and just selling it by yourself? Today I’ll discuss my answer to this question.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Buyer Tips for Navigating Our Current Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-buyer-tips-for-navigating-our-current-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-09 14:59:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Buyer+Tips+for+Navigating+Our+Current+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

These four tips will aid you in better navigating the current real estate market as a homebuyer:

1. Consider submitting a larger earnest money deposit with your offer. There might not be an industry standard for this, but the earnest money is a good faith deposit that accompanies your offer and will speak volumes about your enthusiasm and seriousness about buying the property. By putting in a few thousand dollars extra, then, you’ll let the seller know that you’re a strong and serious buyer. 

2. Show the sellers that you are qualified to purchase their home. Probably most important of all, you need to show that you’ve taken the steps to meet with a lender and not only get pre-qualified, but pre-approved as well. A pre-approval, again, solidly demonstrates that you’re a serious and able buyer.  

“Put your best foot forward when making your offer to the extent that you’re comfortable.”

3. Give the sellers time to move and find out what terms are important to them. With good communication, your agent can help you with this. Whether the seller wants to have an expedient close and move-out or they need extra time, it’ll look good if you can accommodate the timetable that works best for them. 

4. Write your best offer! In this moment’s market, it won’t serve you well to write a lowball offer in the hopes that you’ll negotiate higher. Instead of counting on the seller’s willingness to negotiate and counter back, put your best foot forward when making your offer to the extent that you’re comfortable. In other words, decide how high you’re willing to go, so that if the home sold for more than that, you’d be comfortable walking away. Most sellers won’t have the appetite to go back and forth if another buyer sets themselves apart by making their best offer from the outset. 

If you’re looking to purchase a home in the Greater Madison area, I’d be happy to help. I’m an Accredited Buyer’s Representative, which means I have additional education to best help buyers navigate the market of the moment. Let’s make your dream of homeownership come true! Please give me a call at 608-345-6594 or email me at JDHolt@KW.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Buyer+Tips+for+Navigating+Our+Current+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/May/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Buyer+Tips+for+Navigating+Our+Current+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Realizing the dream of homeownership means navigating the purchase process adeptly. Today’s four buyer tips will help you do so.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Realizing the dream of homeownership means navigating the purchase process adeptly. Today’s four buyer tips will help you do so.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>April Real Estate Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/april-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-12 11:31:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/April/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+April+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There’s not really a one-size-fits-all answer to the question, “How is the market?” It depends on whether you’re looking to buy or sell, what your price point is, where you’re looking to live, and much more. These factors all play a part, so let’s see what the latest numbers have to say for each.

In the Greater Dane County area, we’re expecting home prices to increase. Right now, the median price of a single-family home is $300,000, and condos are around $195,000.

Inventory is illustrated in terms of how many months it would take for all currently listed homes to sell. Six months of inventory is a balanced market; anything above that is a buyer’s market, and anything below is a seller’s market. 

“Ultimately, it’s still a great market for buyers and sellers alike.”

As of now, we have an average of 1.5 months’ worth of inventory. Homes in the $200,000 price range only have two weeks of inventory. The $200,000 to $350,000 range has one month of inventory. At $350,000 to $500,000, there are 2.5 months of inventory—things tend to soften as price points increase. Over $500,000, there are 4.5 months of inventory.

There are about 800 single-family homes currently on the market. On average, they take 87 days to sell. Interest rates are in the low 4% range for a 30-year fixed rate mortgage, so ultimately, it’s still a great market for buyers and sellers alike.

Making the most out of our market, however, depends on who you have working as your real estate professional. I’d be more than happy to help you find a great deal on the perfect home or make a sale for top dollar. If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/April/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+April+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Josh+Holt/Videos/2019/April/Madison%2C+WI+Real+Estate+Agent-+April+Real+Estate+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What do the latest stats tell us about our market? Let’s find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What do the latest stats tell us about our market? Let’s find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To My Blog!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Joshua Holt</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-31 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Our market remains busy, and it’s still an opportune time to command a high price selling your home.  

I know what’s happening in the Madison area, specifically pertaining to home values, that will directly affect you.

So, I’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated.

They will be valuable and useful in helping you stay on top of what’s happening in the community.

Check back because content will be coming soon!

I’m excited to keep you updated on what’s happening in the Madison area!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My monthly messages will provide you with market updates, tips, and other educational information having to do with our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Joshua Holt</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My monthly messages will provide you with market updates, tips, and other educational information having to do with our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Madison, WI, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Joshua Holt</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Joshua Holt</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holt Real Estate Team - your professional Madison, WI Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
